<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--ANI XML Feed Copyright (c) 2015 ANI. All Rights Reserved.-->
<articles>
  <article ID="201601050838180001">
    <author>ANI</author>
    <headline>Afghanistan: Siege near Indian consulate ends, all attackers killed</headline>
    <cats>World </cats>
    <subcats>Middle east </subcats>
    <keywords>afghanistan indian consulate, afghanistan siege, mazar i sharif, </keywords>
    <imagename>16afg0105.jpg</imagename>
    <summary>London, Jan. 5 (ANI): Special Forces have killed the group of armed assailants who were targeting the Indian consulate in Afghanistan's Mazar-i-Sharif city, bringing an end to the siege which lasted for almost 24 hours.</summary>
    <content>
      <p>London, Jan. 5 (ANI): Special Forces have killed the group of armed assailants who were targeting the Indian consulate in Afghanistan's Mazar-i-Sharif city, bringing an end to the siege which lasted for almost 24 hours.</p>
      <p>According to the Guardian, no group has so far claimed responsibility for the raid in which at least one policeman was killed around 11 were injured.</p>
      <p>Gunfights and explosions rang as commandos were seen sliding down a rope from a helicopter on to the roof of the building from where attackers were firing.</p>
      <p>"The clearance operation is over and all three armed assailants have been killed. "We are still doing room-to-room searches. The area is absolutely under government control," Government spokesman Shir Jan Durrani said.</p>
      <p>Afghanistan President Ashraf Ghani called up Prime Minister Narendra Modi and briefed him about the statement.</p>
      <p>The Prime Minister expressed deep appreciation for the exemplary bravery and courage shown by the Afghan National Security Forces in thwarting the terrorist attack and ensuring security and safety of the Indian Consulate and personnel.</p>
      <p>The attack on the Indian consulate came in the wake of the ongoing attack on the Indian Air Force Base in Pathankot, Punjab where seven defence personnel have been martyred.</p>
      <p>The operation continues as one more terrorist is reportedly alive. (ANI)</p>
    </content>
  </article>
  <article ID="201601050838180002">
    <author>ANI</author>
    <headline>Court to hear the Jaitley's defamation suit against Kejriwal today</headline>
    <cats>National</cats>
    <subcats>General News </subcats>
    <keywords>Jaitley, Kejriwal, AAP, DDCA</keywords>
    <imagename>Jailtley0105.jpg</imagename>
    <summary>New Delhi, Jan. 5 (ANI): Patiala House Court on Tuesday is set to hear the criminal defamation case filed by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley against Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal and other Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) leaders.</summary>
    <content>
      <p>New Delhi, Jan. 5 (ANI): Patiala House Court on Tuesday is set to hear the criminal defamation case filed by Finance Minister Arun Jaitley against Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal and other Aam Aadmi Party (AAP) leaders.</p>
      <p>The case comes in the wake of the AAP leaders charging the Delhi District Cricket Association (DDCA) with widespread financial irregularity under the tenure of Jaitley as president.</p>
      <p>The case has been filed against five members of AAP namely, Ashutosh, Sanjay Singh, Kumar Vishwas, Raghav Chadha and Deepak Bajpai apart from Kejriwal.</p>
      <p>Speaking in Parliament earlier, Jaitley had said that the allegations against him in connection with the DDCA scam were baseless and devoid of truth.</p>
      <p>"All these allegations are baseless and devoid of truth. For a total sum Rs. 114 crore, we made a stadium with a capacity of taking 42,000 people. Contrary to that, the Congress built the Jawaharlal Nehru Stadium spending Rs. 900 crores. No one raised doubts on that expenditure, "he had said in the Lok Sabha.</p>
      <p>On December 21 Jaitley had filed a criminal defamation complaint against Kejriwal and five other leaders of AAP for allegedly defaming him in the DDCA controversy before a Delhi court which took cognizance on his plea. (ANI)</p>
    </content>
  </article>
  <article ID="201601050838180003">
    <author>ANI</author>
    <headline>Working on 'leads' provided by India to counter terrorism: Pakistan</headline>
    <cats>World </cats>
    <subcats>Asia </subcats>
    <keywords>pathankot air base, pathankot attack, pakistan pathakot attack</keywords>
    <imagename>16pak0105.jpg</imagename>
    <summary>Karachi, Jan. 5 (ANI): In the wake of the ongoing attack by assailants on the Indian Air Force Base in Pathankot, Pakistan said that it is working on the 'latest leads' provided by the Indian Government to 'effectively' counter and eradicate terrorism from the region.</summary>
    <content>
      <p>Karachi, Jan. 5 (ANI): In the wake of the ongoing attack by assailants on the Indian Air Force Base in Pathankot, Pakistan said that it is working on the 'latest leads' provided by the Indian Government to 'effectively' counter and eradicate terrorism from the region.</p>
      <p>According to the Dawn, the Foreign Office said in a statement that Pakistan remains committed and is in touch with the Indian government.</p>
      <p>The statement came as sections of the Indian media reported that New Delhi had contacted and shared information with Islamabad about the ongoing attack on the Pathankot IAF Base.</p>
      <p>"We understand the pain of many families who have lost their dear ones in this tragedy, as Pakistan itself is a major victim of terrorism. We have extended our deepest condolences to the government and people of India," the spokesman said condemning the attack.</p>
      <p>He added that the two nations needed to remain committed to a 'sustained dialogue process' in the light of the challenge of terrorism.</p>
      <p>At least seven defence personnel have been killed so far in the deadly attack on the airbase which continued into its third day on Monday and search operations continue to smoke out the remaining terrorist who is reportedly still active. (ANI)</p>
    </content>
  </article>
</articles>