<story>
<id>682899</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>yes</story_issue>
<select_magazine>1557</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date>June 13, 2016</issue_date><bylines>
<byline>277</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464794318</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464794318</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1465210154</modifieddate>
<createdby>802</createdby>
<modifiedby>802</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city/>
</cities>
<categories><category>279341</category><category>279686</category><category>280225</category></categories><ordering>682899</ordering><primarycategory>279341</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/anandi-jun13-1_647_060216103610.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt><![CDATA[Anandiben Patel ]]></extra_large_alt>
<extra_large_title><![CDATA[Anandiben Patel ]]></extra_large_title>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/anandi-jun13-1_305_060216103610.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt><![CDATA[Anandiben Patel ]]></large_alt>
<large_title><![CDATA[Anandiben Patel ]]></large_title>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/anandi-jun13-1_300_060216103610.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt><![CDATA[Anandiben Patel ]]></mediumimage_alt>
<mediumimage_title><![CDATA[Anandiben Patel ]]></mediumimage_title>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/anandi-jun13-1_180_060216103610.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt><![CDATA[Anandiben Patel ]]></smallimage_alt>
<smallimage_title><![CDATA[Anandiben Patel ]]></smallimage_title>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/anandi-jun13-1_88_060216103610.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt><![CDATA[Anandiben Patel ]]></extra_small_alt>
<extra_small_title><![CDATA[Anandiben Patel ]]></extra_small_title>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption><![CDATA[Gujarat CM Anandiben Patel at her residence. Photo: Shailesh Raval]]></kicker_image_caption>
<mosimage>
<image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/anandismall_060216103714.jpg]]></image><caption/></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[With Anandiben no longer effective as an electoral face for the assembly poll in 2017, the BJP is mulling a graceful exit for the Gujarat chief minister.]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>Though she has dismissed it as mere rumour, the top leadership of the Bharatiya Janata Party is seriously considering replacing Gujarat Chief Minister Anandiben Patel. It is part of the wider election strategy party president Amit Shah has chalked out for the 2017 Gujarat assembly election. A change in leadership is considered essential if the BJP is to retain the state, since the party faces fierce anti-incumbency after nearly two decades of rule. Prime Minister Narendra Modi, who had handpicked Anandiben in 2014 to take his place as Gujarat CM, is expected to take a final call soon. The fact that she turns 75 later this year may hand the BJP a reason to move her out, as Modi has set an unspoken age limit for cabinet ministers and chief ministers.</p><p>Among the main contenders for the post are two Patels. The frontrunner is health minister Nitinbhai Patel, followed by education minister Bhupendrasinh Chudasama, a Rajput by caste. Finance and energy minister Saurabh Patel is a third possibility. The dark horse, however, is state BJP president and transport and water supply minister Vijay Rupani. A Jain Bania by caste, he is seen as a Modi-Shah favourite as also of the top RSS leadership.</p><p>Should Anandiben be replaced by a non-Patel, the BJP will have to get back Parshottam Rupala as state party president. A powerful Patel leader, he was sent to the Rajya Sabha and is currently BJP vice-president.</p><p>The move to replace Anandiben began after BJP Rajya Sabha MP Om Prakash Mathur, a close aide of the prime minister, submitted an internal party report on April 25. Mathur was earlier general secretary in charge of Gujarat. His report said that Anandiben's personal popularity had nosedived dramatically after the Hardik Patel-led Patidar agitation in August 2015. The stir eroded the BJP's strongest vote bank, the Patels. Constituting an estimated 12-15 per cent of the total votes in the state, they can make or break the fortunes of a political party in Gujarat. Anandiben made a grave error when she slapped sedition charges against Hardik but failed to hold senior police officials accountable for letting their men go on a rampage against the agitating Patels during the August 25 rally in Ahmedabad last year. Ten people were killed, several police chowkis burned and railway lines uprooted.</p><p>{mosimage}Following Mathur's report, a 10 per cent quota was announced for the economically backward classes. This was supposed to be the first step in course correction towards Patel grievances. Narrowly defined as those earning less than Rs 6 lakh a year, the economically backward classes were supposed to include the powerful Patels. But the move has failed to placate them and Anandiben continues to face their wrath in the rural countryside.</p><p>The immediate effect of her mishandling of the Patel agitation manifested itself in the BJP's disastrous performance in the panchayat polls in November 2015. The party lost 23 of the 31 district panchayats, though it did manage to win six municipal corporations in the state. The BJP is interpreting the resurgence of the Congress in rural Gujarat after 18 years of stagnation as a sign of things to come if it doesn't replace the current CM with someone who can revamp the state unit and improve governance.</p><p>The Congress has attracted good response in eight of the 18 Lok Darbars (gatherings to hear people's grievances) it has held in the state. Says Congress spokesperson and Gujarat party leader Shaktisinh Gohil: "We are very confident of winning the 2017 polls and we are working to a plan." The Congress hasn't nurtured any new leadership in the state, but the party has a no-nonsense leader and electoral strategist in state president Bharatsinh Solanki. Both Gohil and Solanki are also working in tandem with Shankersinh Vaghela, leader of the Opposition in the state, and senior leader Siddharth Patel.</p><p>Anandiben is also accused of having a disconnect both with party leaders in the state and the workers. She is seen to lack the acumen required to lead the party in a competitive assembly poll. Worse, she and her family face charges of nepotism relating to a 2010 deal, when the government allotted land on the periphery of the Gir lion sanctuary to a business partner of her daughter Anar Patel, a social worker cum businesswoman. The charges have stuck, even though the allotment was made before she became CM.</p><p>Fighting these allegations, Anandiben broached the subject in an uncharacteristic manner. In a video conference with district collectors last week, she told them corruption should be dealt with firmly in land-related cases. "It is being attributed to me and my family," she said. "Has anyone from my office or on my behalf called you with any personal recommendation?" The answer was a resounding no, but Congress leaders in the state couldn't resist tweeting barbs: "Glad you spoke against corruption in revenue land deals. Waiting for you to speak against crores being charged (by the urban development department from builders) for building use permission."</p><p>Bureaucratic corruption, particularly in the infrastructure and revenue departments, too has risen during her tenure, which is more an indication of her lack of control over her bureaucrats.</p><p>Anandiben's problem is that she lacks personal charisma, and can never outgrow the shadow of the man who appointed her his successor. Modi chose Anandiben because of her loyalty to him. She had done well in his cabinet, both as education minister and as revenue minister. As the former, she curbed corruption in the recruitment of teachers in government schools. As revenue minister, she reformed the department. She was the architect of land acquisition for canal work in the Narmada dam project. As CM too, she has worked hard. Of the 13 lakh toilets built under the Swachh Bharat Mission, as many as 37 per cent, or 500,000, are in Gujarat.</p><p>She dismisses the charges of nepotism, mismanagement of the Patel agitation and organisational inefficiency as being politically motivated. At the end of a local cricket match in Ahmedabad's Karnavati Club on May 30, she said: "In sports as well as in politics, it's important to stay till the last minute. Only those who stay unfazed can progress."</p><p>However, even as the central BJP leadership is planning her removal, the state BJP leadership, especially the main contenders for the CM post, is either silent or dismissing all talk of her replacement as wild speculation. "These are all rumours," says state president Rupani. "We're at present focusing on planning a grand BJP victory in the 2017 election." Political analyst Japan Pathak, who runs the popular news portal DeshGujarat, doesn't buy the argument. "I think the party high command has already taken a decision," he says. "It is only looking for an opportune time to implement it. She is an old Modi loyalist. How to give her a graceful exit might be delaying the decision." The sword is still hanging on Anandiben's chief ministership.</p><div align="right"><b>Follow the writer on Twitter @udaymahurkar</b></div><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[With Anandiben no longer effective as an electoral face for the assembly poll in 2017, the BJP is mulling a graceful exit for the Gujarat chief minister.]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>254559</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Gujarat Assembly Election: Will BJP replace CM Anandiben Patel?]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Perched on a shaky chair]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Perched on a shaky chair]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>2</like>
<dislike>1</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/anandiben-patel-gujarat-assembly-poll/1/682899.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Gujarat Assembly Election: Will BJP replace CM Anandiben Patel?]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/anandi-jun13-1_647_060216103610.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Gujarat Assembly Election: Will BJP replace CM Anandiben Patel?]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/anandi-jun13-1_647_060216103610.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>1</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[anandiben-patel-gujarat-assembly-poll]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Gujarat Assembly Election: Will BJP replace CM Anandiben Patel?]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[Anandiben Patel,Gujarat Chief Minister,2017 Assembly poll ]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>