<story>
<id>682898</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>yes</story_issue>
<select_magazine>1557</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date>June 13, 2016</issue_date><bylines>
<byline>1153</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464794316</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464794316</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1465209348</modifieddate>
<createdby>802</createdby>
<modifiedby>802</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city/>
</cities>
<categories><category>279298</category><category>279686</category><category>280225</category></categories><ordering>682898</ordering><primarycategory>279298</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/african-in-india-jun13-2_647_060216103014.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt><![CDATA[Cyrille, a Congolese student of Delhi's Mahatma Gandhi University.]]></extra_large_alt>
<extra_large_title><![CDATA[Cyrille, a Congolese student of Delhi's Mahatma Gandhi University.]]></extra_large_title>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/african-in-india-jun13-2_305_060216103014.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt><![CDATA[Cyrille, a Congolese student of Delhi's Mahatma Gandhi University.]]></large_alt>
<large_title><![CDATA[Cyrille, a Congolese student of Delhi's Mahatma Gandhi University.]]></large_title>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/african-in-india-jun13-2_300_060216103014.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt><![CDATA[Cyrille, a Congolese student of Delhi's Mahatma Gandhi University.]]></mediumimage_alt>
<mediumimage_title><![CDATA[Cyrille, a Congolese student of Delhi's Mahatma Gandhi University.]]></mediumimage_title>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/african-in-india-jun13-2_180_060216103014.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt><![CDATA[Cyrille, a Congolese student of Delhi's Mahatma Gandhi University.]]></smallimage_alt>
<smallimage_title><![CDATA[Cyrille, a Congolese student of Delhi's Mahatma Gandhi University.]]></smallimage_title>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/african-in-india-jun13-2_88_060216103014.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt><![CDATA[Cyrille, a Congolese student of Delhi's Mahatma Gandhi University.]]></extra_small_alt>
<extra_small_title><![CDATA[Cyrille, a Congolese student of Delhi's Mahatma Gandhi University.]]></extra_small_title>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption><![CDATA[Cyrille, a Congolese student of Delhi's Mahatma Gandhi University. Photo: M Zhazo]]></kicker_image_caption>
<mosimage>
<image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/african1_060216103119.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[Nigerian in Nawada, Uttam Nagar. Photo: Chandradeep Kumar]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/african2_060216103119.jpg]]></image><caption/></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[For many African expats, India is a place that begins with hope and ends in fear, silence and a pervading threat of violence.]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>Pastor Ekitah Bertin came to Delhi from the Democratic Republic of Congo eight years ago. He always told his flock at the Assemblies of God Mission in South Extension that while their skin is black, the colour of their blood was the same as anyone else's, and maybe those who throw stones don't understand, and one can only wish for a change of heart.</p><p>In 2012, the pastor had helped a young Congolese compatriot, Masonga Kitanda Olivier, to come to Delhi to study Information Technology after his family had approached the church in his homeland. "He was a sweet boy. Didn't smoke, didn't drink, and it was his birthday the day they killed him," he says. Olivier was killed in a brutal assault by three men when he objected to them commandeering an autorickshaw he had hailed. The police have since arrested the attackers and say one of them has a criminal record, as does the third assailant who is absconding. No wonder the pastor preaches the virtues of meekness. "Even if they charge you Rs 50 instead of Rs 30, don't argue. Give it, and understand that God watches everything," he says. "God wanted us to come here. Else, we wouldn't get visas. It is His will."</p><p>At the embassy of the Democratic Republic of Congo, a country plagued by civil wars and conflict for decades, Pastor Bertin and others are trying to arrange for the return of his body. For days, it has lain in a morgue in the city, mourned by those that knew him. For days, they have struggled with other bloody memories too.</p><p>{mosimage}Racism and prejudice are never distant for the small but growing communities of African nationals in India. In January this year, a 21-year-old Tanzanian woman was paraded naked in Bengaluru. Authorities have made arrests in the most recent case in Delhi, but had dismissed an earlier assault in Rajpur Khurd as a "minor scuffle". "We still maintain it had nothing to do with racism," says Rajan Bhagat, the Delhi Police Public Relations Officer, of the recent killing. He demurs with a "no comment" when asked about other instances of racist attacks, but promises that the authorities are coordinating meetings between African representatives and the RWAs of localities that have seen such tensions.</p><p>The "ghettoisation" many Africans describe is also an established fact of life. They have set up their own places of worship, and the pastor says the one where he led the prayer services in South Extension was shut down by the MCD in March. He has been scouting for a new address, but it's difficult, he says. There are two other churches in the city that cater to some 2,500 Congolese in Delhi. There are also several Nigerian churches in the city. Most of the Africans are in Delhi to study or run businesses, and according to the state government, are the largest expatriate community in the capital. It's telling perhaps-this casual presumption that the people of one particular continent are equivalent to other national communities. In fact, for all the furore, it's hard to come by any reliable statistic for the number of Africans in India-we're talking about more than 50 nationalities after all. The number of African students in the country-everywhere from Phagwara to Pune-is commonly estimated at between 25,000 and 30,000. But for all their diversity, Africans in India are all too aware of the crude stereotypes and prejudice that stalk them here.</p><p><b>***</b><br />Sonny Eluwa spends most of his evenings at a church in the basement of a building next to a park in Sant Nagar. A nondescript door leads to a staircase, which in turn leads one to a congregation hall with a stage carpeted in red, and decorated with plastic foliage. A place of nostalgia: the walls are covered with pictures of many homelands with hills and huts and clouds, and on most evenings a choir sings songs dedicated to God and his mercies. As Sonny sat in a chair, a man was beating his head against the stage asking for hope. A priest blessed him, and Sonny spoke of a life in a city that would never accept black people for who they are.</p><p>The church caters to a diverse expat community, of Nigerians, Congolese and Sudanese, and in this distant corner where they feel they can be invisible, they feel safer confessing their fears.</p><p>Sonny came to Delhi in 2013 to do business. But the loss of dignity hurts, he says. "They say we eat humans, sell drugs," he whispers. "We're human too. We've come here with hopes, dreams."</p><p>{mosimage}In March last year, Delhi law minister Somnath Bharti allegedly pulled a group of foreigners out of their flats at midnight in Khirki Extension, home to Nigerians, Congolese and Ugandans. Four Ugandan women complained of being groped. "It's like you must live in spite of yourself, and maybe God has willed it for you. Maybe there is hope. Maybe there is no hope. But you must keep your gaze down," a Congolese man says. He refuses to give his name.</p><p>***<br />At her salon Above Blessings in south Delhi's Arjun Nagar locality, Blessing sits braiding her hair, and says she'd rather not give her full name. She has been here only a year, and knows the only way to live in this country is to ignore everything. "They laugh at you, look at you in a way that is embarrassing and threatening. They shout 'Abisi'," she says. "What does it mean?" Habshi is an ancient racist imprecation that has found new life on the streets of the capital.</p><p>***<br />Birender Yadav is Joint Secretary (West Africa) in the external affairs ministry. It fell to him to meet Olivier's uncle and cousin on their arrival on Monday. "India's assured them a speedy trial," he says. Beneath the diplomatic reassurance, on can sense a certain panic. The Indian government hopes to rival China as a trading partner with the resource-rich African continent. The trade is presently pegged at some $70 billion and Prime Minister Narendra Modi is scheduled to visit Kenya, Mozambique, Tanzania and South Africa in July. Stories of racist attacks on Africans in India must be contained. External affairs minister Sushma Swaraj met with African envoys on Tuesday and assured that "India is the land of Gandhi and Buddha...we can never have a racist mindset".</p><p>That's not something Olivier's former roomate Cyrille finds easy to accept. Racism is entrenched in Indian society, he says. When he first came to India for a master's in information technology at the Mahatma Gandhi University in Delhi, he had been excited to make new friends. But when he invited them over for a meal, they refused, saying their parents wouldn't approve. They never invited him over either. It's understandable, he says. After all, Indians discriminate even against their own people.</p><p>***<br />Olivier's father isn't a rich man. For a man to not have the resources to get his son's body home is sad, the pastor says.</p><p>He had spent all his savings to fund his son's education in India. Olivier was working as a French teacher and supporting his family back home. He had been in India since 2012. His friends hoped he'd return someday.</p><p>The government has now promised they would help, says the pastor. "We can only hope."</p><p>It will be a long journey home. One that began in hope but has already ended with such brutal finality for Olivier. For thousands of others the Indian journey continues with quiet dread. At Many's Square, a restaurant in Arjun Nagar, two Burmese chefs are serving rice with pork. A black man sits at a table, having lunch. "Come to Nigeria. I take you there," he says. "We like India people."</p><p>"Don't you feel scared?"</p><p>"Sometimes. But what can we do? We're unlearning our identity here," he says. "We are learning to keep quiet." Racism isn't always about words. It works with silences too.</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[For many African expats, India is a place that begins with hope and ends in fear, silence and a pervading threat of violence.]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>262676</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[For African expats, India a place where hope and fear co-exist]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Indian babylon]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Indian babylon]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>0</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/africans-in-india-racial-attacks-violence/1/682898.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[For African expats, India a place where hope and fear co-exist]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/african-in-india-jun13-2_647_060216103014.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[For African expats, India a place where hope and fear co-exist]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/african-in-india-jun13-2_647_060216103014.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>1</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[africans-in-india-racial-attacks-violence]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[For African expats, India a place where hope and fear co-exist]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[Africans in India,Racial attacks]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>