<story>
<id>682903</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>yes</story_issue>
<select_magazine>1557</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date>June 13, 2016</issue_date><bylines>
<byline>191</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464794323</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464794323</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1465210655</modifieddate>
<createdby>802</createdby>
<modifiedby>802</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city/>
</cities>
<categories><category>279341</category><category>279686</category><category>280225</category></categories><ordering>682903</ordering><primarycategory>279341</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/fake-doctors-jun13-1_647_060216113311.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt><![CDATA['Doctor' Ram Bharose at work in Samastipur. Photo: Ranjan Rahi]]></extra_large_alt>
<extra_large_title><![CDATA['Doctor' Ram Bharose at work in Samastipur. Photo: Ranjan Rahi]]></extra_large_title>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/fake-doctors-jun13-1_305_060216113311.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt><![CDATA['Doctor' Ram Bharose at work in Samastipur. Photo: Ranjan Rahi]]></large_alt>
<large_title><![CDATA['Doctor' Ram Bharose at work in Samastipur. Photo: Ranjan Rahi]]></large_title>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/fake-doctors-jun13-1_300_060216113311.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt><![CDATA['Doctor' Ram Bharose at work in Samastipur. Photo: Ranjan Rahi]]></mediumimage_alt>
<mediumimage_title><![CDATA['Doctor' Ram Bharose at work in Samastipur. Photo: Ranjan Rahi]]></mediumimage_title>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/fake-doctors-jun13-1_180_060216113311.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt><![CDATA['Doctor' Ram Bharose at work in Samastipur. Photo: Ranjan Rahi]]></smallimage_alt>
<smallimage_title><![CDATA['Doctor' Ram Bharose at work in Samastipur. Photo: Ranjan Rahi]]></smallimage_title>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/fake-doctors-jun13-1_88_060216113311.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt><![CDATA['Doctor' Ram Bharose at work in Samastipur. Photo: Ranjan Rahi]]></extra_small_alt>
<extra_small_title><![CDATA['Doctor' Ram Bharose at work in Samastipur. Photo: Ranjan Rahi]]></extra_small_title>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption><![CDATA['Doctor' Ram Bharose at work in Samastipur. Photo: Ranjan Rahi]]></kicker_image_caption>
<mosimage>
<image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/doctor1_060216113446.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[Laxmi Sahni attends to a patient. Photo: Ranjan Rahi]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/doctor2_060216113446.jpg]]></image><caption/><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/doctor3_060216113446.jpg]]></image><caption/></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[Unable to fix its broken public health infrastructure, Bihar comes up with a hare-brained scheme to legitimise its quacks.]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks ago, when Arvind Singh collapsed in the middle of his farmland at Lohagir, his panic-stricken family dialled every one of the dozen-odd unlicensed medical practitioners in the village. By the time village 'doctor' Laxmi Sahni got there, the 52-year-old farmer was writhing in pain, clutching at his stomach, shaking involuntarily and cursing with frustration. Unflustered by all this and seemingly without reflection, Sahni fished out a syringe, found a vein and quickly injected first a painkiller and then an antibiotic. In this case, it even worked-the pain subsided and Singh was rushed to a city hospital in Samastipur, 19 km from Lohagir, for further attention.</p><p>Sahni, 47, carries a stethoscope, syringes and an assortment of antibiotics, painkillers and anti-allergic and digestive tablets along with vials of different injectables and saline bottles in the grey bag that remains strapped to his Honda motorcycle.</p><p>A doctor on the move? Well, almost. Except that Sahni is an arts graduate with no qualification whatsoever in medicine. Yet he has been practising medicine for over two decades. After all, no one asks for your degree in villages where something is better than nothing.</p><p>Unlicensed medical practitioners are a fact of life in Bihar. Rough estimates put their number at some four lakh, practising a deadly hit-and-miss style of medicine in the state's 40,000-plus villages.</p><p>"The patients seldom complain, there are never any legal issues," says one, requesting anonymity. "But, deep down, we know we have no mandate to do what we are doing. A police vehicle always scares us. Life is like one long air-raid drill. We are tired of living like this."</p><p><b>Munnabhai MBBS?</b></p><p>As if on cue, the Bihar government will start a one-year diploma course to educate 'untrained health activists' this July. The State Health Society (SHS), under the Bihar Health Department, stitched up an agreement with the National Institute of Open Schooling (NIOS) in June last year to run the programme. Matriculates with a minimum of three years of experience were eligible to apply. The course fee was fixed at Rs 5,000. "We have already received 22,000 applications," says Sanjay Kumar Sinha, regional director, NIOS.</p><p>{mosimage}"The quacks will get a diploma after completing 400 hours of training," says Dr L.B. Singh approvingly. Chairman of the 10-member state advisory committee overseeing the implementation of the programme, Singh seems at peace with the certification of these ersatz doctors. "They'll be trained at 149 first referral units (FRUs) and 533 primary health centres. The NIOS will engage health department employees and doctors for the training." The students will be assessed after a year, with 40 per cent marks assigned to theory, 60 per cent to practical examinations.</p><p><b>Why quacks thrive in Bihar</b></p><p>As BJP leader and former health minister Nand Kishore Yadav puts it, "The quacks are not the real problem, the healthcare vacuum is." Bihar is fifth among states with the highest shortfall of primary health centres in rural areas. Against the required strength of 3,099 such centres in 2015, the state had only 1,883, or 1,216 centres less than required for its 92.3 million people at the time.</p><p>{mosimage}While the private healthcare business is booming in the state, aided by the growing middle class willing to pay for costly treatment, the rural healthcare infrastructure remains skeletal. Bihar has only one government doctor for every 30,000 people. The World Health Organization specifies a ratio of one doctor to every 1,000 people in low-income countries. There are privately employed or self-employed doctors; but like pizza parlours, they don't open shop in villages. Government-run clinics are either too far away or have unending queues.</p><p><b>A necessary evil?</b></p><p>Several NGOs find it useful to enlist these quacks in initiatives such as the pulse-polio immunisation programme. Singh is convinced their programme is a path-breaking initiative. "Quacks are already part of the healthcare system," he says. "Training them would enhance their skills, minimise risk and help people with minor ailments. They can also refer emergency cases to MBBS doctors."</p><p>The course is 'comprehensive', covering everything from lessons on high-risk pregnancy, resuscitation of a new-born, maternal and child healthcare to communicable diseases, internal haemorrhage, even cancer.</p><p><b>Course of 'action'</b></p><p>Sinha insists the programme will at the very outset tell the 'medical practitioners' "what not to do". But as an SHS officer admits, "The government just cannot monitor these unlicensed medical practitioners. The NIOS certification may give them the status of a community health worker. But these 'doctors', many of whom already have a thriving practice, are unlikely to scale down their activities just because the certificate does not allow them to, say, prescribe a medicine."</p><p>Sahni, for instance, is delighted at the stamp of legitimacy the course will give him, even if it means dropping the doctor prefix before his name. "We are already doctors," he says, "the diploma will only legitimise what we do." And therein lies the biggest threat.</p><p>"We have seen several instances where these rural medicine men have turned acute cases into chronic ones," says Dr Ajay Kumar, chairman, IMA Academy of Medical Specialities, Bihar, citing examples of quacks who misdiagnose, prescribe strong, unnecessary medication, and buy cheap, out-of-date antibiotics. "If the rural population of Bihar has developed high drug resistance, it is only because of these medical imposters," he says. "More than 80 per cent of Bihar's people live in its villages. Are they second-grade citizens that they deserve inferior medical care by a brigade of 'qualified' quacks?"</p><p>{mosimage}Only last month, Phoolwanti Devi, wife of a labourer in Amanabad in Patna district, lost her four-year-old son Anshu after a local quack, Dhaneshar Choudhary, injected him with something unknown. Seemingly unperturbed by this, the man continues to practise medicine, some 35 km from Bihar health minister Tej Pratap Yadav's residence.</p><p>"The government," says Dr Ranjit Kumar, general secretary of the Bihar Health Service Association, "should first take note of why qualified doctors are migrating from Bihar." Medicine, he adds, is a highly specialised practice, unlicensed practitioners cannot take it up on whim. "Can you allow air hostesses to fly planes because you do not have enough pilots?" he asks. Yet, this is exactly what is happening. Ram Bharose, 36, who has a degree in commerce, and is now contesting the Bihar panchayat elections, has been practising medicine in Lohagir in Samastipur district for the past 10 years.</p><p>The solution, according to Nand Kishore Yadav, is in meeting the National Rural Health Management (NRHM) criteria of having one subcentre per 5,000 people in 'general' areas and another per 3,000 people in 'difficult' areas. Until then, Bihar will continue to be at the mercy of its newly legitimised quacks.</p><div align="right"><b>Follow the writer on Twitter @Amitabh1975</b></div><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[Unable to fix its broken public health infrastructure, Bihar comes up with a hare-brained scheme to legitimise its quacks.]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>223950</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Public healthcare: Bihar comes up with hare-brained scheme to legitimise its quacks]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Licence to murder]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Licence to murder]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>0</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/bihar-public-health-infrastructure-fake-doctors/1/682903.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Public healthcare: Bihar comes up with hare-brained scheme to legitimise its quacks]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/fake-doctors-jun13-1_647_060216113311.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Public healthcare: Bihar comes up with hare-brained scheme to legitimise its quacks]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/fake-doctors-jun13-1_647_060216113311.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[bihar-public-health-infrastructure-fake-doctors]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Public healthcare: Bihar comes up with hare-brained scheme to legitimise its quacks]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[Bihar public health infrastructure,Fake doctors,Medical system]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>