<story>
<id>682904</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>yes</story_issue>
<select_magazine>1557</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date>June 13, 2016</issue_date><bylines>
<byline>263</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464794324</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464794324</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1465210597</modifieddate>
<createdby>802</createdby>
<modifiedby>802</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city/>
</cities>
<categories><category>279686</category><category>279733</category><category>280225</category></categories><ordering>682904</ordering><primarycategory>279733</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/glasshouse-13jun-1_647_060216113846.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt><![CDATA[Illustration by Anup Ray]]></extra_large_alt>
<extra_large_title><![CDATA[Illustration by Anup Ray]]></extra_large_title>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/glasshouse-13jun-1_305_060216113846.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt><![CDATA[Illustration by Anup Ray]]></large_alt>
<large_title><![CDATA[Illustration by Anup Ray]]></large_title>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/glasshouse-13jun-1_300_060216113846.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt><![CDATA[Illustration by Anup Ray]]></mediumimage_alt>
<mediumimage_title><![CDATA[Illustration by Anup Ray]]></mediumimage_title>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/glasshouse-13jun-1_180_060216113846.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt><![CDATA[Illustration by Anup Ray]]></smallimage_alt>
<smallimage_title><![CDATA[Illustration by Anup Ray]]></smallimage_title>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/glasshouse-13jun-1_88_060216113846.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt><![CDATA[Illustration by Anup Ray]]></extra_small_alt>
<extra_small_title><![CDATA[Illustration by Anup Ray]]></extra_small_title>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption><![CDATA[Illustration by Anup Ray]]></kicker_image_caption>
<mosimage>
<image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/glasshouse1_060216113949.jpg]]></image><caption/><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/glasshouse2_060216113949.jpg]]></image><caption/><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/glasshouse3_060216113949.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[Free for all by Anup Roy]]></caption></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[The Indian strategic community is delighted with Union minister for 
environment Prakash Javadekar clearing the Tillanchang island in the 
Nicobar island chain for a missile test facility. ]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p><b>Missile paradise</b><br />The Indian strategic community is delighted with Union minister for environment Prakash Javadekar clearing the Tillanchang island in the Nicobar island chain for a missile test facility. The UPA had in 2011 stalled a navy proposal to use the island as a temporary missile test range for underwater-launched weapons saying it was a bird habitat, but Javadekar overruled those concerns last year. Two nuclear submarines carried out their first critical tests on the island recently-the SSBN Arihant fired a K-4 ballistic missile and the nuclear-powered attack submarine INS Chakra fired a land-attack version of the Klub cruise missile. The icing on the cake: both tests were successful.</p><p><b>Women's power</b><br />Tamil Nadu CM J Jayalalithaa is in a grateful mood, strengthening her connect with the women voters who propelled the AIADMK to victory in the May 16 elections. Women are to get 50 per cent reservation in grassroots political leadership, and for this she is increasing the number of wards in civic bodies through delimitation. Elections are due in October. Civic wards were last classified 25 years ago.</p><p><b>Ladies' man</b><br />He's 85, but there's no slowing him down. After his salvos at Sonia Gandhi and Rahul in his memoir, Natwar Singh's turned to a somewhat gentler subject. In Praise of Older Women has him, well, writing of some that he's known, from the vastly dissimilar Vijayalakshmi Pandit and Indira Gandhi, to actor Nargis and writer Han Suyin.</p><p><b>{mosimage}De-spirited Mandarins</b><br />The Chinese had planned a grand banquet for President Pranab Mukherjee on May 26, hosted by Xi Jinping and his glamorous wife Peng Liyuan. Given that official banquets have become exceedingly rare in Xi's China amid a clean-up campaign, a request from the Indian side to keep the event 'dry' came as especially sad news for Beijing's mandarins, who were looking forward to a rare opportunity to relive their pre-austerity past.</p><p><b>Click away</b><br />A great one for e-governance initiatives, Andhra Pradesh CM N. Chandrababu Naidu will now extend it to property registration. This August 15, the state will open registration seva kendras in a phased manner. Set on the lines of passport seva kendras, the entire registration process will take 45 minutes. Stamp vending machines and standardised documents will end the rampant corruption, eliminate middlemen and reduce dependence on document writers.</p><p><b>CM shockers</b><br />The list of BJP candidates for the June 11 Rajya Sabha elections has come as a rude shock to party chief ministers. Rajasthan CM Vasundhara Raje reportedly opposed a seat from Rajasthan for close Narendra Modi aide Om Prakash Mathur, but had to give in at party president Amit Shah's insistence. Similarly in Chhattisgarh, the BJP nominated tribal leader and known opponent of state CM Raman Singh, Ramvichar Netam. The CM proposed the name of another tribal leader, Nankiram Kanwar, but was overruled. High command rules.</p><p><b>All in the beans</b><br />Poll strategist Prashant Kishor used the 'chai pe charcha' as a key electioneering tool for PM Modi. Now Ashutosh Niranjan, DM of UP's most backward district, Gonda, has started using it to feel the pulse of the people there. At the 'Coffee with Collector', which began on May 26, he meets village heads for an hour every day.</p><p><b>{mosimage}GST in sight</b><br />The Union ministry for finance is likely to push the Goods and Services Tax Bill in the Rajya Sabha during the monsoon session of Parliament which begins on June 24. The NDA has a two-pronged strategy. To persuade the Congress and other opposition parties, the government indicated its willingness to drop the controversial provision of 1 per cent tax to favour manufacturing states. The NDA senses favourable numbers in the Rajya Sabha after the current phase of biennial elections. The Congress numbers are set to reduce while the NDA and other parties will increase their strength.</p><p><b>Ghost buster</b><br />Kerala finance minister Thomas Isaac has requested an official car with the number 13 and opted to stay in 'Manmohan bungalow' in state capital Thiruvananthapuram, despite the myth that its occupants don't complete their terms.</p><p><b>Daddy's pet</b><br />When a dubious land deal cast a shadow on Maharashtra revenue minister Eknath Khadse, his daughter Sharda not only prepared a line of defence but also told Khadse's staff what to say. Grapevine has it that she'll be inducted in the Devendra Fadnavis government if Khadse steps down for 'health reasons'.</p><p><b>A special gift</b><br />Bangladesh Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina's gifts to Mamata Banerjee are a gentle reminder for the West Bengal chief minister to put her signature on the Teesta water-sharing agreement. {mosimage}<br /></p><div align="right"><i><b>with Santosh Kumar, Ananth Krishnan, Kiran Tare, Ashish Misra, Amarnath K Menon, Javed Ansari, Anshuman Tiwari, Amitabh Srivastava and Jeemon Jacob</b></i><br /></div><br /><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[The Indian strategic community is delighted with Union minister for 
environment Prakash Javadekar clearing the Tillanchang island in the 
Nicobar island chain for a missile test facility. ]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>274216</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Glasshouse]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Glasshouse of the week]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Glasshouse of the week]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>0</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/glasshouse-of-the-week/1/682904.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Glasshouse]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/glasshouse-13jun-1_647_060216113846.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Glasshouse]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/glasshouse-13jun-1_647_060216113846.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[glasshouse-of-the-week]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Glasshouse]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[Tillanchang island,Jayalalithaa,Pranab Mukherjee,Chandrababu Naidu,GST,Arun Jaitley]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>