<story>
<id>682907</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>yes</story_issue>
<select_magazine>1557</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date>June 13, 2016</issue_date><bylines>
<byline>1351</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464794327</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464794327</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1465210576</modifieddate>
<createdby>802</createdby>
<modifiedby>802</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city>285702</city>
</cities>
<categories><category>279341</category><category>279686</category><category>280225</category></categories><ordering>682907</ordering><primarycategory>279341</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/goa-jun13-1_647_060216114655.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt><![CDATA[Parrikar and Parsekar unveil a tiled mural of themselves at Parra]]></extra_large_alt>
<extra_large_title><![CDATA[Parrikar and Parsekar unveil a tiled mural of themselves at Parra]]></extra_large_title>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/goa-jun13-1_305_060216114655.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt><![CDATA[Parrikar and Parsekar unveil a tiled mural of themselves at Parra]]></large_alt>
<large_title><![CDATA[Parrikar and Parsekar unveil a tiled mural of themselves at Parra]]></large_title>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/goa-jun13-1_300_060216114655.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt><![CDATA[Parrikar and Parsekar unveil a tiled mural of themselves at Parra]]></mediumimage_alt>
<mediumimage_title><![CDATA[Parrikar and Parsekar unveil a tiled mural of themselves at Parra]]></mediumimage_title>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/goa-jun13-1_180_060216114655.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt><![CDATA[Parrikar and Parsekar unveil a tiled mural of themselves at Parra]]></smallimage_alt>
<smallimage_title><![CDATA[Parrikar and Parsekar unveil a tiled mural of themselves at Parra]]></smallimage_title>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/goa-jun13-1_88_060216114655.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt><![CDATA[Parrikar and Parsekar unveil a tiled mural of themselves at Parra]]></extra_small_alt>
<extra_small_title><![CDATA[Parrikar and Parsekar unveil a tiled mural of themselves at Parra]]></extra_small_title>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption><![CDATA[Parrikar and Parsekar unveil a tiled mural of themselves at Parra]]></kicker_image_caption>
<mosimage>
<image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/goa1_060216114534.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[AAP leader Arvind Kejriwal addresses a rally at Campal ground, Panaji. Photo: Edric George]]></caption></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[Goa chief minister Laxmikant Parsekar is taking the flak for promises his mentor Manohar Parrikar didn't keep.]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>These days, when government officials and politicians in Goa approach Chief Minister Laxmikant Parsekar for policy decisions, they get either of these two responses: Paatravank vicharche padattale (I need to consult Sir) or paatraav yetgat tharovya (let us decide when Sir comes). The 'Sir' in question is Manohar Parrikar, who might have bequeathed the chief ministership to Parsekar in November 2014 when he moved to Delhi as the Union minister for defence but who still seems to be ruling the state by proxy.</p><p>It was something Aam Aadmi Party convenor Arvind Kejriwal was quick to catch on to as he launched his party's campaign for assembly elections in the state next year. "The present government is a 'kathputli' (puppet) one," he declared at a rally in Panaji on May 23. "Parrikar concentrates less on defence and more on Goa."</p><p>The arrangement is proving costly for the incumbent BJP. Parsekar is unpopular with party MLAs because they feel he does not take them along. The RSS is unhappy with the government's continued grants to church-run English-medium schools, which it perceives as pandering to Catholics.</p><p>The Catholics, the new voters of the BJP, are in turn upset with the government for reneging on its promise to consult them on the regional development plan for villages.</p><p>{mosimage}The middle class is miffed that the government has backtracked on its intention to shift four casinos anchored on the Mandovi river to an alternative site. Not only did the government defer the decision by a year in March, it also issued a licence for a fifth casino.</p><p>There has also been no effort to arrest the culprits in the Rs 16,000 crore mining scam. Instead, Parrikar, tried to play down the scandal in November 2014, saying the loss to the state exchequer had been exaggerated. The ban on mining too was lifted in March 2015.</p><p>Discontent is also brewing among taxi drivers and fishermen, who accuse the government of turning a deaf ear to their demands. When taxi owners went on a two-day strike in April protesting digital meters and the competition from rent-a-car services, Parsekar made no attempt to talk to them. Nor has he made any effort to pacify local fishermen who have been agitating against the use of LED lights and bull trawling by commercial fishing operators, which they say puts them at a disadvantage.</p><p>It's a choppy sea, therefore, that the BJP seems to be negotiating a few months away from the election. Fighting the 2012 election on the plank of corruption in the Congress regime, the party had won 24 of Goa's 40 assembly seats in alliance with the Maharashtrawadi Gomantak Party (MGP).Today, AAP is looking to occupy the opposition space vacated by the faction-ridden Congress.</p><p>The BJP's-and Parsekar's-troubles began when Parrikar left for Delhi and chose Parsekar to run the government in his absence. Deputy CM Francis Souza, the second most senior person in the party, did stage a brief revolt, but that fizzled out after an unprecedented 15 of the 21 BJP MLAs supported Parsekar in a ballot.</p><p>Parsekar's first, and only, independent decision was to reject the demand for special status to Goa. In August 2015, he had announced that 40 workers of the Forum for Rights of Children to Education (FORCE) would be prosecuted for damaging public property during their agitation. Parrikar, however, made him withdraw the announcement.</p><p>The former CM apparently flies down every weekend and holds a durbar in his home town Parra in north Goa. Parsekar and his officials are summoned to his residence, where Parrikar looks at important files and issues directives to the CM. "Parsekar's only job is to nod his head at such meetings," says a BJP source. "He does not dare to take any big decision when Parrikar is not around."</p><p>Calangute BJP MLA Michael Lobo, however, denies Parrikar is remote controlling the government. "Parrikar has some great ideas on turning Goa into a developed, tourist-friendly state," he says. "If he feels things are not moving at a certain pace, he might give some instructions. You can't call it remote controlling."</p><p>Convincing the electorate, though, will be a different matter. Voters are unlikely to forgive what they perceive as the BJP's U-turns on the several assurances the party had incorporated in its 2012 election manifesto. Goa RSS chief Subhash Velingkar is especially chagrined at Parrikar's 'betrayal' over the grant to Catholic educational institutions. Velingkar had filed a petition against then CM Digambar Kamat's June 2011 decision to provide financial assistance to 136 church-run English-medium schools. Parrikar made him withdraw the petition, saying his government was about to announce a policy on the issue. "He made us wait for two years making sugarcoated conversations," says a livid Velingkar, a retired teacher. "A day before he resigned as CM, Manohar signed an order to continue the grant. It was a clear breach of trust." Parrikar, in fact, announced the decision before the press, keeping Velingkar in dark.</p><p>"Manohar thinks he can become an inclusive leader if he keeps the church happy," says Velingkar from his home in Panaji. "But most of Goa's Christians want Konkani, not English, as the medium of primary education."</p><p>On May 21, Velingkar gathered 3,000 people under the banner of the Bharatiya Bhasha Suraksha Manch (BBSM) at Mayem, around 18 km from Panaji, and took to the streets in protest. Giving Parsekar a deadline of October 2, Velingkar, who claims he is using money from his pension to run the agitation, said, "If the grant is not discontinued, we will create an alternative to the BJP and ensure the party loses the 2017 assembly elections." BBSM asserts that the grants to English medium-schools will strike a death blow to local languages.</p><p>D'Souza, however, denies that the BJP has made any U-turn on its election promises."It is our policy to provide grants to English-medium schools," he says. "We can have a rethink on it. As far as the mining scam is concerned, the Lokayukta has started an inquiry. As for the casinos, we can shift them to land instead of the deep sea."</p><p>Yet others find fault with Parsekar, not Parrikar, for bringing the BJP to this pass. The workaholic Parrikar put in 16-18 hour workdays, and travelled the countryside to oversee preparations for big events like the Goa carnival. Parsekar makes no such field trips. "Unlike bhai (Parrikar),"says a BJP legislator, "Parsekar prefers to operate out of his office or his official residence Mahalaxmi in Panaji."</p><p>Rohan Khaunte, an independent MLA from Porvorim, thinks Parsekar pushes Parrikar to decide on issues where a public backlash is expected, and takes decisions on other matters. Anyhow, the BJP will pay a heavy electoral price for Parrikar's U-turns, he says. "He promised us the moon but did not even give us its shadow."</p><p>Political observers believe that the BJP might lose seven to eight seats in north Goa where the BBSM has intensified its agitation, down from the present 21. The BBSM is also working at weaning away BJP ally MGP or fielding independent candidates against the BJP. "We will not vote for the Congress and will not allow the BJP to retain the CM's chair if our demand is not met," Velingkar says.</p><p>AAP could make inroads into the Congress bastion of South Goa. Congress president Luizinho Faleiro, however, claims AAP will not be able to displace the party as people still have faith in the Congress.</p><p>Sensing trouble, the Goa BJP had organised a two-day self-assessment camp for its legislators at the RSS-run Rambhau Mhalgi Prabodhini training institute in Mumbai in the first week of May. Speaking at the camp, Parrikar advised Parsekar to focus on fulfilling the leftover promises in the last year of his tenure to win back the state. Parsekar listened carefully, no doubt, intent on overturning a popular superstition in Goa: that no CM staying in official residence 'Mahalaxmi' has returned to power.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><div align="right"><b>Follow the writer on Twitter @kirantare</b></div><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[Goa chief minister Laxmikant Parsekar is taking the flak for promises his mentor Manohar Parrikar didn't keep.]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>226601</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[As AAP threat looms, why it is curtains for the BJP in Goa]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Curtains for the BJP?]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Curtains for the BJP?]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>1</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/goa-laxmikant-parsekar-manohar-parrikar/1/682907.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[As AAP threat looms, why it is curtains for the BJP in Goa]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/goa-jun13-1_647_060216114655.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[As AAP threat looms, why it is curtains for the BJP in Goa]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/goa-jun13-1_647_060216114655.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[goa-laxmikant-parsekar-manohar-parrikar]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[As AAP threat looms, why it is curtains for the BJP in Goa]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[Goa chief minister,Laxmikant Parsekar,Manohar Parrikar]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>