<story>
<id>682915</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>yes</story_issue>
<select_magazine>1557</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date>June 13, 2016</issue_date><bylines>
<byline>1253</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464794336</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464794336</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1464941371</modifieddate>
<createdby>802</createdby>
<modifiedby>802</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city/>
</cities>
<categories><category>279686</category><category>279730</category><category>280225</category></categories><ordering>682909</ordering><primarycategory>279730</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/upfront-jun13-2_647_060216124603.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt/>
<extra_large_title/>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/upfront-jun13-2_305_060216124603.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt/>
<large_title/>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/upfront-jun13-2_300_060216124603.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt/>
<mediumimage_title/>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/upfront-jun13-2_180_060216124603.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt/>
<smallimage_title/>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/upfront-jun13-2_88_060216124603.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt/>
<extra_small_title/>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption/>
<mosimage>
<image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/upfront1_060216124622.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[Itty Abraham]]></caption></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[Under the provisions of the draft Geospatial Information Regulation Bill, even the guy selling pictures of Bharat Mata outside the local temple is not safe.]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>The Geospatial Bill imposes the paranoia and restrictions of an analogue age on a digital India. Many readers will remember signs once prominently displayed at dams, bridges, airports and other infrastructural monuments to Nehruvian nation-building that prohibited taking photographs of these 'sensitive installations'. Since most of us didn't have cameras anyway, or if we did, wouldn't use them to photograph a dam when there were friends waiting to be immortalised on expensive film, this prohibition didn't cause us much grief. Rather, it helped reinforce the idea of the state as a precious and omniscient force in our middle-class lives. That the link between a small dam on the Periyar river and national security was tenuous was not something we stopped to think about: if the sign said it was true, then that was all we needed to know.</p><p>{mosimage}Like me, some of my peers went abroad for higher studies only to face the shock of our lives when we saw how India was represented in maps overseas. I remember protesting to my professor that a prominently displayed classroom map of India was incorrect and that Kashmir did not look like that-as if it had been nibbled on. He heard me out and then informed me that the areas I thought were missing from the map had been under Pakistani control since 1947. It is difficult, decades later, to describe the shock I felt when something I took to be unquestionably true turned out not to be so. Could it be true that the maps I had learned to draw so painstakingly in geography class were not accurate? What else that I took to be true was not?</p><p>One response to this youthful crisis of representation is to become a sceptic. Another is to go into denial. It appears that the latter position dominates the minds of the authors of the draft Geospatial Information Regulation Bill, 2016, now available for public comment and discussion. The subtext of the bill is that if you don't accept the boundaries of India that the state says are true and correct, you can be punished with fines up to Rs 100 crore and possible imprisonment up to seven years. Up to seven years of imprisonment for illegally acquiring, disseminating, publishing or distributing India's 'geospatial information'? That seems a little severe by any standard when this information is freely available on the web and is sitting in libraries around the world. If the idea is to prevent state enemies from gaining access to maps and geo-tagged images they can use to plan their deadly projects-the logic behind the original prohibition I encountered as a student-it's already too late.</p><p>The bill creates a vetting authority whose job is 'protecting national security, sovereignty, safety and integrity' but the severity of these punishments offers a different reading. Clearly, the intended audience for fines of this magnitude is the corporate sector, Indian and foreign. Who else could afford these fines? And here lies the unresolved tension in the bill. It begins with an 'analog' conception of territorial integrity as national security and seeks to protect that conception in the digital age. The bill targets a range of evildoers, from terrorists to digital corporates; the problem is, it is unsure which is the greater enemy.</p><p>Geospatial information, according to the draft bill, is 'imagery' and 'data' acquired from 'aerial platforms' that can visualise and record 'natural or man-made physical features, phenomenon or boundaries of the earth, from drones in the near above to satellites further up there'. But also, the bill covers geospatial documents, including charts, maps and photos that have spatial tags of any kind. This is just the kind of definition that keeps lawyers rich. Under the enormously wide-ranging provisions of the draft bill, every social media and internet company is in trouble. Any Indian employee of Facebook or Google working anywhere in the world could potentially be arrested if a user uploads an 'incorrect' image of India into their proprietary systems. These false images could include the classroom map that I complained about as a student or a conceptual artist's Photoshopped vision of India 2020 or even the guy selling pictures of Bharat Mata outside the local temple.</p><p>Due to limitations of space, it is not possible to raise additional issues of serious concern, from the lack of due process in the enforcement provisions to the claim to universal jurisdiction. But the bottom line is this. This effort to control spatial images of India has not come to terms with the digital age, even as the bill clearly sees new digital media and technologies as the problem to be addressed. Moreover, demanding that geospatial representations of India be 'correct' won't change conditions on the ground; it will merely suppress public knowledge of the gap between state claims and lived reality.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><div align="right"><i><b>Itty Abraham teaches at the National University of Singapore. His latest book, How India Became Territorial: Foreign Policy, Diaspora, Geopolitics, is published by Stanford University Press</b></i></div><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[Under the provisions of the draft Geospatial Information Regulation Bill, even the guy selling pictures of Bharat Mata outside the local temple is not safe.]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>354325</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Neither correct nor authentic]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Neither correct nor authentic]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Neither correct nor authentic]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>0</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/geospatial-information-regulation-bill/1/682915.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Neither correct nor authentic]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/upfront-jun13-2_647_060216124603.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Neither correct nor authentic]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/upfront-jun13-2_647_060216124603.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[geospatial-information-regulation-bill]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Neither correct nor authentic]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[Geospatial Information Regulation Bill]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>