<story>
<id>682911</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>yes</story_issue>
<select_magazine>1557</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date>June 13, 2016</issue_date><bylines>
<byline>290</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464794332</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464794332</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1465210540</modifieddate>
<createdby>802</createdby>
<modifiedby>802</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city/>
</cities>
<categories><category>279362</category><category>279686</category><category>280225</category></categories><ordering>682911</ordering><primarycategory>279362</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/letters-jun13-3_647_060216120801.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt/>
<extra_large_title/>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/letters-jun13-3_305_060216120801.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt/>
<large_title/>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/letters-jun13-3_300_060216120801.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt/>
<mediumimage_title/>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/letters-jun13-3_180_060216120801.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt/>
<smallimage_title/>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/letters-jun13-3_88_060216120801.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt/>
<extra_small_title/>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption/>
<mosimage>
<image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/letters1_060216120859.jpg]]></image><caption/><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/letters2_060216120859.jpg]]></image><caption/></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[<p>Your survey points to the continuing gap between traditional toppers 
Delhi, Maharashtra and the South and the yet-to-take-off states such as 
Bihar, Uttar Pradesh and West Bengal.</p>]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p><b>Best Colleges of India </b></p><p><b>May 30, 2016</b><br />India Today's pick of the top colleges for undergraduate students<br /></p><p>Your survey points to the continuing gap between traditional toppers Delhi, Maharashtra and the South and the yet-to-take-off states such as Bihar, Uttar Pradesh and West Bengal.</p><p><i><b>R Namasivayam, Nagpur</b></i></p><p><b>College hunting grounds</b><br />Going through your cover story Make your Alma Mat(t)er, I kept wondering about the many fine institutions that I know of, through family and friends who have studied there and vouched for its credentials. Only at the end of the survey, on page 128 to be precise, did I get the real picture. One would expect a magazine of your status and credibility to put this information (Missing In Action) right at the beginning of an otherwise great package. An even better approach would be to include these institutions on the basis of data available in the public domain.<br /><i><b>Harsh Kalra, via e-mail</b></i></p><p>Paise ko paisa kheenchta hai (Money begets money), so goes an old Hindi saying. Commercialisation of education as we know it today runs on donations, favours, tuition fees and incidental expenses such as hostel charges and laboratory fees. Education is a constitutional right, but opportunities of higher education are denied to the common man. Parents who earn a few thousand rupees a month do not have the luxury of spending lakhs on educating their children. It is a sorry state of affairs.<br /><i><b>Mahesh Kapasi, New Delhi</b></i></p><p>I read with disbelief the section in your cover story titled Which City is Good for your Course. Kolkata hosts some of the finest colleges in the country, which have produced Nobel laureates, scientists, authors, performers, music maestros and so on. The poor quality of your assessment is evident. You have put Hansraj College in New Delhi at No. 5 position in a nod to the fact that Shah Rukh Khan studied there. It is simply appalling that Presidency College or St Xavier's found no place in your list seemingly because no Bollywood superstar studied there.<br /><i><b>Shyamal Dutta, Kolkata</b></i></p><p>Congratulations on yet another 'gold standard' in guides for students to decide on their colleges at the end of their school education. The fact that there is very little churning in the 'top 10' is reassuring but is also cause for worry at the same time. Obviously not many-barring a few 'emerging' colleges-are making an effort to enter the hallowed league.<br /><i><b>Krishan Kalra, via e-mail</b></i></p><p>While your survey provides valuable insight into the best educational institutes in India, none of these ranks anywhere near the best in the world. This should have been the real challenge and priority for the present government, which instead is embroiled in street fights with university students.<br /><i><b>R Namasivayam, Nagpur</b></i></p><p><b>{mosimage}Under duress</b><br />The escalation of conflict between Punjab and Haryana over the Sutlej-Yamuna Link is a direct consequence of rising water scarcity (Digging in for a Fight). The data is distressing: of the 20 major river systems, 14 are water stressed, with 75 per cent of the total population living in water-stressed regions. Moreover, climate change, increased pace of urbanisation and the demands of a burgeoning population are adding to woes. Punjab has made an emotional argument for Ravi, Beas and Sutlej's exemption from water-sharing by virtue of the three largely flowing through the state. But, the water-sharing agreement is a legacy of undivided Punjab and should be respected. During floods, Punjab politicians were quick to blame Haryana for not taking the excess water. There is much at stake in the harmonious resolution of these disputes; the Centre must not postpone the 'inconvenient' issue for another day.<br /><i><b>JS Acharya, Hyderabad</b></i></p><p><b>Only himself to blame</b><br />Bullet Raj was a possibility Nitish Kumar should have expected when he chose to align with Lalu Prasad Yadav for the assembly elections in Bihar last November (Bullet Raj in Bihar). He has to nip it in the bud before the situation escalates and gets out of control. It will not be easy, though, given that Lalu's Rashtriya Janata Dal has the higher numbers in the assembly. Nitish is about to learn, as you sow, so shall you reap.<br /><i><b>Ashutosh Puntambekar, via-e-mail</b></i></p><p><b>For an elevated minority status</b><br />Much like the Parsis, the Jews are a small but significant minority in the country (Minority Report). Of the many strands of Jewish community in India, the Bene Israeli lineage is unclear. They are settled predominantly in Mumbai. In the early 19th century, Baghdadi Jews settled around Bombay and their members such as the Sassoon family and the late Lt General J.F.R. Jacob are renowned for their contribution to society. It is interesting that prime minister Indira Gandhi made Pakistan surrender to General Jacob, a Jew. Gen Jacob apparently once said, "The only place I encountered anti-Semitism was from the British in the army, among Indians it doesn't exist."<br /><i><b>HN Ramakrishna, Bengaluru</b></i></p><p>Indian Jews have assimilated into the Indian mainstream well and-unlike their fellow Jews elsewhere- have rarely faced anti-Semitism. The hostility Muslims harbour towards Israel does not extend to Indian Jews. The Indian Jewish community's renewed plea for minority status is an attempt at acquiring security. The renovation of the Thane synagogue, a grade II-B heritage structure, faced stiff resistance from the Thane Municipal Corporation with the community repeatedly bearing the brunt of land acquisitions. With official recognition as a minority group, they think their land would enjoy better protection. The minority status would also bestow benefits such as easy registration of marriages and 50 per cent seats reserved in educational institutions. Given the atmosphere of friendliness between India and Israel now, the longstanding demand has a chance of seeing the light of day.<br /><i><b>Nalini Vijayaraghavan, Thiruvananthapuram</b></i></p><p><b>{mosimage}Guilty by default</b><br />With all due regard to the great jurist, Soli Sorabjee's criticism of the Supreme Court ruling on the constitutional validity of Section 499 of the IPC is not credible (Upfront/Between Two Rights, a Wrong). It does not impinge on one's right to free speech. It declares that if anyone conveys orally or in writing false information about someone, they will be punished. The SC's decision to maintain balance between free speech and the right to reputation is a wise one. The 'chilling effect' argument is not sustainable. The possibility of misuse or delay in judicial processes are not grounds to declare a well-established provision of law unconstitutional. We often witness leaders of political parties engaging in hate speeches and character assassination. If the element of criminality in defamation is removed, it can give free rein to causing insult and injury with mere payment of damages. The courts should take extra care in handling criminal cases of defamation and clear them expeditiously.<br /><i><b>MK Bhandari, Dehradun</b></i></p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[<p>Your survey points to the continuing gap between traditional toppers 
Delhi, Maharashtra and the South and the yet-to-take-off states such as 
Bihar, Uttar Pradesh and West Bengal.</p>]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>274185</tag>
<tag>251160</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Mails and letters to the editor]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Mails and letters to the editor]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Mails and letters to the editor]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>0</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/mails-and-letters-to-the-editor/1/682911.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Mails and letters to the editor]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/letters-jun13-3_647_060216120801.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Mails and letters to the editor]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/letters-jun13-3_647_060216120801.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[mails-and-letters-to-the-editor]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Mails and letters to the editor]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[Mails,Letters]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>