<story>
<id>682909</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>yes</story_issue>
<select_magazine>1557</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date>June 13, 2016</issue_date><bylines>
<byline>445</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464794329</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464794329</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1465210027</modifieddate>
<createdby>802</createdby>
<modifiedby>802</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city/>
</cities>
<categories><category>279686</category><category>279749</category><category>280225</category></categories><ordering>683085</ordering><primarycategory>279749</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/jat-divide-jun13-1_647_060216115724.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt><![CDATA[Suresh Sharma, mall owner]]></extra_large_alt>
<extra_large_title><![CDATA[Suresh Sharma, mall owner]]></extra_large_title>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/jat-divide-jun13-1_305_060216115724.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt><![CDATA[Suresh Sharma, mall owner]]></large_alt>
<large_title><![CDATA[Suresh Sharma, mall owner]]></large_title>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/jat-divide-jun13-1_300_060216115724.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt><![CDATA[Suresh Sharma, mall owner]]></mediumimage_alt>
<mediumimage_title><![CDATA[Suresh Sharma, mall owner]]></mediumimage_title>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/jat-divide-jun13-1_180_060216115724.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt><![CDATA[Suresh Sharma, mall owner]]></smallimage_alt>
<smallimage_title><![CDATA[Suresh Sharma, mall owner]]></smallimage_title>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/jat-divide-jun13-1_88_060216115724.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt><![CDATA[Suresh Sharma, mall owner]]></extra_small_alt>
<extra_small_title><![CDATA[Suresh Sharma, mall owner]]></extra_small_title>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption><![CDATA[Suresh Sharma, mall owner | His popular RN Mall in Rohtak was set ablaze by rioting Jats. Photo: M Zhazo]]></kicker_image_caption>
<mosimage>
<image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/jat3_060216115820.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[Jagmohan Mittal, Auto king - His spanking new Maruti Suzuki Nexa showroom was burnt down two days after opening; 200 ready-to-deliver cars, SUVs destroyed at his stockyard]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/jat2_060216115820.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[Mukesh Kumar, Bookshop owner - Had taken a Rs 30 lakh loan to stock up on academic books ahead of the new school/college session. A small PC kiosk he had set up recently was also burnt down]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/jat1_060216115820.jpg]]></image><caption/></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[The three-day orgy of violence in February has ruptured the state's social fabric, pitting Jats against others. Here's why Haryana is now sitting on a social powder keg.]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>Bhaisaab, you should get someone more trustworthy," a businessman in Rohtak presses an old friend glumly, dwelling on the "perils" of employing a Jat as his driver. "I don't like the way he constantly seems to eavesdrop," he says. But Jagmohan Mittal, better known as 'Haryana's Auto King' with a string of Maruti-Suzuki showrooms across the Jat-dominated southern districts, says he doesn't really have a choice.</p><p>Mittal, whose spanking new Nexa showroom along the Delhi Bypass in Rohtak was gutted by Jat arsonists just two days after it was inaugurated on February 18 (nearly 200 ready-for-delivery cars and SUVs were reduced to cinder at his stockyard on the city's outskirts), appears completely bewildered. "I employ over 5,000 people and a man's caste had never before been a concern," says the businessman who carried out a quiet caste audit of his workers in the wake of the quota agitation. "Close to 70 per cent are Jats," he says, somewhat surprised himself. And though he isn't planning any mass retrenchments, the sheer scale of the violence and the Manohar Lal Khattar government's evident inability to tackle the agitators have set him thinking.</p><p>{mosimage}There is a never-before sense of distrust, a discernible wariness that is pervasive throughout the Haryanvi hinterland today. Three days and nights of abject mayhem and the unprecedented collapse of the police and civil administration this February, have sharpened caste identities dangerously-the Jats on one side pitted against the rest of the 35 castes that constitute Haryana society, the paintees biradari. And although not immediately apparent to outsiders, the streetscape is completely altered -the usually loud, raucous conversations are more whispered; it's now routine to look over one's shoulder; the non-Jat (Punjabi, Saini, Brahmin, Baniya) shop owners in the bazaars are visibly subdued.</p><p>Gulshan Rai Tandon, 74, a retired state electricity board employee in Sonepat's Gohana town, sees distressing parallels in the carnage with his Partition childhood. "It was like 1947 all over again, the fear, the morbid insecurity, the acrid stench of burning homes and shops," he says, recounting how his family was forced to flee from their ancestral home in what is now Pakistan. "It is time to move again," he said to his son this February 20.</p><p>Like elsewhere, in the small towns and cities across the eight riot-torn districts-Rohtak, Sonepat, Jhajjar, Kaithal, Jind, Bhiwani, Hisar and Panipat-Gohana witnessed some of the worst violence, with Jat mobs from the surrounding villages armed with Molotov cocktails, firearms and pickaxes methodically targeting non-Jat establishments, looting shops before fire-bombing them. All this under the 'watchful' eyes of the police, district administration officers and army columns that inexplicably backed off from confronting the arsonists.</p><p>"Yaad kar ke rooh kaamp jaati hai (My soul shivers when I recall it all)," says Mohit Tandon, whose bookstore, nondescriptly tucked into a corner of Gohana's Civil Road, was miraculously spared. But like others whose very livelihoods were consigned to flames, the 40-year-old shopkeeper is paying a stiff price. He is constrained to abandon Gohana, the only home he's known. "Even if I decided to carry on here, there is simply no way I am going to expose my children to the continuing trauma of living amidst all this fear and loathing," he says. Recalling the first day his eight-year-old son went back to school after the riots, he says, "Can you imagine, the burnt down shops is all they talked about in class...it was like the Jat children versus the rest."</p><p>So Mohit is moving out. For the time being, only his family will move into the rented accommodation he has found in what he hopes will be a relatively safer Karnal city. He plans to stay back because "it's not easy to uproot and move the business to a new place".</p><p>{mosimage}The Tandons are not the only ones seeking safer havens outside Jatland. Mukesh Kumar, 49, had freshly stocked his bookshop which sells academic books, as he usually does ahead of the new session. "After they (the rioters) filled up trollies with whatever they could use or sell, they torched the place," he says, visibly close to tears. A small computer kiosk he had set up just recently in a space next door, was also burnt down. "The shops were all that kept my family alive," he says.</p><p>"I will leave this infernal place, one hundred per cent," says Mukesh. But for now, he has to wait. For even if he wanted to sell his shop, there are simply no takers in Gohana, and it's the same in any place that witnessed the February violence. In Rohtak, realtors say property prices have fallen by as much as 60 per cent.</p><p>For the moment, besides the Rs 30 lakh bank loan he took to restock the shop, there is some respite from the compensation the Khattar government paid shop owners with claims under Rs 1 crore. "What's the point of staying on?" Mukesh asks, insisting that local Jats even resent the fact that the government has tried to partially compensate their losses.</p><p>Further down Civil Road, Jaipal Sharma, 45, a former Indian Air Force sergeant, seems much more financially sound but is equally despairing. "This was no agitation for reservations," he says insisting that even though they were Jats, the crowd that attacked were essentially "looters who came and did what they had to, fully confident that neither the police nor the soldiers would lift a finger to stop them".</p><p>Sharma points to two key facts: firstly, that the mobs happily targeted shops owned by Brahmins, Baniyas and Punjabis, despite the fact that none of these communities was opposed to or in contention with Jats in seeking a quota as backward castes. Second: they came in past noon on February 20, safe in the knowledge that the administration had imposed a curfew and the shop owners would not be around to protect their businesses.</p><p>The fear, Sharma and other shopkeepers of Gohana say, has still not abated. "We are forced to live amidst the very people who attacked us and they seem to have gotten away scot-free," he says pointing to the fact that even three months on, the police have made few arrests and absolutely no recoveries of the looted goods.</p><p>Sanjay Mehndiratta, a mithai shop owner, says local villagers are openly moving around on the scooters looted from his elder brother's two-wheeler Honda agency in Gohana. "They (police) can see it but there is no move to book the looters. It's simply not a priority for them. And the culprits are confident that since they got away with it once, they can do it again," says Sharma, reluctantly disclosing that "many of those who accompanied the looters, continue to threaten us".</p><p>{mosimage}Former Nagaland and Uttar Pradesh DGP, Prakash Singh, 80, who has been unforgiving in his 414-page report to the Khattar government on the abdication of duty by the police and civil administration, is equally worried about what could well become an irrevocable caste divide across the state.</p><p>"It was to all intents and purposes an agitation for reservation but the issue receded into the background," Singh told India Today. Charting the year-long build-up ahead of February's violence, Singh describes in detail the venomous statements and public speeches by leaders on both sides of Haryana's caste cauldron-Jats like the Akhil Bharatiya Jat Aarakshan Sangharsh Samiti (ABJASS) chief Yashpal Malik and Hawa Singh Sangwan, as well as Kurukshetra MP Raj Kumar Saini, a highly voluble OBC leader.</p><p>Singh says he is "astounded that state officials failed to take note of the vituperative caste confrontation in the state. Every one of those speeches (reproduced in Devanagari text in the body of his report) is actionable under the law." Admitting that the only way to try and salvage and repair the societal faultlines in Haryana today would be to ensure accountability and punishment of the guilty, the former top cop insists this must include "not just the officials, but equally all the culprits".</p><p>Rajinder Chaudhary, 55, a former professor of economics at Rohtak's Maharishi Dayanand University who now concerns himself with people's issues, agrees that the central reason for the deepening insecurity is the state government's reluctance to act against the perpetrators. Chaudhary toured the eight violence-impacted districts as part of an unofficial 'people's commission', and his contention is borne out by what Prakash Singh describes as the "pathetic arrest figures" in the wake of the scores of instances of rioting. Consider these numbers: just 593 accused were arrested against 2,124 FIRs registered by the Haryana police. As many as 345 of those arrested have already been let off on bail.</p><p>Chaudhary, worryingly, points to the fact that a majority of the non-Jats whose homes and shops were destroyed "haven't even begun rebuilding". He believes this is a precursor to a migration where non-Jats will find ways to move out of Jat-dominated areas. But wait, there's worse to come. In Sonepat, a Jat-dominated district where business is controlled by non-Jat 'refugees', shopkeepers in the city say they have armed themselves. "The next time this nonsense happens, we will be ready. Next time no Punjabi, Saini or anyone else will die without a Jat falling first," shopkeepers told the Prakash Singh committee.</p><p>Back in Rohtak city, Suresh Sharma, 55, a businessman whose highly popular RN Mall was set ablaze, refuses to be cowed down. Having lost crores after the rioters torched Rohtak's only McDonald's restaurant and two plush Gold Class PVR cinemas, he is now preparing to fight back. "This time they (Jats) took us by surprise in collusion with the administration. If there is a next time, we will be waiting for them," Sharma told India Today on May 28, even as Haryana's Jat leadership declared that they would renew their agitation from June 5.</p><p>In the first official admission since the violence finally ended on February 24, Haryana finance minister and one-time CM hopeful Capt Abhimanyu conceded that the state had failed. Declining comment on the actions or lapses by individual officers or politicians, Abhimanyu says that on May 27 there had been a "complete failure of the administrative, intelligence and law and order machinery". He acknowledged the growing "mistrust" between Jats and other communities, but insisted the violence (his ancestral home and other property in Rohtak was attacked too) was politically driven.</p><p>Whatever the case, Haryana is clearly sitting atop a veritable tinderbox, where any future caste confrontation could result in carnage. This is something that both chief minister Khattar, and the politicians that oppose him, need to ponder over.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><div align="right"><i><b>Follow the writer on Twitter @Asitjolly</b></i></div><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[The three-day orgy of violence in February has ruptured the state's social fabric, pitting Jats against others. Here's why Haryana is now sitting on a social powder keg.]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>226671</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Jat quota agitation: Why Haryana is sitting on a social powder keg]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Failed state]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Failed state]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>1</like>
<dislike>1</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/jat-agitation-reservation-haryana/1/682909.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Jat quota agitation: Why Haryana is sitting on a social powder keg]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/jat-divide-jun13-1_647_060216115724.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Jat quota agitation: Why Haryana is sitting on a social powder keg]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/jat-divide-jun13-1_647_060216115724.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[jat-agitation-reservation-haryana]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Jat quota agitation: Why Haryana is sitting on a social powder keg]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[Jat agitation,Jat Reservation,Unrest in Haryana]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>