<story>
<id>682908</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>yes</story_issue>
<select_magazine>1557</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date>June 13, 2016</issue_date><bylines>
<byline>269</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464794328</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464794328</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1464936376</modifieddate>
<createdby>802</createdby>
<modifiedby>802</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city/>
</cities>
<categories><category>279686</category><category>279591</category><category>280225</category></categories><ordering>682915</ordering><primarycategory>279591</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/iran-jun13-1_647_060216114839.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt><![CDATA[PM Modi with Iranian president Hassan Rouhani ]]></extra_large_alt>
<extra_large_title><![CDATA[PM Modi with Iranian president Hassan Rouhani ]]></extra_large_title>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/iran-jun13-1_305_060216114839.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt><![CDATA[PM Modi with Iranian president Hassan Rouhani ]]></large_alt>
<large_title><![CDATA[PM Modi with Iranian president Hassan Rouhani ]]></large_title>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/iran-jun13-1_300_060216114839.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt><![CDATA[PM Modi with Iranian president Hassan Rouhani ]]></mediumimage_alt>
<mediumimage_title><![CDATA[PM Modi with Iranian president Hassan Rouhani ]]></mediumimage_title>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/iran-jun13-1_180_060216114839.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt><![CDATA[PM Modi with Iranian president Hassan Rouhani ]]></smallimage_alt>
<smallimage_title><![CDATA[PM Modi with Iranian president Hassan Rouhani ]]></smallimage_title>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/iran-jun13-1_88_060216114838.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt><![CDATA[PM Modi with Iranian president Hassan Rouhani ]]></extra_small_alt>
<extra_small_title><![CDATA[PM Modi with Iranian president Hassan Rouhani ]]></extra_small_title>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption><![CDATA[PM Modi with Iranian president Hassan Rouhani at their joint press conference. Photo: PTI]]></kicker_image_caption>
<mosimage>
<image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/iran1_060216115106.jpg]]></image><caption/></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[India's trade agreements with Iran are a beginning but outstanding issues need to be speedily resolved to reap the benefits.]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>For the past five years, India and Iran have engaged in an irate correspondence over an Iranian firm. Iran's largest fibre optic manufacturer, Sim Noor Pooya Co., bagged a 2010 contract to work with India's Power Grid Corporation. The deal went sour after contractual disagreements. Power Grid is yet to pay the Iranian firm for services rendered because they didn't get approvals to pay the Iranian company in India and refused to pay in a third country (as Iran was still under sanctions). The Iranian firm claims to have lost about 2 million euros in the dispute, which is yet to be resolved. "This is a typical example of business getting lost in systemic, procedural issues. Without solving banking issues, how can anybody do business in a country?" asks Pervinder Singh Chandok, vice-president of the Tehran-based India-Iran Chamber of Commerce and Industry. Chandok represents one of the oldest Indian families in Iran and has been witness to the peaks and troughs of Indo-Iran relations.</p><p>{mosimage}The latest high was Prime Minister Narendra Modi's visit to Iran between May 22 and 23, where he signed 12 deals with his Iranian counterpart Hassan Rouhani. The centrepiece iswathe Chabahar port agreement. India is to invest about $500 million (Rs 34,000 crore) in developing a port and related infrastructure over 10 years. The strategically located Chabahar, just 1,000 km from Gujarat, will be India's gateway to the land-locked Central Asian countries and Afghanistan. Currently, over 80 per cent of India's total imports from Iran comprise mineral products. Agro and allied products, including processed food, make for about 40 per cent of India's exports to Iran. The growth potential lies across these sectors, including textiles, pharmaceuticals and services such as consultancy and telecom.</p><p>Traders say that Chabahar provides a much required trading route with Central Asia, bypassing a hostile Pakistan. The Federation of Indian Exporters Organisation (FIEO) estimates a 30 per cent reduction in freight costs through this new route.</p><p>The first phase of the Chabahar port will become operational within 18 months. "Once you have the proximity to Chabahar, Central Asia and Afghanistan, we can look at a quantum jump in exports and a big boost in services," says Ajay Sahai of the FIEO.</p><p>India's trade with Central Asia is less than two per cent of its total exports. The FIEO hopes to more than double trade with Central Asian countries like Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan and Uzbekistan to about $10 billion in the next five years (from $3-4 billion today).</p><p>Of course, all this will depend on India's relationship with Iran, which till now can at best be characterised as ambivalent. Tanvi Madan of the Brookings Institution explains: "There were problems in the mid-2000s- practical negotiating issues. Iranians are tough negotiators. To implement the port agreement, three countries (Iran, India and Afghanistan) have to be interested at the same time."</p><p>Prasanna Sarambale, group vice-president, Sterling and Wilson Private Limited, recalls the enthusiasm Iranians displayed during his visit there as part of a CII delegation, about 20 days before the prime minister's visit. "Iran has a huge deficit of automobiles and is looking at Indian firms to set up base there." In May this year, India and Iran reached an agreement to use European banks to clear the $6.4 billion of pending oil payments to Tehran. However, the two countries are yet to negotiate details on how funds will flow in and out of Iran for bilateral trade.</p><p>Many exporters have received orders and even advances in euros and other foreign currencies in the past, but in the absence of RBI instructions, the money has had to be remitted and orders were lost to the advantage of India's competitors. Exporters worry that if the issue of receipt of payment in foreign currency for exports to Iran is not resolved, trade could actually come to a complete halt.</p><p>The fact that Indian banks don't have a presence in Iran doesn't help much. Grant of credit lines is another important issue for a country struggling with the impact of sanctions. Italy and South Korea have already extended cheaper, longer duration credit lines to Iran. India's Exim Bank has extended buyers' credit under the NEIA (National Export Insurance Account) but only for steel plates and rails for the economic corridor India is building in Iran. This needs to be extended to other items of trade. Clearly, India has some distance to go before it realises the potential of its Central Asian gateway.</p><div align="right"><i><b>Follow the writer on Twitter @shwetapunj</b></i></div><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[India's trade agreements with Iran are a beginning but outstanding issues need to be speedily resolved to reap the benefits.]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>222581</tag>
<tag>225305</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Beyond the India, Iran handshake: What Modi should do next]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Beyond the handshake]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Beyond the handshake]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>2</like>
<dislike>3</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/indo-iran-ties-modi-rouhani-trade-agreements/1/682908.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Beyond the India, Iran handshake: What Modi should do next]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/iran-jun13-1_647_060216114839.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Beyond the India, Iran handshake: What Modi should do next]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/iran-jun13-1_647_060216114839.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[indo-iran-ties-modi-rouhani-trade-agreements]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Beyond the India, Iran handshake: What Modi should do next]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[Indo-Iran ties,Modi-Rouhani,India Iran Trade agreements]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>