<story>
<id>682910</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>yes</story_issue>
<select_magazine>1557</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date>June 13, 2016</issue_date><bylines>
<byline>414</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464794331</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464794331</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1464934907</modifieddate>
<createdby>802</createdby>
<modifiedby>802</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city/>
</cities>
<categories><category>279349</category><category>279686</category><category>280225</category></categories><ordering>682910</ordering><primarycategory>279349</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/cover_647_060316080735.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt/>
<extra_large_title/>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/cover_305_060316080735.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt/>
<large_title/>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/cover_300x350_060316080735.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt/>
<mediumimage_title/>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/cover_180_060316080735.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt/>
<smallimage_title/>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/cover_88_060316080735.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt/>
<extra_small_title/>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption/>
<mosimage>
<image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/editorsnote1_060216120616.jpg]]></image><caption/></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[Although our country is perennially in election mode, there is always an
 extra edge to the poll drama in UP, which has traditionally been the 
nerve-centre of Indian politics.]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>With the recent assembly elections behind us-giving the BJP a boost, highlighting the continuing might of regional satraps, and pushing the Congress further into the abyss-the 2017 Uttar Pradesh polls are now on the radar of the major political parties. This was the state from where the NDA stormed to power in the 2014 general elections with 71 out of 80 Lok Sabha seats. Any Opposition front against the Narendra Modi government will have to treat it as the semi-final before the big fight in 2019.</p><p>{mosimage}Although our country is perennially in election mode, there is always an extra edge to the poll drama in UP, which has traditionally been the nerve-centre of Indian politics. It elects almost 15 per cent of the Lok Sabha, and eight of our 14 prime ministers have called it their home. But Uttar Pradesh has also been synonymous with bad governance, extreme poverty, and deep caste and religious divisions. Of the two principal regional parties in the state, the Bahujan Samaj Party (BSP) led by Mayawati is scoffed at for its alleged corruption scandals, just as the Samajwadi Party (SP) led by Mulayam Singh Yadav is derided for its alleged 'goonda raj'.</p><p>That is why the 2012 assembly election results were seen as a watershed. On the back of a huge victory, Mulayam promoted his 38-year-old son Akhilesh as chief minister. An engineer by education, Akhilesh had run the campaign on a development platform, turning the ideology of his party on its head by embracing modernity and promising law and order. He sidelined candidates who had criminal cases against them, and even his big dole idea of distributing free laptops to meritorious students had a hi-tech twist to it.</p><p>Over the next few years, however, the state waited in vain for Akhilesh to assert himself. Kept on a tight leash by his father, and hemmed in by a party too set in its ways to embrace change, his government seemed no different from other SP regimes. Law and order deteriorated, and several appalling crimes broke the spirit of an electorate craving for development. The chief minister was regarded as too soft, disinterested in policy matters, and unable to stamp his personality on the government.</p><p>It seems to have taken the 2014 Lok Sabha elections, in which SP won just five seats, to finally jolt Akhilesh into action. With defeat looming in 2017, he suddenly changed gears by pushing big-ticket projects. These include a 320 kilometre Lucknow-Agra expressway, four-lane highways connecting 44 district headquarters, the Lucknow metro and an IT City. Akhilesh is getting the work done at double-quick speed. He desperately wants something to showcase from his first term in office to keep the marching armies of the Opposition at bay, and to establish his primacy within a Yadav family that has more than a dozen members in various levels of politics.</p><p>For this week's cover, Executive Editor Kunal Pradhan and Group Photo Editor Bandeep Singh went to Lucknow to analyse Uttar Pradesh's complicated political equation. Pradhan travelled with Akhilesh to Saifai and, for the cover photo, Singh shot him after a hard day of monitoring projects in the afternoon sun. "He woke up late, but for a man who had been virtually written off in 2014, Akhilesh seems much more in control now," Pradhan says.</p><p>A lot of water will flow under the bridge before the elections. BJP president Amit Shah is looking to use the state as a gateway for Modi's 2019 re-election campaign, and Mayawati is on the comeback trail after four years on the margins. In the face of these challenges, the state's young chief minister seems to have realised-even if belatedly-that development, and development alone, is the calling card that matters. Whether he will succeed or not is another matter, but a battle royale is in the offing.</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[Although our country is perennially in election mode, there is always an
 extra edge to the poll drama in UP, which has traditionally been the 
nerve-centre of Indian politics.]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>223121</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[From the Editor-in-Chief]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[From the Editor-in-Chief]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[From the Editor-in-Chief]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>0</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/from-the-editor-in-chief-aroon-purie-akhilesh-yadav-up-assembly-election/1/682910.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[From the Editor-in-Chief]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/cover_647_060316080735.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[From the Editor-in-Chief]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/cover_647_060316080735.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>1</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[from-the-editor-in-chief-aroon-purie-akhilesh-yadav-up-assembly-election]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[From the Editor-in-Chief]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[Akhilesh Yadav,UP assembly election,Aroon Purie ]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>