<story>
<id>683294</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>yes</story_issue>
<select_magazine>1557</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date>June 13, 2016</issue_date><bylines>
<byline>1095</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464868186</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464867488</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1465368399</modifieddate>
<createdby>727</createdby>
<modifiedby>707</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city/>
</cities>
<categories><category>937685</category><category>937780</category></categories><ordering>683294</ordering><primarycategory>937780</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/sb-cover-story_647_060616120502.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt><![CDATA[Ute Weimer (left) and Bala TV of Lovetreats. Photo: Nilotpal Baruah]]></extra_large_alt>
<extra_large_title><![CDATA[Ute Weimer (left) and Bala TV of Lovetreats. Photo: Nilotpal Baruah]]></extra_large_title>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/sb-cover-story_305_060616120502.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt><![CDATA[Ute Weimer (left) and Bala TV of Lovetreats. Photo: Nilotpal Baruah]]></large_alt>
<large_title><![CDATA[Ute Weimer (left) and Bala TV of Lovetreats. Photo: Nilotpal Baruah]]></large_title>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/sb-cover-story_300x350_060616120502.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt><![CDATA[Ute Weimer (left) and Bala TV of Lovetreats. Photo: Nilotpal Baruah]]></mediumimage_alt>
<mediumimage_title><![CDATA[Ute Weimer (left) and Bala TV of Lovetreats. Photo: Nilotpal Baruah]]></mediumimage_title>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/sb-cover-story_180_060616120502.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt><![CDATA[Ute Weimer (left) and Bala TV of Lovetreats. Photo: Nilotpal Baruah]]></smallimage_alt>
<smallimage_title><![CDATA[Ute Weimer (left) and Bala TV of Lovetreats. Photo: Nilotpal Baruah]]></smallimage_title>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/sb-cover-story_88_060616120502.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt><![CDATA[Ute Weimer (left) and Bala TV of Lovetreats. Photo: Nilotpal Baruah]]></extra_small_alt>
<extra_small_title><![CDATA[Ute Weimer (left) and Bala TV of Lovetreats. Photo: Nilotpal Baruah]]></extra_small_title>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption><![CDATA[Ute Weimer (left) and Bala TV of Lovetreats. Photo: Nilotpal Baruah]]></kicker_image_caption>
<mosimage>
<image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/sb-cover-story-1_060316125312.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[Laxminarayan Srinivasaiah (left) and Anil Nadig of Jivabhumi. Photo: Sandesh Ravikumar]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/sb-cover-story-2_060316125312.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[Shobha Nair, Pradeep Nair (middle) and Denzil D'Souza of Ubyld. Photo: Nilotpal Baruah]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/sb-cover-story-3_060316125312.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[(Left to Right) Karan Gupta, Himesh Joshi, Arjit Gupta and Rohit Ramasubramaniam. Photo: Sandesh Ravikumar]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/sb-cover-story-4_060316125312.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[Sowmya Parthasarathy (left) and Diksha Jain. Photo: Nilotpal Baruah]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/sb-cover-story-5_060316125312.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[Ute Weimer (left) and Bala TV of Lovetreats. Photo: Nilotpal Baruah]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/sb-cover-story-6_060316125312.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[Aditya (left) and Abhijeet Rao of Nuts Over Salad. Photo: Nilotpal Baruah]]></caption></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[Bangalore's e-commerce startups are offering DIY furniture, sex toys, second-hand goods and more.<br /><br />]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p><b>THE FARMER CONNECT<br />Jivabhumi</b><br />Imagine a day when you get all your food supplies delivered to your doorstep from a farmer near you. And you actually know his name, the region and the method he uses to cultivate the rice you eat. {mosimage}</p><p>To make this dream a reality is the purpose behind Jivabhumi, a social-impact driven e-commerce startup in the city. In its early stages currently, Jivabhumi deals in dry groceries, oils and spices and has a large network of 1,200 farmers. Set up only six months back by IT professionals Anil Nadig, 39 and Laxminarayan Srinivasaiah, 40, Jivabhumi currently finds it suppliers in small farmers with land holding of less than five acres and farmer's collectives. All of them use either natural or organic farming methods and quality control is according to the standards set by Participatory Guarantee System of India (PGS).</p><p>Jivabhumi follows a fortnightly cycle where produce is procured from the farmer based on orders and then shipped. "In the future, we are looking to introduce fresh produce and a subscription model to ensure a farmer working with us receives an assured monthly income," says Nadig. Website jivabhumi.com</p><p><b>DIY FURNITURE<br />Ubyld</b><br />Pradeep Nair, 40, Denzil D'Souza, 36 and Shobha Nair, 36, were Do-It-Yourself (DIY) urban gardeners who were on a quest for planters, when this business idea struck them. Ubyld, their year-old e-commerce start-up delivers affordable, upcycled wooden furniture that can be put together using a comprehensive instruction manual and tools provided in a kit that accompanies the furniture. {mosimage}</p><p>D' Souza and Shobha take care of furniture design while Pradeep handles the front-end of the business. They have an experience centre in Thanisandra where they invite those looking for custom furniture for homes and offices to assemble them. From as few as 12 furniture items on their website when they first began, Ubyld now has a 100. "We want people to know that upcycled wood can be used to make great furniture too. Why cut trees then?" says Pradeep adding that the pine wood used in their furniture comes from Sweden as packaging material for heavy machinery. </p><p>"It is kiln-dried, heat treated, chemical-free and has already been transported in water. In countries like the USA, people use it to build houses, it is only here that we don't value upcycled wood as much," he adds. Recently, Ubyld has also started a new section called Vbyld for those who want upcycled furniture without going through the hassle of assembling it on their own. This service is currently available only in Bangalore. Future plans include furniture packages for homes that include over 50 pieces of furniture and curios. "Basically, you can furnish an entire home in under 3 lakh," says Pradeep. They also plan to make the Vbyld range available in other cities. Website ubyld.com</p><p><b>SECOND-HAND GUARANTEE<br />Zefog</b><br />This is the typical Bangalore startup story of four IITians coming together to solve a problem through an e-commerce venture. What sets them apart however, is their product. Zefo, less than a year old, brings you the experience of shopping second-hand furniture and appliances online, but minimises the risks you would face while doing so directly. {mosimage}</p><p>"So far, there have been only pure discovery platforms like OLX and Quikr that do not solve the problem of trust deficit. In a low-trust country like India, we want to be the trust platform where we deal directly with customers," says Rohit Ramasubramaniam, 26, who previously worked with Helion Ventures. Zefo, a user-friendly web platform lists second-hand furniture and appliances with markers of their true condition, does light refurbishment and even disinfects items before delivery. So now, a second-hand piece of furniture is delivered in record time, installed and can even be returned.</p><p>"Customer experience is very critical for us. We do stringent quality control, photograph the items on our own and provide specific dimensions, so you get exactly what is listed online", explains Ramasubramaniam. From their launch in August last year and five orders a day, Zefo is now doing over 70 deliveries every day. A Delhi launch is on the cards and the start-up with over 40 employees has already raised a round of seed funding. Website gozefo.com</p><p><b>KEEP IT FRESH<br />Foodtribe</b><br />Diksha Jain, 31 and Sowmya Parthasarathy, 31, first met in college and discovered that they had many things in common, including households that believed in cooking every meal with freshly ground spices. {mosimage}</p><p>"There was no concept of packaged food, in fact we wouldn't even use the kneaded dough for the next meal," explains Jain. Their love for all things fresh resulted in Foodtribe, a single-destination e-commerce platform for chemicalfree food. The focus is on providing chemical-free ingredients that would help one create a meal from scratch. Overwhelmed by the response and logistical challenges that came with the model, Foodtribe is currently working on its new model. </p><p>It is now planning to launch a supply of homemade masalas and handmade soaps in the next quarter. "Some of these will be made using recipes handed down through generations," explains Jain. "We want to cater to people who want to eat fresh food and don't always have the time to head to the flour mill to have their flour and spices ground," she adds. The shift towards non-perishable food is mainly due to the lack of economical logistics partners, they say. Websitefacebook.com/FoodTribe/</p><p><b>HOT PORTAL<br />Lovetreats</b><br />A happy coincidence brought together a German and an Indian to start Bangalore's hottest new online pleasure shop. Bala TV, 34, and Ute Weimer, 25, met at a party when he was working with a video games company and she was in the country working with Fairtrade India. {mosimage}</p><p>Bala TV had visited adult toy shops in Amsterdam on his various tours and hoped to start something like that in India. Incidentally, Weimer too had a similar dream. They got talking, became friends and Lovetreats was born in October 2015. "The idea was to create a space that felt safe and non-judgemental. In a country where sex education is low, even something as basic as buying condoms can be a chore. I knew I wouldn't start this alone and was looking for a woman co-founder. </p><p>Then Ute came along," says Bala TV. The website features a host of sleek sex toys, bath and body products, massage candles and more. Rising from a 150 product inventory to a whopping 1000, the core of the venture remains to stay sex-positive and at the same time be women friendly. Websitelovetreats.in</p><p><b>GREEN MEALS<br />Nuts Over Salads</b><br />What happens when a chef and gym owner get together for a friendly chat? They talk about healthy food options in the city and find that there is no service that provides Bangaloreans with a nutritious, post-gym meal option. For the past 10 months, chef Aditya Rao, 32, has been preparing healthy salads and delivering them across the city through his e-commerce venture, Nuts Over Salads.{mosimage}</p><p>"There was no business plan; we started out with a home-kitchen. For the first three months, I was doing most of the deliveries myself," he says. Aditya, who studied hospitality and worked with city-based restaurants, has now partnered with his brother, Abhijeet Rao, 27, who gave up professional scuba diving in the Andamans to handle the front end of Nuts Over Salads. Besides delivering a salad meal to health-conscious Bangaloreans, the outfit also provides subscription models and has paired up with Fresh Pressery to add cold-pressed juices to the meals. "We were the first in the country to start the subscription models that vary from weeks to months," says Aditya. </p><p>From a modest entry, Nuts Over Salads is now a fullfledged business venture delivering as many as 400 salads a day around town. The next step, they say, is a chain of takeaway retail outlets with the first one opening in a month's time on the centrally located Residency Road. "Currently, we only deliver lunch and hence want our customers to have the option of picking up snacks and dinner. We are also coming up with several product additions like our own cold-pressed juices, nutrition bars, marinades and dressings. We want to create a one-stop-shop for healthy food options," he explains. Websitenutoversalads.com</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[Bangalore's e-commerce startups are offering DIY furniture, sex toys, second-hand goods and more.<br /><br />]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>356057</tag>
<tag>262037</tag>
<tag>621985</tag>
<tag>734601</tag>
<tag>832546</tag>
<tag>916800</tag>
<tag>993498</tag>
<tag>1062429</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[From sex toys to DIY furniture: These 6 Bangalore startups are offering it all]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[From sex toys to DIY furniture: These 6 Bangalore startups are offering it all]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[From sex toys to DIY furniture: These 6 Bangalore startups are offering it all]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>3</like>
<dislike>3</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/just-a-click-away-sex-toys-foodtribe-lovetreats-nuts-over-salads-zefog-ubyld-jivabhumi/1/683294.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[From sex toys to DIY furniture: These 6 Bangalore startups are offering it all]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/sb-cover-story_647_060616120502.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[From sex toys to DIY furniture: These 6 Bangalore startups are offering it all]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/sb-cover-story_647_060616120502.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>1</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[just-a-click-away-sex-toys-foodtribe-lovetreats-nuts-over-salads-zefog-ubyld-jivabhumi]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[From sex toys to DIY furniture: These 6 Bangalore startups are offering it all]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[Just a click away, Sex toys, Foodtribe, Lovetreats, Nuts over salads, Zefog, Ubyld, Jivabhumi]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>