<story>
<id>683433</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>yes</story_issue>
<select_magazine>1557</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date>June 13, 2016</issue_date><bylines>
<byline>273</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464932317</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464932147</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1464938950</modifieddate>
<createdby>837</createdby>
<modifiedby>727</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city/>
</cities>
<categories><category>937683</category></categories><ordering>683433</ordering><primarycategory>937683</primarycategory><extralargeimage/>
<extra_large_alt/>
<extra_large_title/>
<largeimage/>
<large_alt/>
<large_title/>
<mediumimage/>
<mediumimage_alt/>
<mediumimage_title/>
<smallimage/>
<smallimage_alt/>
<smallimage_title/>
<extrasmallimage/>
<extra_small_alt/>
<extra_small_title/>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption/>
<mosimage>
<image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/anuradha_060316110855.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[Chess champion, writer and online sensation, Anuradha Beniwal. Photo: Antonio Stacy]]></caption></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[Writer and online sensation Anuradha Beniwal, wants to break free from expectations.<br /><br />]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>People are leaving, slowly. The place will soon be deserted. The glare of the afternoon sun outside, hinting at summer madness is peeping in through the huge glasses of the cafe. </p><p>The ravishing Anuradha Beliwal, sitting in a short yellow dress says,"order a large latte before I collapse. So many people asking me so many questions. As if I am one of those Ms Know-It-Alls that you see on news channels. So tired I am." She calls out to the waiter in her Haryanvi accent. He is amused. Beliwal, 29, is a woman who is very clear about certain things in life. </p><p>She likes her coffee very hot. She will not give an opinion about things she has no clue of, but will speak at a high pitch at The Rumor Mill, a popular cafe in Chandigarh. She will not say a word on feminism and most importantly--"I must not be bombarded with boring journalist-type questions. You can ask my age and the usual stuff quickly. We will then talk about our lives, you can also share your darkest desires if you want." She would like to have a long conversation, talk about her travels, about what moves her and what does not. {mosimage}</p><p>About what makes her what she is. "Another important thing, you must not print most of the stuff we talk about. That should be interesting, no?" She is a national chess champion, she's travelled Europe solo, her Hindi travelogue Azaadi Mera Brandhas just been published by Rajkamal Prakashan. She's almost a celebrity. Her video during the Jat agitation in Haryana went viral. </p><p>Hers was the only sane voice around. "Believe me, it came straight from the heart. My old mother was stuck for hours in her own neighborhood while young men destroyed public property, felled trees and created mayhem. The video was just a reaction. People thought it was a well-conceived shoot. Truth is, I was so angry that I just aimed the camera at myself and pressed the record button," she says. </p><p>The author, who is from a small village in Rohtak, says people took offence that she spoke so harshly during the agitation. "Of course, sometimes one tends to forget that we are such an oversensitive people who just can't digest criticism from one of our own. The hate mails were neverending. No one understands that I howl sometimes after reading long nasty mails and just want to be hugged tight," she whispers. </p><p>Now that she is a known face, Beniwal complains that everybody asks her too many questions. "Some are inquisitive if I'll be joining politics. Arre, even I have not thought about that. Give me a break man." Beniwal asserts that she is no social analyst. "Journalists keep asking me complicated questions on national politics. Of course, I know that most of the times they are just showing off their knowledge." Beniwal, an English honours graduate from Miranda House, Delhi University chose to write in Hindi, insisting that she wanted her cousins to take a peep into her life and discover the world through her eyes. </p><p>"I am very close to them. I shifted to London three years back, but we are always in touch through WhatsApp. See, I have prevailed upon them to use smartphones living in a small nondescript village in Rohtak. Now that's an achievement I can boast of." Talking about how the book was conceived, Beniwal says that she didn't quite know what to do with all the documentation of the solo travels that she undertook across ten countries in Europe in the summer of 2015. </p><p>"I was writing a blog and contributing to several travel websites. But this was just too big. Only a book could do justice. By the way, do read it, it has some interesting anecdotes, like how two local men hosted me in Switzerland. And also how I got fired from an eight pound an hour waitress' job in London because I drank a gin and tonic during working hours. What a cruel world we live in." </p><p>How can any conversation with Beniwal can be complete without her controversial piece in Daily O on not wearing a bra in London? "I was in my class in London and by the time I finished it, thousands were following me on Twitter. While many loved what I wrote, others thought that I was the most 'shameless' thing on two legs. </p><p>Ask any woman--doesn't she take off the darn thing as soon as she is home? So what if I went out without wearing one and felt happy that I wasn't ogled at or harassed. Well, some admiring glances though." </p><p>She is almost through with her coffee. A brief pause later, she whispers, "You want to know what annoys me the most? Being overanalysed by armchair intellectuals. What is the big deal if I do not apply sindoor that shouts my marital status? Why does the world have to know that if I am a virgin or taken? And yeah, do see how I am trolled after I say that when I started travelling I was a complete vegetarian but by the end of the trip I had tried beef cooked in different ways," she says.</p><p>All set to write her second book which will chronicle her travels in the Scandinavian countries, Beniwal does not want to talk about books anymore. "Look outside. There is a world out there."</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[Writer and online sensation Anuradha Beniwal, wants to break free from expectations.<br /><br />]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>227037</tag>
<tag>494237</tag>
<tag>263549</tag>
<tag>734610</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Leave me alone]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Writer and online sensation Anuradha Beniwal, wants to break free from expectations.]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[Leave me alone]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Writer and online sensation Anuradha Beniwal, wants to break free from expectations.]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>0</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/writer-and-online-sensation-anuradha-beniwal-bwriter-and-online-sensation-anuradha-beniwal/1/683433.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>0</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>0</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position/>
<audio_url/>
<animated_image_position/>
<animated_image/>
<map_embed_code_position/>
<map_embed_code/>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position/>
<social_embed_code/>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Leave me alone]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage/>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Leave me alone]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage/>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>1</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[writer-and-online-sensation-anuradha-beniwal-bwriter-and-online-sensation-anuradha-beniwal]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Leave me alone]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[Writer,Anuradha Beniwal,Life,Break free]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>