<story>
<id>683444</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>yes</story_issue>
<select_magazine>1557</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date>June 13, 2016</issue_date><bylines>
<byline>660</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464934230</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464933926</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1464939784</modifieddate>
<createdby>837</createdby>
<modifiedby>727</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city/>
</cities>
<categories><category>937683</category></categories><ordering>683444</ordering><primarycategory>937683</primarycategory><extralargeimage/>
<extra_large_alt/>
<extra_large_title/>
<largeimage/>
<large_alt/>
<large_title/>
<mediumimage/>
<mediumimage_alt/>
<mediumimage_title/>
<smallimage/>
<smallimage_alt/>
<smallimage_title/>
<extrasmallimage/>
<extra_small_alt/>
<extra_small_title/>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption/>
<mosimage>
<image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/savita-bhatti_060316011232.jpg]]></image><caption/></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[For the gross injustice caused to the victims of 1984 riots, the Indian politician can only redeem himself with an apology first. <br /><br />]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>Justin Trudeau does everything with aplomb. From carrying his dashing looks with ease, to explaining the core principles of quantum computing with an air of understated intelligence, to greeting a plane filled with Syrian refugees with compassion, to showing off his effortless yoga skills, the man is gunning for perfection. I'm sure he has his share of detractors, but the Canadian Prime Minister stole our hearts when he formally apologised in the House of Commons for the Komagata Maru incident in 1914, in which hundreds of Sikh, Muslim and Hindu passengers on board the Komagatu Maru ship, were denied entry to Canada and forced to return to an uncertain and ultimately violent fate in India. {mosimage}</p><p>"I have to be honest," says Sukhi Ghuman, a descendant of one of the passengers on the ship,"I was holding back tears during the apology, just being there present inside the House of Commons where I got to see Trudeau giving the apology first-hand. It was truly amazing." By Indian political standards, Mr Trudeau, you are falling in a big trap. Promising to apologise for the Komagatu episode was one of your electoral promises, but to actually remember your poll promise and act on it, shows political naivety. </p><p>I'm sure you can learn a lesson or two on feigned amnesia from your thick skinned counterparts in India. They are yet to say a simple sorry for one of India's biggest moment of shame post Independence-the 1984 riots in Delhi after the assassination of then Indian Prime Minister, Mrs Indira Gandhi. I don't need to report the horrifying statistics of the 1984 massacre and the stony wall of injustice meted out to the victims. </p><p>Blood of thousands of innocents lost out to the powerful and mighty because it belonged to ordinary men. Ironically, the Delhi Police closed the case due to lack of evidence. Yes, we all know the botched up details of the story. Leave aside compensation or bringing the culprits to book, can any political party just go to a riot victim, hold his hand and say, "We are sorry. We are sorry that your enemy was not someone across the border but your own brother. We apologise for what happened and we assure you that this won't ever be repeated". Too simplistic a solution some may say, but I would say even the smallest of step is better than having your feet stuck in cemented soil.</p><p>Can we expect this magnanimity from our so called 'leaders'? Harsimrat Kaur Badal, MP from Bathinda, who has steadfastly raised this issue in Parliament says that in the context of the apology of the Canadian PM, our PM could apologise as well, but let the Congress take the lead first. I guess our leaders are so well bred in the Lucknowi tradition of saying pehle aap, pehle aapthat Congress waits for BJP, the BJP exhorts the Congress and AAP butts in like a naughty child. Saying sorry is a voluntary act of quashing your ego. </p><p>It's an act where you put somebody else's pain, and suffering before your own. By saying sorry one embraces compassion and humility. Why cannot our leaders cast aside party differences and admit a wrong? Why can't our leaders ever show us their hearts, torn with misgivings and doubts? Is being insensitive, uncaring and unfeeling the new synonyms for the Indian politician? </p><p>So when the rulers reign over chaos and break rules, can you expect the population to be humane? The rich and powerful flout norms, kill innocents sleeping on roads, befool the banks and exchequer, and churn out tales of intrigue by killing their own kin. And no where do we see remorse or shame of making a mistake. Let's just not keep "being human" on the T-shirts only. Let's do it in life as well. While the adamant politician doesn't say a sorry, others don't get too lucky. Like this boy-- Boy: Daddy I want to get married Dad: First say sorry.. Boy: For what? Dad: Say sorry.. Boy: But for what, what did I do? Dad: You first say sorry ... Boy: But what's my fault? Dad: You first say sorry ... Boy: BUT WHY??? Dad: You first say sorry ... Boy: Please, atleast tell me a reason??? Dad: You first say sorry ... Boy: Ok, I am sorry Dad: Now you are ready, your training is complete. When you learn to say sorry without any reason, you can marry.</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[For the gross injustice caused to the victims of 1984 riots, the Indian politician can only redeem himself with an apology first. <br /><br />]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>356096</tag>
<tag>323739</tag>
<tag>228139</tag>
<tag>227260</tag>
<tag>243269</tag>
<tag>352713</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Is it too late to say sorry?]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[For the gross injustice caused to the victims of 1984 riots, the Indian politician can only redeem himself with an apology first. ]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[Is it too late to say sorry?]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[For the gross injustice caused to the victims of 1984 riots, the Indian politician can only redeem himself with an apology first. ]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>0</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/victims-of-1984-riots-indian-politician-can-only-redeem-himself-with-an-apology-first/1/683444.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>0</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>0</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position/>
<audio_url/>
<animated_image_position/>
<animated_image/>
<map_embed_code_position/>
<map_embed_code/>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position/>
<social_embed_code/>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Is it too late to say sorry?]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage/>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Is it too late to say sorry?]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage/>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>1</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[victims-of-1984-riots-indian-politician-can-only-redeem-himself-with-an-apology-first]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Is it too late to say sorry?]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[Injustice,victims,1984 riots,Canada,Justin trudeau,Komagata Maru,Sorry,Apologize]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>