<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Articles>
 
 
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>Business</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline>By Mail Today Bureau  in Mumbai</Byline>
    <Headline> General  Atlantic  to acquire  21.61% stake  in IIFL Wealth</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt; GLOBAL private equity firm General Atlantic Singapore Fund Pte Limited will acquire 21.61- per cent stake in IIFL Wealth Management Limited, a subsidiary of IIFL Holdings Limited, for an estimated ` 1,122 crore.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; IIFL Holdings said on Saturday that General Atlantic will make a strategic investment to become a minority shareholder in IIFL Wealth Management.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The IIFL Board has approved the proposed issue and allotment of 17 lakh equity shares of its wealth management arm at a price of ` 586.70 each for total consideration of ` 100 crore to General Atlantic, the company informed the Bombay Stock Exchange ( BSE).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Additionally, IIFL Holdings would allot 1.36 crore warrants of IIFL Wealth for an estimated ` 863 crore to the international private equity firm. On full conversion of warrants ( which may take up to 18 months), the proposed transaction will result in aggregate investment by General Atlantic of up to ` 963 crore into IIFL Wealth Management.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Besides, General Atlantic will acquire 27.15 lakh shares worth ` 159.34 crore from employees of IIFL Wealth Management.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The company said that the transactions would result in total investment of ` 1,122.34 crore from General Atlantic leading to an equity ownership by GA of up to 21.61 per cent in IIFLW on a fully diluted basis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; As on September 30, IIFL Holdings owned 76.79 per cent of the total outstanding shares of IIFL. Upon consummation of the transaction, the company will own 53.86 per cent of IIFLW on a fully diluted basis that is assuming full conversion of warrants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; IIFL Holdings founder and chairman Nirmal Jain said, “ General Atlantic is well- aligned with our mission and will help to take IIFL Wealth to the next level through expanded products and services.” Transaction worth an estimated ` 1,122 crore&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
 
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>Business</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline>By Mail Today Bureau in New Delhi T</Byline>
    <Headline> Modi tells Mann Ki  Baat on paper gold</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt;Gold- related schemes,  pakistan including Gold  Monetisation, to be  launched on the eve  of Diwali, says PM &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt; T HE new gold monetisation scheme, aimed at attracting gold owned by households to the banking system, would be introduced during Diwali, ahead of Dhanteras, next month , Prime Minister Narendra Modi announced on Sunday. Besides the gold monetisation scheme, the government will also launch ‘ sovereign gold bonds’ and gold coins with Ashok Chakra, he said in his&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; I don’t think anybody can reduce the love of people for gold. But to keep gold in the form of dead money does not augur well in this age.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Gold can become strength, an economic strength. Gold can become the country’s economic property and every Indian should contribute to this ‘ — NARENDRA MODI, PRIME MINISTER ‘ monthly radio programme Mann Ki Baat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The gold monetisation scheme will allow people to put gold into banks in return for interest payment and aims to mobilise thousands of tonnes of the precious metal lying idle with households.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The PM said that in accordance with the traditional practice, people keep gold in lockers for which they have to pay to banks. “ Now, keep gold in the bank and the bank will pay you in the form of interest. This would transfer gold from dead money to live power,” he explained. “ Please, don’t let your gold be dead money. Gold is very important for the country and can become an economic strength for us and every Indian should contribute to this.” The country consumes nearly 1,000 tonnes of gold every year most of which is imported, and the yellow metal accounts for the second- largest expense on the import bill next only to oil.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The move will also help to cut expensive imports.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The PM said that he is happy to announce that as per the promise made in the Budget, the government is going to launch some important schemes during Diwali, prior to Dhanteras, when gold is purchased. Diwali is on November 11.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; On the sovereign gold bond scheme, to be launched in the coming weeks, Modi said that people will not get any gold bar but a piece of paper which will have the same value as that of gold. “ When you return that piece of paper, you will get money as per the value of gold at that time.” Explaining its benefits, Modi said because of this, one would not need to buy gold and worry about where to keep it. It will be a matter of just a piece of paper which nobody will come to steal, he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ I am also happy to announce that we will be bringing out gold coins with Ashok Chakra. It has been 70 years since Independence, but till now we are using foreign gold coins or gold bullion bars, which are also used by foreigners. Why can’t we have swadeshi- mark coin? This is why in the coming weeks, before Dhanteras, these will be available,” Modi said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The government will start with gold coins of 5 gm and 10 gm with Ashok Chakra. Along with this, 20 gm cold coin will also be available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ I am confident that these new schemes will give new direction to the economic development of the country. I want your cooperation in this,” Modi added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The government is launching these schemes with a view to mobilise a part of 20,000 tonnes of idle gold lying with households and temples.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Security Printing and Minting Corporation of India Limited will minting these coins. 20,000 coins of 5 gm and 30,000 coins of 10 gm would be made available, sources said. They added that these coins would be cheaper than market rate and will be distributed through branches of banks and post offices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The government will also launch sovereign gold bonds and gold coins with Ashok Chakra, Modi says in his radio programme Mann Ki Baat&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
 
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>Business</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline>By Teena Jain Kaushal  in New Delhi</Byline>
    <Headline> Right time to move  your home loan?</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt;If you are thinking of transferring  your home loan to reduce  interest rates, do check all the  facts before going ahead&lt;/p&gt;   &lt;p&gt; PROCESS OF LOAN TRANSFER Close the deal with the existing bank One needs to submit a letter to the existing lender requesting a loan transfer Based on your request, the bank will give a consent letter/ NOC and a statement mentioning the outstanding amount Provide the NOC to the new lender, who then sanctions your loan amount to the old lender for an account closure Once the transaction is over, your property documents will be handed over to the new lender The leftover post- dated cheques/ ECS are cancelled COST INVOLVED Pre- payment penalty: There is no pre- payment penalty on floating rate home loans. If you have a fixed rate loan, check&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; out with the bank on the penalty amount Processing fee: The new bank will charge you processing fees on transfer of a loan. But you can negotiate with the bank Stamp duty: Banks need to pay stamp duty to the government on the title deed submitted with the bank. The cost is recovered from you Legal charges: Banks hire lawyers to validate legal status of the property COST BENEFIT Assuming a person has taken a ` 30 lakh loan for 10 years at 10.5 per cent interest rate, the interest outgo is around ` 18.5 lakh In case, the interest rate is 9.5 per cent, the total interest outgo is around ` 16.5 lakh. This works out to an annual saving of around ` 20,000 Include other charges such as processing fees and stamp fees while working out the total cost THINGS TO WATCH OUT FOR It is always better to switch the loan early on during the tenure to save on interest cost There are no benefits of switching the loan when less than five years of repayment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; is left Check for foreclosure charges, which is the charge levied by banks for early closure of loan and processing fees charged by the bank where loan is being transferred.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; One should keep in mind that the teaser rate rises after a stipulated time frame Do not go for loan transfer just because teaser loan schemes offer low rates One should get a statement from current lender stating that property documents will be dispatched within a certain time frame to avoid hassles in future A loan transfer will not be possible if there is an irregular repayment with the current lender The processing fee to the new lender can also be negotiated and waived Processing fee to new lender can be waived heavily’ in India&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
 
 
 
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline>By Astha Saxena in New Delhi</Byline>
    <Headline> Weather  change  brings swine  f lu &amp; viral  fever to city</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt;Winter knocks with swine f lu and viral scare&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;EVEN as cases of dengue and malaria have shown a downward trend in the Capital, Delhiites continue to be under risk of viral fever and asthmatic attacks. Doctors have cautioned that the situation may aggravate with the spread of swine flu and due to the onset of winters. In the last few days, there has been a rise in the number of patients complaining of fever, bodyache, cold, cough and breathlessness. “Viral fever usually subsides on the third day but this time we are witnessing patients with consistent fever for five consecutive days. Variations in day and night temperatures confuse our body and increase the physiological stress. The body is unable to regulate fluid intake resulting in dehydration, muscle cramps and fatigue,” Dr Navneet Kaur, Internal Medicine, Apollo Spectra Hospitals told MAIL TODAY. Carrying an inhaler is becoming a must for those prone to asthma. During winters, joint pains are common, especially among the elderly, but the orthopaedics in the city suggest everyone to take extra care of joints in the season as it promises not only to aggravate joint pain, but also trigger other chronic cases like gout and arthritis. “This is the time of the year when cases of viral fever goes up. People with a history of asthma or breathlessness should carry an inhaler and always cover their face while travelling,” Dr SP Byotra, senior consultant, department of Internal medicine, Sir Ganga Ram hospital told MAILTODAY. The maximum temperature recorded on Sunday was 32 degrees Celsius while the minimum temperature stood at 20 degrees Celsius. If experts are to be believed then the cases are going to rise in the coming days. “The cases will go up in the coming days. With the onset of winters, more and more people will complain of viral fever. The earliest recognizable symptoms of a viral infection are often fatigue and body ache. This may be followed by fever. Headache is also a common symptom of viral infection. Vomiting and diarrhoea may be present in some cases,” Dr Pranjit Bhowmik, HOD, Internal Medicine, Asian Institute of Medical Science told MAIL TODAY. According to the doctors, one should go for flu vaccination to avoid falling ill. “Those having a history of diabetes, asthma, heart and kidney problem should immediately take the flu vaccination. Even children below the age of five years and people above the age of 65 years should go for the vaccination,” Dr Sushila Kataria, associate director, department of Internal medicine, Medanta said. Experts also recommended that people should keep themselves well hydrated during this period. Water increases the amount of oxygen that the blood is able to carry to all the cells in the body. As a result, all parts of the body functions better, including those that are essential for a strong immune response that helps in repelling viruses&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;This is the time of the year when cases of viral fever goes up.People with a history of asthma or breathlessness should carry an inhaler and always cover their face while travelling. —Dr SP Byotra, Sir Ganga Ram Hospital&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline />
    <Headline> ‘ ‘  ‘ Sorry, we gave  rise to the ISIS’</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt;Ex- PM admits  rise of jihadi  group was due  to the Iraq war&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt; TONY Blair has finally said sorry for the Iraq War — and admitted he could be partly to blame for the rise of ISIS. The extraordinary confession by the former British prime minister comes after 12 years in which he refused to apologise for the conflict. Blair makes his dramatic ‘ mea culpa’ during a TV interview about the ‘ hell’ caused by his and George Bush’s decision to oust Saddam Hussein.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In the exchange, Blair repeatedly says sorry for his conduct and even refers to claims that the invasion was a war ‘ crime’ – while denying he committed one.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Blair is asked bluntly in the CNN interview, to be broadcast on Sunday: “ Was the Iraq War a mistake?” He replies: “ I apologise for the fact that the intelligence we received was wrong. I also apologise for some of the mistakes in planning and certainly, our mistake in our understanding of what would happen once you removed the regime.” Principle cause Challenged that the Iraq War was ‘ the principle cause’ of the rise of Islamic State, he said: “ I think there are elements of truth in that. Of course you can’t say those of us who removed Saddam in 2003 bear no responsibility for the situation in 2015.” In the ‘ trial by TV’, respected US political broadcaster Fareed Zakaria accuses him of being President Bush’s ‘ poodle’ over the conflict. Blair’s confession comes a week after The Mail on Sunday published a bombshell White House memo revealing for the first time how Blair and Bush agreed a ‘ deal in blood’ a year before the invasion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; A 2002 briefing note from US Secretary of State Colin Powell to the President showed Blair had secretly pledged to back the conflict — while telling MPs and British voters that he was seeking a diplomatic solution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In his CNN interview, Blair candidly asks for forgiveness for his blunder in not realising ‘ what would happen once you removed the regime’. The admission makes a mockery of the statement in the Powell memo that Blair would ‘ demonstrate ( to Bush) that we have thought through ‘ the day after’ – a reference to the consequences of invasion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; However, the bloody chaos in the region continues to this day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; And in a separate development, former Labour Home Secretary David Blunkett has revealed that he challenged Blair before the war about avoiding chaos after Saddam’s downfall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Lord Blunkett says Blair failed to give him such ‘ reassurances’ — and instead placed blind faith in the two main ‘ hawks’ in the US administration, vice- president Dick Cheney and defence secretary Donald Rumsfeld.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Lord Blunkett also vented his fury that Sir John Chilcot, who is leading the long- delayed inquiry into the Iraq War, had failed to ask him to give evidence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ Given my front- row seat at these events, I am mystified Chilcot has not asked me to provide either oral or written evidence,” Lord Blunkett told The Mail on Sunday. “ I would have thought that over the six years the inquiry has been going on, Sir John would have found the time to ask the then home secretary what he knew,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Blair’s confession about the Iraq War and the rise of ISIS is in stark contrast to his repeated refusal to shoulder the blame for the conflict, or its long term consequences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In 2004, he told MPs: “ I will not apologise for the conflict. I believe it was right.” He stuck to his hard line in 2007, saying: “ I don’t think we should be apologising at all for what we are doing in Iraq.” Remarkably, Blair himself predicted how the apology U- turn he finally made on Sunday would be reported.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In his 2010 memoirs, he explained why he had so far refused to say ‘ yes’ when asked if he was sorry, because he knew it would prompt damaging headlines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; All the key figures, including Blair and other senior Labour politicians, are understood to have been given notice of the broad thrust of Chilcot’s verdict on them, expected to be made public next year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; As a master of public relations and media manipulation, Blair may have calculated that since Chilcot is likely to accuse him of major errors of judgment, it is better for him to volunteer an apology now, rather than be forced to do so if. The former prime minister’s decision to make his apology in the US, as opposed to the UK, is also significant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Daily Mail Blair, in the past, had refused to apologise for the USBritish decision to oust Saddam Hussein from power in Iraq saying the action was necessary rise to the&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline />
    <Headline> ‘ BEYONCE’S A CONTROL FREAK’</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt;FOR 40 years, it has been one of the world’s favourite rock songs — while baffling its millions of fans with its wilfully obscure lyrics. Queen’s Bohemian Rhapsody, released on October 31, 1975, has consistently featured at the top of ‘all-time greatest’ song lists, and sold more than 2.5 million records in the UK alone — twice reaching No1. But Queen’s flamboyant frontman and songwriter Freddie Mercury steadfastly refused to explain his lyrics to the song. His only utterance was that it was ‘about relationships’. His bandmates, too, have remained tight-lipped. But now, on the eve of its 40th anniversary, Mercury’s biographer Lesley-Ann Jones has revealed its hidden message — a confession by Freddie that he was gay. Lyricist Sir Tim Rice knew Freddie well and he agrees with her explanation. “It’s fairly obvious to me this was Freddie’s coming- out song,” said Tim. “I’ve spoken to Roger Taylor (the band’s drummer) about it. There is a very clear message in it. This is Freddie admitting that he is gay. “In the line ‘Mama, I just killed a man’ he’s killed the old Freddie, his former image,” says Tim. “With ‘Put a gun against his head, pulled my trigger, now he’s dead’ he’s dead, the straight person he was originally. He’s destroyed the man he was trying to be, and now this is him, trying to live with the new Freddie.” ‘“I see a little silhouetto of a man” — that’s him, still being haunted by what he’s done, and what he is. Every time I hear the song I think of him trying to shake off one Freddie and embracing another – even all these years. Do I think he managed it? I think he was in the process of managing it rather well.” “Freddie was an exceptional lyricist, and Bohemian Rhapsody is one of the great pieces of music of the 20th Century.’ Lesley-Ann Jones put the theory that Bohemian Rhapsody was a confession about his sexual orientation to Freddie in 1986. The singer laughed, then fell silent, before answering: “Bad timing!” But the writer says her interpretation was confirmed by Freddie’s lover Jim Hutton after Mercury’s death — aged just 45 –from an Aids-related illness in November 1991. She says Hutton told her: “You were right. Freddie was never going to admit it publicly, because he had to carry on the charade about being straight, for his family. But we discussed it many times. It was Freddie’s confessional. It was about how different his life could have been. How much happier he would have felt, had he been able to be himself. The world heard a masterpiece of imagination. It was so intricate, and had so many layers, but its message was simple.” Daily Mail&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline />
    <Headline> ‘ SAINI’S REMOVALWAS OVERDUE’</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt; CONGRESS deputy leader in the Lok Sabha Capt Amarinder Singh on Sunday said that the removal of Sumedh Singh Saini as the Director General of Police was long overdue and he should have been replaced long back.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; He said, while his removal was a welcome step, but people of Punjab will not be satisfied till the guilty in the Bargadi ( Kotkapura) firing incident are not dismissed and charged with murder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Amarinder hoped that the new DGP Suresh Arora, who has a reputation of being an upright officer, comes up to the expectations of people and stops shielding the guilty cops to restore public confidence in police functioning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Meanwhile, Congress said Punjab Chief Minister Parkash Singh Badal and his deputy Sukhbir Singh Badal should resign taking moral responsibility for the failure of police to control the turmoil in the state.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Manjeet Sehgal Amarinder Singh&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline />
    <Headline> 60 shops  gutted in  Mumbai fire</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt; Trump hails OVER 60 shops were gutted in a major fire that broke out in South Mumbai's busy Crawford market due to a short circuit in the wee hours of Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Fire officials said there was no casualty reported in the blaze. “ Our control room received an alert at 5.23 am on Sunday that a massive fire broke out at Crawford market.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Soon 10 fire tenders and eight water tankers were pressed into action,” a fire brigade official told PTI. The fire was brought under control by 8 am.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Preliminary probe suggested it was caused by a short circuit. Over 60 shops, mostly of perfumes and packaging material, were destroyed, he said. Brihanmumbai Municipal Corporation ( BMC) Commissioner Ajoy Mehta and Mumbai Mayor Snehal Ambekar visited the spot and interacted with shop owners whose shops were gutted.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Some of them alleged that the fire department did not take their call seriously. “ Had the fire department taken our call seriously and swung into action immediately, the loss could have been minimized.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Our repeated calls to 101 went unanswered and we had to report this incident to 100 ( police number),” Mahatma Phule Dukandar Sewa Sangh president Ratnakar Karale said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Mayor Ambekar, however, said: “ As per my knowledge, all the machinery with entire force was present here ( in the market) to douse the fire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; But, if there is a need to upgrade the system, I would discuss it with the municipal commissioner.” PTI&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline />
    <Headline> Adele found  new album  song boring,  wasted $ 2mn</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt; SHE has admitted that her latest album — the first for four years — very nearly didn’t happen because her newfound happiness caused her to write ‘ boring’ songs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; But as Adele saw her hotly anticipated new single from the album topping the charts on both sides of the Atlantic, the true cost of her comeback in cash and reputation began to emerge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Music industry sources told The Mail on Sunday that Adele’s inability to write new trademark songs of pain and heartache meant the new album, 25, has cost as much as £ 4 million to make, with at least half of that wasted on material which didn’t make the final cut.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; She has also alienated some of the biggest names in music who collaborated with her only to be left furious when she tossed their work aside.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ The average cost of an album by a star of her stature is around £ 2 million,” one music executive said. “ This new album hasn’t just been blood, sweat and tears. It has been millions of pounds down various drains, deadlines missed and record company executives tearing their hair out wondering if anything was ever going to be finished.” As Adele embarked on a publicity blitz to promote her new song on Friday, she admitted: “ I wrote a lot of songs that didn’t make the album because they simply weren’t good enough. I did pretty much write an album about being a mum, but that’s boring, so I scrapped it. I thought I’d run out of ideas.” Her words have ruffled feathers at the highest echelons of the music industry, with one insider saying: “ The basic problem is that Adele got happy and couldn’t write. Every theme she has had in the past has been a broken relationship and a sad life, and then there she is at 22 with ten Grammys, an Oscar, a Golden Globe, millions of pounds as well as a partner and a baby.” Daily Mail Adele&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline />
    <Headline> All- round show</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt; state leadership of the party for its “ remarkable victory” in the recentlyheld elections for the Ladakh Autonomous Hill Development Council ( LAHDC) of Jammu and Kashmir. “ The credit for party’s victory goes to the leadership of its national president Amit Shah, Prime Minister Narendra Modi besides the hard work put in by party activists and the hectic campaigning undertaken by Deputy Chief Minister Nirmal Singh and his colleague ministers,” BJP state president and party MP from Jammu Jugal Kishore Sharma said. The BJP formed a coalition government with the PDP for the first time in the state after it clinched poll victories in the Jammu region.&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline>By Rakesh Ranjan  in New Delhi</Byline>
    <Headline> Arvind puts  ball in Jung’s  court in the  garbage game</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt; AS THE logjam between the Delhi government and BJP- ruled MCDs over salary dues of sanitation workers continues, Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal has urged Lieutenant Governor Najeeb Jung to recover Rs 1,600 crore from the Delhi Development Authority ( DDA) to end the crisis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Kejriwal has written to Jung asking him to direct the DDA to clear its dues of Rs 1,600 crore to the civic bodies, which are facing a financial crunch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; With this, the AAP government has put the ball in L- G’s court. The Delhi government has already expressed its inability to provide additional funds to the civic bodies. The MCDs, on the other hand, have blamed the AAP government for not giving their shares to the MCDs in a timely manner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Demanding their salary dues, the sanitation workers in Delhi have gone on strike.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Mentioning financial constraints faced by the three municipal corporations of Delhi, Kejriwal said activities of the civic bodies are adversely affected and the issue was also raised in a meeting called by Union Urban Development Minister on October 1.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In a letter to the lieutenant governor, Kejriwal said due to financial crunch the municipal corporations are unable to meet their core functions relating to handling and removal of garbage. “ Often the municipal corporations delay paying monthly salaries to Safai Karmcharis ( sanitation workers) which leads to threats of strikes by them. The Delhi government has made efforts to release the funds and grants under Plan and Non- Plan heads to all the three municipal corporations in time. Underlining property tax as one of the main sources of revenue generation to the MCDs,” the CM said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; It is noteworthy that DDA owes more than Rs 1,600 crore to them in terms of property tax. The due was Rs 765 crore to South Delhi Municipal Corporation, Rs 590 crore to North Delhi Municipal Urges L- G to direct DDA to clear ` 1.6k- cr dues&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; East Delhi Municipal Corporation, Kejriwal said in his letter. Urging the Lt Governor to look into the matter, the CM asked him to give suitable instructions to DDA to clear all outstanding dues to the MCDs at the earliest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Demanding regular payment of salaries, arrears, regularisation of their posts, cashless health card, sanitation workers went on strike from October 23. In June, they had gone on strike demanding timely payment of their salaries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; sanitation workers union decided to call off the strike after an assurance from Delhi government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; However, some other unions decided to continue with the strike. “ We have decided to call off the strike after a meeting with Minister Sandeep Kumar, who assured us that the government will give the remaining portion of grant for this financial year in December. The decision to call off strike was also taken in view of the approaching Diwali festival,” Sanjay Vikas Sanyukt Morcha chief said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Claiming that the Morcha represented 27 unions of MCD sanitation workers, Gehlot said the meeting was held after the striking workers dumped garbage in front of the residence of Delhi Assembly Deputy Speaker Ram Niwas Goyal and burnt the effigy of Kejriwal. A senior government official said the remaining annual grant to MCDs in December although it is payable in March next year.&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline />
    <Headline> Beyonce was fixated on pursuit of fame</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt; SHE is one of the biggest superstars on the planet: a £ 500 million pop powerhouse who is known around the world by just her Christian name, counts Barack and Michelle Obama as friends and was personally chosen by the President to perform at his inauguration.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; At 34, Beyoncé is at the top of her game. Meticulously packaged, groomed and marketed, she slavishly controls her public image — so it was a rare glimpse of the real woman behind the impenetrable mask when last week she snapped ‘ Stop it’ at an assistant fussing in an attempt to stop her falling out of her pink couture outfit at a glittering charity event in New York.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; But for one man, the outburst came as no surprise. Her first love, Lyndall Locke, who dated the singer for a decade from when she was a 12- year- old wannabe until they split when she toured the world with Destiny’s Child, said she had always been fixated on the pursuit of fame — and the ‘ simple girl from Houston’ rapidly became a ‘ control freak’. “ She was focused and knew what she wanted,” he says. “ She’d started singing when she was five and her parents supported her. There was a Beyoncé train on the fast track to fame and you were either on it or off it. Some people fell off the train and others jumped.” In an exclusive interview with The Mail , Lyndall reveals the true scope of the machine that has propelled her to stardom – a campaign orchestrated by her father, Mathew Knowles, who gave up his job and invested his life savings to making her a success, driving them to bankruptcy in the process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Mathew ‘ Big Mac’ Knowles was the mastermind of ‘ Project Beyoncé’, as it was known in the family. “ Let me tell you, there was no messing with Big Mac.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; He gave me the third degree about who I was and what my intentions were,” says Lyndall. “ He gave me the talk about ‘ not messing anything up’.” Lyndall says he understood this to mean not to get Beyoncé pregnant. “ We shared our first kiss at a Brian McKnight concert when Bey was 13. She was a little southern belle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; She was an awesome kisser. We would hang out and do normal boyfriend- girlfriend things, although I was never allowed to stay over.” Daily Mail Reveals singer’s ex- boyfriend Lyndall Locke&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline />
    <Headline> Brace for chaos as  Africa summit starts</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt; GET ready for massive traffic snarls in and around Central and New Delhi areas as the four- day India- Africa Forum Summit starts on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Heavy security arrangements have been put in place apart from traffic restrictions that may led to chaotic traffic in the coming days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; On Sunday evening, traffic restrictions were imposed around the Indira Gandhi Stadium, the venue of the summit, leading to traffic congestion near ITO intersection, Vikas Marg, Delhi Gate, Rajghat and Mathura Road.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; According to the traffic police, there will be multiple VVIP arrangements, which shall affect traffic in and around ITO, Vikas Marg, the Ring Road stretch near Delhi Secretariat, the Mathura Road stretch near Pragati Maidan, India Gate and adjoining areas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Officials said traffic will be mainly affected on October 29, the day when the heads of various states, many of whom will be provided prime minister- level security, meet at the venue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Leaders of 54 African countries and Unions have been invited to the summit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; There will be no traffic restrictions on Lodhi Road, Vikas Marg and major part of the Ring Road that can be used by the general public.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Meanwhile, two helicopters will be deployed round- the- clock for the summit. While one will be dedicated to surveillance, the other will be for handling contingencies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; A separate control room has been set up to monitor the Indira Gandhi Stadium and the VVIP routes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Around 200 CCTV cameras have been installed at the venue and 300 more in central Delhi areas, including ITO, Delhi Secretariat, Raj Ghat and all areas in the vicinity of the stadium,” said TS Luthra, Joint Commissioner of Police ( Security).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Mail Today/ New Delhi Traffic crawls near ITO after restrictions were imposed around IG Stadium due to India- Africa Forum Summit.&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline />
    <Headline> Captain’s warning</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt; SENIOR Congress leader Captain Amarinder Singh has asked Delhi Chief Minister Arvind Kejriwal to spell out Aam Aadmi Party’s agenda for Punjab rather than adding to the already existing “ chaos and anarchy” in the state. “ Please stay away from Punjab as you ( Kejriwal) have nothing to offer except for adding to chaos and anarchy — the two things you are best known for,” Amarinder said after Kejriwal visited the state to boost his party’s prospects. The AAP had eaten into the Congress vote bank in the 2014 parliamentary elections and could do so again in the 2017 Assembly polls.&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline />
    <Headline> CM’s condolence</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt; PUNJAB Chief Minister Parkash Singh Badal expressed grief and sorrow over the demise of veteran Bollywood actor and younger brother of well- known artiste Dharmendra, Ajit Singh Deol who passed away in Mumbai. In a condolence message, the CM said that with the death of Ajit whose son Abhay Deol is also a film star, Punjab has lost a true son of the soil who had made his presence felt in the tinsel world of Hindi as well as Punjabi film industry. He said that Ajit would be ever remembered as a simple- hearted person who played a vital role in promoting Punjab, Punjabi and Punjabiat in every corner of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline />
    <Headline> Drugs don’t give musical high: Keith Richards</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt; notoriously hedonistic standards of rock ‘ n’ roll. But now Keith Richards has made a surprising confession by claiming that taking drugs does not inspire musical creativity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In an interview for BBC Radio 4' s Desert Island Discs, the Rolling Stones guitarist dismissed any link as ‘ a lie’ and declared: “ There is really no correlation between drugs and music and how you perform it.” Richards, 71, who co- wrote some of the band’s biggest hits including ( I Can't Get No) Satisfaction and Jumpin’ Jack Flash, told host Kirsty Young that taking drugs night. “ I have never felt it did anything for my creativity. It kept me up a lot at nights looking for the stuff,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ It was something that I had to stop because I realised there are experiments that go on too long. Some people can handle things and other people can’t. If the drugs become more important than the music then you’ve lost the battle.” His comments comes as a surprise for his fans and critics alike because at the height of the band’s success in the 1970s, ‘ Keef’ was as well known for his drug- fuelled lifestyle as The guitarist had several high- profile brushes with the law, and in 1978 he was handed a suspended jail term in Canada after pleading guilty to possessing heroin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Richards’s former excesses have only added to his appeal in some quarters — Johnny Depp famously based his roguish Jack Sparrow in the Pirates Of The Caribbean films on the star. Richards, who still chain- smokes cigarettes, says becoming a grandfather had encouraged him to stop rebelling and he now regards his old persona as something of a ‘ ball and chain’. Daily Mail&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline />
    <Headline> FACE OF ISIS SUICIDE BOMBING</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt; A BRITISH ISIS fighter has carried out a devastating suicide bomb attack near the jihadi held city of Ramadi in Iraq.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Abu Khalid al- Britani killed at least 50 Iraqi soldiers in a double suicide bomb attack with a Tunisian fighter whilst defending Ramadi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; A photograph was posted online in tribute to the British fighter, who was half Yemeni and half Somali in origin but never lived in Somalia. Another fighter known as Abu Maidah as- Somali, who used to live in London and Sweden, described the dead jihadi as his ‘ best friend’. Abu Maidah revealed that the British suicide bomber was in his 40s and was not fluent in Somali. The two fighters met in a terrorist training camp before Abu Khalid volunteered to fight in Iraq.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Abu Khalid al- Britani is the third Britisher to blow himself up whilst fighting for ISIS. Daily Mail Abu Khalid al- Britani&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline>By Mail Today Bureau in New Delhi</Byline>
    <Headline> Harassed hubbies dial  Delhi women’s helpline</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt; FOR A commission that exclusively caters to women, a sizable number of complaints received are from men.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Most men say their wives and families harass them for money, property or simply divorce. There are cases of sexual harassment too. Some complaints are lodged by men against men. For instance, a complaint where a DU professor is said to be impotent but is marrying a third time and needs to be stopped.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The Delhi Commission for Women Act, 1994, provides for ‘ safeguarding the rights of ( only) women as per the Constitution of India and other laws’. However, in the light of so many men approaching DCW, it has decided to redress their issues as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; DCW Chairperson, Swati Maliwal, told Mail Today, “ Initially, we were surprised that men were walking into our office, in spite of the name itself saying Delhi Commission for Women. Most of the complaints pertain to wives inflicting mental, emotional and even physical torture on their husbands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Most seem genuine so we are not turning them away.” A senior official said the procedure adopted during such cases ranges from counseling the accused wife to lodging an FIR against her. “ If it is a soft case, we either sit the couple down with their respective families and discuss their problem or send them to the Delhi Legal Services Authority ( DLSA) for mediation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; If serious charges are involved, the complaint is referred to the local police station for an FIR,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In many such cases, the aggrieved men are poor and are fighting their wives and the woman’s relatives, who support them. DLSA provides legal help to such men.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; DCW cites the case of 30- yearold Parwinder ( name changed) whose wife declared that she had a lover and wanted to annul the marriage on the wedding night.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; When he informed her brothers, they threatened to kill his family unless he kept the woman. She consumed sleeping pills once and set herself on fire on another occasion after dialing 100 and telling police that she was being burnt for dowry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In another case, 29- year- old Suresh ( name changed) was locked up by his wife in her maternal home and not allowed to go out for work or given food for three days. He was also severely beaten up and barely managed to escape.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Then there are complaints where men have levelled accusations against other men. A DU professor is alleged to be destroying the lives of women by marrying them while being impotent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Most complaints pertain to wives inflicting mental and even physical torture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Majority of them seem genuine, so we are not turning them away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; — SWATI MALIWAL , DCW chairperson&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline />
    <Headline> How Freddie  Mercury  came out of  the closet</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt; FOR 40 years, it has been one of the world’s favourite rock songs — while baffling its millions of fans with its wilfully obscure lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Queen’s Bohemian Rhapsody , released on October 31, 1975, has consistently featured at the top of ‘ all- time greatest’ song lists, and sold more than 2.5 million records in the UK alone — twice reaching No1.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; But Queen’s flamboyant frontman and songwriter Freddie Mercury steadfastly refused to explain his lyrics to the song. His only utterance was that it was ‘ about relationships’. His bandmates, too, have remained tight- lipped.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; But now, on the eve of its 40th anniversary, Mercury’s biographer Lesley- Ann Jones has revealed its hidden message — a confession by Freddie that he was gay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Lyricist Sir Tim Rice knew Freddie well and he agrees with her explanation. “ It’s fairly obvious to me this was Freddie’s coming- out song,” said Tim. “ I’ve spoken to Roger Taylor ( the band’s drummer) about it. There is a very clear message in it. This is Freddie admitting that he is gay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ In the line ‘ Mama, I just killed a man’ he’s killed the old Freddie, his former image,” says Tim.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ With ‘ Put a gun against his head, pulled my trigger, now he’s dead’ he’s dead, the straight person he was originally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; He’s destroyed the man he was trying to be, and now this is him, trying to live with the new Freddie.” ‘“ I see a little silhouetto of a man” — that’s him, still being haunted by what he’s done, and what he is. Every time I hear the song I think of him trying to shake off one Freddie and embracing another – even all these years. Do I think he managed it? I think he was in the process of managing it rather well.” “ Freddie was an exceptional lyricist, and Bohemian Rhapsody is one of the great pieces of music of the 20th Century.’ Lesley- Ann Jones put the theory that Bohemian Rhapsody was a confession about his sexual orientation to Freddie in 1986. The singer laughed, then fell silent, before answering: “ Bad timing!” But the writer says her interpretation was confirmed by Freddie’s lover Jim Hutton after Mercury’s death — aged just 45 – from an Aids- related illness in November 1991.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; She says Hutton told her: “ You were right. Freddie was never going to admit it publicly, because he had to carry on the charade about being straight, for his family. But we discussed it many times. It was Freddie’s confessional. It was about how different his life could have been. How much happier he would have felt, had he been able to be himself. The world heard a masterpiece of imagination.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; It was so intricate, and had so many layers, but its message was simple.” Daily Mail Biographer claims singer penned song to confess his sexuality&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline />
    <Headline> Mahapanchayat wants  bail for Sunped accused</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt; on Sunday organised a mahapanchayat at Sector 10 to express their solidarity with the accused in the Sunped killings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Large number of members of the Rajput community from Faridabad, Gurgaon, Ghaziabad and Delhi assembled in the mahapanchayat and unanimously urged the state to facilitate bail for the accused, who face charges of murder and attempt to murder and make sure no more arrests are made in connection with the case till the CBI completes its inquiry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; A Dalit family had been set ablaze reportedly by upper caste people in Sunped village of Faridabad on October 20. Two children were burnt to death in the incident. The Faridabad police have registered FIRs against 11 upper caste people in connection with the case.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ The case has several loopholes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; We suspect that the accused have been framed under serious charges. We are satisfied with the government’s recommendation for a CBI probe. It is only fair that the accused are granted bail, especially to the 70- year- old accused who has been accused of torching the Dailt family,” president of the Rajkul Sanskritik Manch SR Rawat said. Rawat also headed the mahapanchayat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The community also demanded that the seven accused, who are currently lodged in the Gurgaon jail in Bhondsi, to be brought to the Faridabad jail in Neemka village.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Apart from this, the mahapanchayat demanded compensation of Rs 50 lakh and a government job for the three Rajputs, who died last year in inter- caste clashes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ If the state government does not act on our demands in the next seven days, we will organise a bigger mahapanchayat and take to the streets to ensure justice,” Rawat said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Ajay Kumar/ Gurgaon Two Dalit children were burnt to death allegedly by upper caste people in Sunped village.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Say that they have been framed in the case&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline />
    <Headline> Maliwal  cracks the  whip on  sale of acid</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt; IN VIEW of the recent acid attack on a 55- year- old woman in RK Puram, the Delhi Commission for Women ( DCW) has asked all district magistrates in the city to furnish details of acid sale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In her letter, DCW chairperson Swati Maliwal quoted the Supreme Court order of July 18, 2013, which directed regulation of acid so it could not be used as a weapon of revenge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The court, in its order, had regulated sale of acid, directing sellers to keep a log of sold quantity. They were also directed to sell acid to buyers fulfilling certain conditions like showing identity cards and giving reason for procuring it. “ We are getting information that the Supreme Court order is not being complied with, which, in our view is not just violation of court orders but more importantly, detrimental to the interests of the citizens,” Maliwal said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The information sought by the DCW concerns list of licenced retailers, their addresses and stock of acid stored by them as well as action taken to confiscate acid in the past two years, including date of raids and officers who participated in it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The commission has sought information regarding action taken in case of violation of Supreme Court order, collection of fine from violators and expenditure of the collected amount. The letter, written on October 23 by the chairperson, has directed the district magistrates to furnish all the asked details in next 10 days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The spurt of acid attacks as a form of revenge had prompted the SC to issue an order to regulate its sale.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Mail Today/ New Delhi Asks DMs to furnish details in 10 days&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline />
    <Headline> Moore says Bond can’t be gay or woman</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt; JAMES BOND legend Sir Roger Moore has courted controversy by insisting that 007 could never be portrayed as a gay man — or be played by a woman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Sir Roger, who has previously come under fire for questioning whether the spy could be played by a black actor such as Idris Elba, risks a further backlash over his latest comments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; He said: “ I have heard people talk about how there should be a lady Bond or a gay Bond. But they wouldn’t be Bond for the simple reason that wasn’t what Ian Fleming wrote.” The 88- year- old star said ‘ political correctness’ should not be pandered to, insisting: “ It is not about being homophobic or, for that matter, racist – it is simply about being true to the character.” His views are at odds with those of Daniel Craig, whose 007 movie Spectre opens tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; When asked last week if Bond could be black, a woman or gay, he replied: “ Anything’s possible. You can do anything as long as it’s credible and it works.” And fellow Bond star Pierce Brosnan said, “ Sure, why not?” when asked if the character could be gay, though he doubted producers would allow it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Sir Roger, whose one- man theatre tour continues tomorrow in Liverpool following publication of his book Bond On Bond, said political correctness also meant villains were now always from undefined nations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ There is a danger always of causing offence,” he said. “ I suppose you could just about get away with a villain from Burkina Faso, but that’s about it,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In another blow to Craig, Sir Roger claims the best Bond was Shakespearean actor Timothy Dalton, saying: “ The films didn’t deserve him. He’d distinguished himself on the stage and did some interesting things with the part.” Not very long ago, Daniel Craig joked that he’d rather slit his wrists than reprise his role as James Bond for a fifth movie. “ I’d rather break this glass and slash my wrists,” he said during an interview with London’s Time Out magazine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ We’re done. All I want to do is move on,” the 47- year- old actor added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; He said he’s not talking with anyone about staying on in Her Majesty’s Secret Service but added the caveat that if he were to do another Bond movie, ‘ it would only be for the money’. Daily Mail Calls for producers to shun political correctness&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline>By Siddhartha Rai in New Delhi</Byline>
    <Headline> NOWRSS RAKES UP  ` 2K Cr LOAN ROW  TOTARGET NITISH</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>New book levels corruption charges on Kumar when he  was minister in NDA govt, JD( U) questions timing of release&lt;p&gt; IN A last- ditch attempt to turn the tables on Mahagathbandhan leader Nitish Kumar in the battle for Bihar, the RSS has accused the state’s chief minister of financial bungling worth ` 2,000 crore. The RSS- affiliated ‘ Shikhsha Sanskriti Utthan Nyas’, led by rightwing educationist Dinanath Batra, has launched a book that claims the scam took place when Nitish was the Union Agriculture Minister in the Atal Bihari Vajpayeeled NDA government during 1998- 99.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The book, titled Bhrashtachar Ka Bolbala ( Rampancy of Corruption), is a personal account of two- time President’s award winner and former assistant director general of Indian Council of Agricultural Research ( ICAR) Sadachari Singh Tomar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Tomar claimed he took up the role of a whistleblower to expose Nistish, who had a hand in the embezzlement of money meant for two World&lt;/p&gt; Bank-funded projects worth `2,000 crore in 1998- 99. The projects were meant for modernisation and computerisation of the agricultural sector. The book has been endorsed by the Right Wing, with Batra and Yoga Guru Ramdeva contributing to it. The foreword has been written by noted anti-corruption activist and lawyer Prashant Bhushan. Reacting sharply to the allegations, JD (U) spokesperson KC Tyagi questioned not just the veracity of the claims, but also the timing of the release of the book. “The BJP will see in Bihar the same results that it saw in Delhi. I categorically reject and condemn such an effort by the BJP and the RSS. This is part of their longstanding strategy of defamation and character assassination. This proves they have lost all hope and are out of issues to take on Nitish Kumar. Such attempts only show their desperation,” he said. Agricultural centres “The two projects were meant for modernising and computerising 437 agricultural centres in the country. The first National Agricultural Research Project of `1000 crore was sanctioned in 1995 and the second National Agricultural Technological Project of equal funding was sanctioned during 1998-99. On visiting the centres, I found that the computer terminals and other equipment were still lying packed. On unpacking we discovered all purchases were substandard,” Tomar told MAIL TODAY. Tomar claimed in his book that he blew the whistle on the alleged irregularities as a member of the project management committee and was victimised for this after Nitish Kumar took over as the agriculture minister. “Nitish Kumar and my superiors who he patronised harassed me as I had collected evidence of their involvement in the bungling of funds. Kumar protected them in the face of several inquiries. When I complained to the Chief Vigilance Commissioner, the then agriculture secretary was relieved from his post, but he came back within 40 days as another inquiry initiated against him exonerated him,” claimed Tomar. “The then PM Atal Behari Vajpayee was in the know of things,” Tomar claimed. Tomar said he was bogged down by seven inquiries initiated against him. “None of them could establish any wrong doing on my part. Then, as a last resort, and that too illegally, I was terminated. All, at the behest of Kumar. Even the CBI that was ordered to probe the matter ignored the evidence I provided,” Tomar said. “I moved the high court which ruled against me as the case went on for 11 years. My lawyer Prashant Bhushan asked for five minutes in court, but he was denied even that. Then we moved the Supreme Court which in 2013 gave me relief. It found the charges against me baseless and reinstated my pension,” Tomar said. Later, Tomar dug up his case by way of RTI applications. “I was shocked to find that the CBI had not even looked at the body of evidence running into 1,066 pages that I had presented. I had also filed a PIL in Delhi High Court after which feathers were ruffled and some officials complicit in the bungling were given voluntary retirement to hush up the matter,” Tomar said. Tomar, meanwhile, had moved from ICAR to Indian Agricultural Research Institute in Pusa. “The biggest incrimination of Nitish Kumar and my vindication is that I spent 5 years in Pusa researching the state of the two projects in India and presented my findings. These were accepted after number of peer reviews. I proved that Kumar presided over the scam,” Tomar alleged. Tomar claimed to have put all these details and the RTI findings in the book. “I have incorporated all the evidence and acts of omission that happened at Kumar’s behest. I have included the RTI information too,” he said. In another startling revelation, Tomar told MAIL TODAY that RSS stalwart and social worker Nanaji Deshmukh too knew of the scam. “We had installed computer systems and networking hardware at Nanaji’s Chitrkoot camp. But the equipment was substandard,” Tomar said. Tomar said Nanaji fell out with PM Vajpayee over this issue. “Nanaji tried to take my case to Vajpayee as he was convinced of the scam. When he arrived at Vajpayee’s residence he was not allowed audience. That was the day he had told me: ‘I will never enter his house’. And he never did,” said Tomar.</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline />
    <Headline> Patel lashes out</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt; Ahmed Patel took a dig at both the AAP government and the BJP- controlled municipal corporations in Delhi saying the litter all around the city over the past few days that is due to strike of sanitation workers could have been avoided. He also said PM Modi’s Swachh Bharat drive should move beyond photo ops and expensive ads and include benefit of sanitation workers across the country.&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline>By Radhika Bhalla  T</Byline>
    <Headline> PRETTY IN pastels</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt;This festive season, celebrate  your feminine side with soft hues  and delicate fabric in celeb style&lt;/p&gt;   &lt;p&gt; T HIS festive season, celebrate your feminine side with soft hues and delicate pastels. Good girls finish first, as Deepika Padukone proves in this beautiful Anju Modi creation that she wore in the Capital recently.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Keeping the saccharin spirit in check, this floor- sweeping anarkali combines powder pink flowers with an overall blueish- grey fabric. The cream coloured top with a key hole neck, and light coloured lipstick ensure that her look is on spot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Complementing her pretty face, Tamannaah Bhatia rocks this light blue strapless gown by Terani Couture to perfection. The silver straps running across the torso and peek- a- boo mesh neck add a sexy, evening flair to the design, with the delicate necklace keeps it princess- like. Pick a clutch bag in a tone similar to the glitter, and complete the look with a rosy tint of lipstick for best results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; For a festive look that doesn’t leave you resembling an overdecked up bride, opt for a lehenga set in any of the delicate hues like cotton candy, soft coral, mint, lavender or lime. Play it smart by contrasting the top and dupatta like Sonam Kapoor has in this ensemble by Shehla Khan, and keep your make- up minimal to match the overall look.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; While the classic pencil dress has given way to a flowy silhouettes and casual- chic styles, Malaika Arora Khan shows how to continue with the trend in this Gauri and Nainika design. The statement flower and leaves details add to the simple look, while the one- shoulder style makes it look fresh/ interesting. Team a pastel hue with white, cream or other light tone shoes and keep your pout a soft yet bright colour.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Tamannaah Bhatia ( left) looks gorgeous in a light blue dress. Sonam Kapoor ( right) keeps it simple in a pink ensemble and minimal make- up, while Malaika Arora ( top right) says with a statement flower&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline>By Manjeet Sehgal  in Chandigarh</Byline>
    <Headline> Punjab shunts top cop to  calm religious tension</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt; growing tension in the state, the Punjab government on Sunday shunted out Sumedh Singh Saini as Director General of Police ( DGP) and appointed Suresh Arora, a 1982- batch IPS officer, as the new DGP. The development comes after Chief Minister Parkash Singh Badal and Shiromani Akali Dal president and Deputy chief minister Sukhbir Singh Badal called an emergency party meeting at Badal's residence on Saturday evening.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Sources close to the party said the party leadership was against Saini continuing as the police chief and that the move is seen to placate frayed tempers and resentment brewing against the police after the recent firing in Faridkot district that left two Sikhs dead during a protest against the desecration of Guru Granth Sahib. On October 14.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; M AIL T ODAY has also learned that Saini had met Sukhbir Singh Badal, who also holds the Home portfolio on October 16 and had offered to step down.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Saini— now transferred to state police housing corporation— though earned kudos for handling the Dinanagar terror attack had failed to arrest the people involved in a series of sacrilege incidents Move after two Sikhs died in police firing on Oct 14&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; besides the Sikh protests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Saini is known for his role in maintaining law and order in Punjab, between 1980 and 1990 in particular when the state was infested with Sikh militancy. He also won the nation's highest award for gallantry in 1987 in recognition of his leadership in operations against the Khalistan terrorists . He was also injured in an assassination attempt made in Chandigarh in 1991.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Meanwhile, new Punjab DGP, Suresh Arora on Sunday said Punjab is passing through a difficult phase and the immediate need is to repose the faith among the masses. “ It is a difficult time. The biggest challenge before me is to foster mutual trust, brotherhood among the masses besides maintaining law and order ,” Arora said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; When questioned how he will tackle the sacrilege incidents, Arora said it is too early to comment as he has yet to take briefings from the SIT which is probing the sacrilege incidents. He also refused to comment on the ‘ foreign hand’ theory given by the police.&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  
  
 
 
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>News</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline>By Astha Saxena  in New Delhi</Byline>
    <Headline> Winter knocks  with swine f lu  and viral scare</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt; EVEN as cases of dengue and malaria have shown a downward trend in the Capital, Delhiites continue to be under risk of viral fever and asthmatic attacks. Doctors have cautioned that the situation may aggravate with the spread of swine flu and due to the onset of winters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In the last few days, there has been a rise in the number of patients complaining of fever, bodyache, cold, cough and breathlessness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ Viral fever usually subsides on the third day but this time we are witnessing patients with consistent fever for five consecutive days. Variations in day and night temperatures confuse our body and increase the physiological stress. The body is unable to regulate fluid intake resulting in dehydration, muscle cramps and fatigue,” Dr Navneet Kaur, Internal Medicine, Apollo Spectra Hospitals told M AIL T ODAY . Carrying an inhaler is becoming a must for those prone to asthma. During winters, joint pains are common, especially among the elderly, but the orthopaedics in the city suggest everyone to take extra care of joints in the season as it promises not only to aggravate joint pain, but also trigger other chronic cases like gout and arthritis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ This is the time of the year when cases of viral fever goes up. People with a history of This is the time of the year when cases of viral fever goes up. People with a history of asthma or breathlessness should carry an inhaler and always cover their face while travelling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; — Dr SP Byotra, Sir Ganga Ram Hospital ‘ ’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; asthma or breathlessness should carry an inhaler and always cover their face while travelling,” Dr SP Byotra, senior consultant, department of Internal medicine, Sir Ganga Ram hospital told M AIL T ODAY . The maximum temperature recorded on Sunday was 32 degrees Celsius while the minimum temperature stood at 20 degrees Celsius. If experts are to be believed then the cases are going to rise in the coming days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ The cases will go up in the coming days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; With the onset of winters, more and more people will complain of viral fever. The earliest recognizable symptoms of a viral infection are often fatigue and body ache.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; This may be followed by fever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Headache is also a common symptom of viral infection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Vomiting and diarrhoea may be present in some cases,” Dr Pranjit Bhowmik, HOD, Internal Medicine, Asian Institute of Medical Science told M AIL T ODAY . According to the doctors, one should go for flu vaccination to avoid falling ill. “ Those having a history of diabetes, asthma, heart and kidney problem should immediately take the flu vaccination.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Even children below the age of five years and people above the age of 65 years should go for the vaccination,” Dr Sushila Kataria, associate director, department of Internal medicine, Medanta said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Experts also recommended that people should keep themselves well hydrated during this period. Water increases the amount of oxygen that the blood is able to carry to all the cells in the body. As a result, all parts of the body functions better, including those that are essential for a strong immune response that helps in repelling viruses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Experts also recommended that people should keep themselves well hydrated during this period&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
 
  
  
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>Special</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline>By LIPLA NEGI  A</Byline>
    <Headline> BALANCE  BACK INTO  YOUR DIET  Bringing</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt;Micronutrients  are crucial to a  balanced diet&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt; A RE YOU taking enough micronutrients? It’s a question that would leave most of us puzzled. Yes, we try to limit the calories by shunning carbs and fats from our diet. But micronutrients seldom cross our mind while having food.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Micronutrients include minerals and vitamins, which play a vital role in growth and proper functioning of the body. “ They often get overshadowed by the macronutrients, which are carbohydrates, protein and fats. Though required in small amount, these play a very significant role in maintaining a healthy body and mind,” says Lovneet Batra, nutritionist, Fortis La Femme, New Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Experts feel that the growing obsession for fad diets, size- zero body and quick weight- loss options is responsible for the insufficient intake of micronutrients. While many do not know and understand the role of essential minerals such as zinc, magnesium, iron, iodine and calcium in a balanced diet, vitamins like A, B, C, E and K get sidelined due to poor dietary habits like not eating fruits and green leafy vegetables, and relying heavily on fast foods.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; SMALL BUT SIGNIFICANT Though required in small quantity, micronutrients play a significant role in optimal functioning of the body’s systems. “ These help strengthen immunity, boost energy levels and remove toxins from the body. Micronutrient deficiency can lead to stunted&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; risk of various diseases in adults,” says Dr Karuna Chaturvedi, consultant nutritionist, Jaypee Hospital, Noida.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; It could also be the hidden cause of many common problems like muscle ache, hair fall, headache, weakness and lethargy. “ We may not feel it but these nutrients do affect our performance and productivity. For example, iron deficiency can result in muscle breakdown or anaemia. Low calcium can lead to abnormal flow of blood during menses. Likewise, zinc deficiency can give you hair fall and dull skin. While phosphorous is important for healthy teeth and bones, copper boosts metabolism,” explains Dr Sanjeev Bagai, vice- chairman and director, Manipal Hospital, Dwarka.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; HECTIC STUMPS HEALTHY Think of healthy eating, and most of us imagine that it means eating less. However, eating healthy simply means eating mindfully.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ When it comes to eating a balanced diet, ‘ time’ becomes the biggest challenge for most people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Due to hectic lifestyle, people often compromise on the nutritive value of the food. They are too busy and overworked to cook three meals a day, which have a balance of macro and micro&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; but it lacks nutrition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The desire to lose weight faster also leads to micronutrient deficiency. They go for fad diets, which are neither wholesome nor nutritious.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ You need to have a holistic approach towards diet. All food groups are equally important, which is why it is called a balanced diet,” says Batra.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; NAIL THE NUTRITION If feeling fresh, well rested and energetic is what you want, then you must take up your daily intake of fruits, vegetables and cereals — easy and excellent sources of minerals and vitamins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ Aim for at least three serving for fruits and two servings of vegetables,” advises Batra. Mindful eating is the best way to squeeze “ It requires changing of a few habits such as taking out time for food rather than having it in a hurry. Take your meals on time because eating late slows down your metabolism and disturbs the absorption of nutrients,” she adds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Also, minimise the consumption of processed foods.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ If you know your day is going to be hectic, pack a salad or smoothie. You only need a few minutes to make these! Delicious and filling, these offer a powerful punch of nutrients and antioxidants,” suggests Dr Batra. While buying grocery, go for local and seasonal foods. “ It’s best to take your nutrition from fresh food.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Supplements are fine but the rate of absorption is not as good as real food,” says she.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; lipla. negi@ mailtoday. in Take your meals on time because eating late slows down metabolism and disturbs the absorption of nutrients. Avoid processed foods&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>Special</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline>By Kumar Vikram in Vaishali/  Siddhartha Rai in New Delhi</Byline>
    <Headline> BJP BACKS JOB QUOTA TO ENSURE WIN  ‘ ‘</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt;SUNDAY was a day of making amends by the BJP. The prime minister tried to allay apprehensions regarding BJP’s views on caste- based reservations though indirectly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In an obvious reference to which class he was talking to, he made an attempt to appropriate Dalit icon BR Ambedkar in his ‘ Mann ki Baat’ programme. He declared that Ambedkar’s London house was now Indian property and that it had been converted into a memorial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; In the 13th edition of the monthly programme, Modi tried to assure the weaker sections, mentioning that state and central governments were providing scholarships to tribal and backward communities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Apprehensive that it could do some damage, the Grand Alliance cried hoarse as the PM also announced the abolition of interviews in Group B, C and D nongazetted posts in the central government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; JD( U) spokesperson KC Tyagi accused the PM of making way for implementing the vision of the RSS chief Mohan Bhagwat who had called for a review of the policy of quota.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Saffron brigade looks concerned as the state is headed for third and fourth phases of polling in next few days. The main challenge is to remove the confusion over RSS chief Mohan Bhagwat statement on reservation. To undo the damage, the party has fielded its foot soldiers to make people understand its view on reservation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; BJP chief Amit Shah has deployed about a dozen of ministers and senior leaders for the two phases of polls which is crucial for the party. Union ministers, including Rajiv Pratap Rudy, Ram Kripal Yadav, Radha Mohan Singh, have been given seperate charge of districts and they have been asked to camp in districts to closely monitor the ground level management.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Party workers in Vaishali said that Bhagwat’s statements suggesting a review of the reservations has gone against the party in the first two phases of polling. “ Caste has always played significant roles in Bihar politics. Youths are highly dependent on caste- based reservations, for everything, whether it is admission in colleges or jobs or benefits of government schemes,” said a party worker in Vaishali.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Following the reactions over RSS chief Mohan Bhagwat’s comment, Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Sunday said there will be no dilution in reservation and that there has been no change wherever there is a BJP government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Out of the remaining three phases, two phases of polls is crucial for the BJP. In third phase, polling is scheduled to take place in the Lok Sabha seats of Rajiv Pratap Rudy, Ashwini Chaube, RK Singh, Shatrughan Sinha and Ram Kripal Yadav. BJP is contesting 34 of the 50 seats and its partners have been given only 16 seats in this round.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; BJP chief has deployed dozen of ministers and senior leaders to closely monitor the ground level management for the upcoming crucial phases&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt; ‘ ‘ ‘ ‘ Caste has always played significant role in Bihar politics. Youth are highly dependent on caste- based reservations, for everything, whether it is admission in colleges or jobs or benefits of government schemes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; — A BJP worker&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
 
 
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>Special</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline>By Giridhar Jha  in Saran/ Hajipur</Byline>
    <Headline> Modi’s 6- point  formula for  Bihar’s growth</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt;HOLDING Chief Minister Nitish Kumar and Rashtriya Janata Dal president Lalu Prasad squarely responsible for the underdevelopment of Bihar over the past 25 years, Prime Minister Narendra Modi on Sunday offered his formula for the allround progress of the state.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Addressing as many as four rallies at Marhaura ( Saran), Hajipur, Nalanda and Naubatpur ( Patna) three days before the crucial third- phase polling in Bihar, Modi said that his party had a six- point formula to propel the state on the fast- track of development if the NDA was voted to power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ Our agenda for the state is bijli ( electricity), paani ( water) and sadak ( roads),” he said. “ As for the families, we will ensure padhai ( education), kamaai ( employment) and dawaai ( healthcare for elders).” Dubbing the grand alliance of the Janata Dal- United, Rashtriya Janata Dal and the Congress as a veritable symbol of dambh ( arrogance), daman ( oppression) and dagaa ( betrayal), he said that these parties had ruined Bihar in their respective 60- year- long reign and the time had come to teach them a lesson in the ongoing polls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ I have mustered courage to talk about development in this election but they remain busy trying to denigrate me all the time” Modi said. “ But the more they sling the mud on me the more lotuses bloom in Bihar,” he said, referring to the election symbol of the BJP. Hitting back at the criticism of Nitish and Lalu that the people of Bihar did not need a baahri ( outsider) like him to run the state, Modi asked as to who was responsible for forcing the Bihari youth to leave their villages in search of livelihood and become outsiders elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ Lalu and Nitish must explain who has made these youths outsiders in other states,” he said, while exhorting people to elect a government that could check the migration of its talented work force.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The Prime Minister said that the places such as Saran district were known for its chocolate factory and sugar mills but all the industries later closed down for want of electricity. “ May I know who are responsible for the closure of those factories which once provided employment to the local youths?” he asked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; On pulses issue, he accused the Nitish Kumar government of deliberately creating the crisis for electoral reasons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Addressing a rally at Hajipur, Modi asked Nitish to explain as to why his government had not conducted raids on the hoarders to seize pulses from them in the state. “ In the rest of the country, 72,000 tonnes of pulses have been recovered in the course of raids on the hoarders,” he said. “ Bihar is the only state where this has not been done because of the polls.” Alleging that those who had set their eyes on the fodder were now eyeing the pulses, he warned the hoarders to mend their ways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; FAMILIES, Says Nitish govt willfully creating crisis of pulses&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
  
 
  <Article>
    <Publication>Mail Today</Publication>
    <Frequency>Daily</Frequency>
    <ArticleName>Sports</ArticleName>
    <Publishdate> October 26, 2015</Publishdate>
    <Byline>By Shaghil Bilali in Gurgaon</Byline>
    <Headline> Emily wins  Indian crown  Emily wins  Indian crown</Headline>
    <Bodytext>
      <Bodytext>&lt;p&gt;Scores awire- to- wire  victory for her maiden LET  title as Cheyenne fumbles&lt;/p&gt;   &lt;p&gt; D ANE rookie Emily Kristine Pedersen had a dream end to her campaign at the Hero Women’s Indian Open as she registered a thrilling wire- to- wire victory at the Black Knight Course here on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; The 19- year- old High School student made bogeys on the final two holes, but her one- over 73 in the final round and even- par 216 aggregate was enough for a one- stroke triumph.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; It was redemption of sorts for Emily after she lost in the play- off at the Lacoste Ladies Open de France last month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; However, at one point on Sunday, the title seemed up for grabs as Tiger Woods’s niece Cheyenne took the lead after a birdie on the 11th hole, but her hopes of a second Ladies European Tour title were dashed by an 18th- hole double bogey.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Cheyenne’s one- under 71 in the final round left her one- stroke short of Emily, in the company of Welshwoman Becky Morgan ( 73) and another Dane Malene Jorgensen ( 72).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; No Indian golfer made an impression and they never looked like serious title contenders. Amateur Aditi Ashok ( 77) at tied 11th and Vani Kapoor ( 75) at 20th did some face- saving exercise, while it was a nightmarish experience for Saaniya Sharma and Smriti Mehra, who shot 11- over 83 each in the last round to end the week in 60th and 62nd positions respectively.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Emily covered her mouth in disbelief after sinking her last putt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ When I made a bogey on 17th hole, memories of the defeat in France came to my mind. I was thinking there could be another play- off, but am extremely happy that I won my first title. India was a nice experience. I was on my first trip and won a wire- to- wire title, there couldn’t have been a better experience,” said Emily, who promised to return next year to defend her title.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Cheyenne shared the limelight with the Dane for a couple of hours on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; No one would have given her a chance when she hit a 77 on the first day, but after a second- round 69, the Indian Open trophy looked within her grasp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; On Sunday, she took the course by storm firing birdies on the second, fourth, sixth and 11th holes. She was in sole lead before a bogey on 15th. However, she was still in joint lead and looked capable of pipping Emily, but the American’s second shot on 18th found the bunker.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Her recovery shot hit the cart path and the ball went into right bush. She took a penalty drop and ended up with a double bogey.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; She needed Emily to make a double bogey to take the contest into a play- off.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Emily’s hands were shaking when she stood over her 12- feet up- and- down par putt on the 18th, which she missed. But a tense- looking Dane sank bogey putt from three feet to win the title.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ I played fantastic golf throughout the day, but you can’t win a tournament after a double bogey on the final hole,” Cheyenne said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Becky also missed the chance to take the tournament into a play- off after dropping a shot on the last hole, while Malene managed a par to finish one stroke behind Emily.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Aditi showed inconsistent form as she made three birdies, four bogeys and two double bogeys on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “ I didn’t play bad except on Hole Nos. 4 and 10, where I made a double bogey each. It was a tough course and I learnt a lot from playing in the Indian Open,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Aditi will now tee off at the Sanya Ladies Open in China from November 6- 8.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Amateur Aditi finishes as the best Indian at 11th spot, while Vani ends 20th at the Indian Open&lt;/p&gt;</Bodytext>
    </Bodytext>
    <Copyright>Reproduced From Mail Today. Copyright 2015. MTNPL. All rights reserved.</Copyright>
  </Article>
 
 
</Articles>
