<story>
<id>682368</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>no</story_issue>
<select_magazine>0</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date/>
<bylines>
<byline>366</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464769215</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464768812</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1464775576</modifieddate>
<createdby>880</createdby>
<modifiedby>820</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city>285563</city>
</cities>
<categories><category>938496</category></categories><ordering>682368</ordering><primarycategory>938496</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/20160601_124320_559_060116015015.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt/>
<extra_large_title/>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/20160601_124320_305_060116015015.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt/>
<large_title/>
<mediumimage/>
<mediumimage_alt/>
<mediumimage_title/>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/20160601_124320_180_060116015015.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt/>
<smallimage_title/>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/20160601_124320_88_060116015015.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt/>
<extra_small_title/>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption/>
<mosimage>
<image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/ui_060116030017.jpg]]></image><caption/><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/performance_060116015309.jpg]]></image><caption/><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/should-you-buy_060116015309.jpg]]></image><caption/></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title>LG G5</title><rating>7.5/10</rating><pron_cons_img>http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday//images/stories/20160601_124320_305_060116014915.jpg </pron_cons_img></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item>Excellent display</item><item>Flagship-class performance</item><item>Fun, fantastic cameras</item><item>Excellent audio performance</item></tech_pros><tech_cons><item>Not enough modules</item><item>Lacklustre build quality</item><item>Low-light photography</item><item>Disappointing battery life</item></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image>http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/1_060116021529.jpg  </image>  <image>http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/2_060116021529.jpg  </image>  <image>http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/3_060116021529.jpg  </image>  <image>http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/4_060116021529.jpg  </image>  <image>http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/5_060116021529.jpg  </image>  <image>http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/6_060116021529.jpg  </image>  <image>http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/7_060116021529.jpg  </image>  <image>http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/8_060116021529.jpg  </image>  </tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[  Does the LG G5 edge past the Galaxys (and others) on the back of 
its one-of-a-kind modular approach? We find out. ]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>Even as Google continues to think and rethink on its apparently game-changing Project Ara that aims to create a modular phone, South Korean giant LG has gone ahead and given to us what it thinks is the real game-changer in terms of smartphone innovation in 2016. The LG G5, for all intends and purposes, is the world's first commercially available modular smartphone. <br /></p><p>Although its modularity is limited -- right now -- you can't argue with the fact that the G5 is a gadget straight out of the future, much like Sony's 4K-toting <a target="_blank" href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/technology/story/sony-xperia-z5-review-best-phone-ever-made-by-sony/1/522176.html">Xperia Z5</a>  Premium. A future in which "one smartphone fits them all" concept would mean the end of having to buy a new phone every year. The possibilities!</p><p>On the inside, the G5 - successor to the critically-acclaimed G4 - is LG's current-generation flagship smartphone, packed with top features and hardware. All that innovation and high-end hardware will cost you Rs 52,990 in India, which falls in between the <a target="_blank" href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/technology/story/samsung-galaxy-s7-edge-and-galaxy-s7-review-on-the-edge-of-perfection/1/630463.html">Samsung Galaxy S7 and the Galaxy S7 Edge.</a>  Does the LG G5 edge past the Galaxys (and others) on the back of its one-of-a-kind modular approach? Not really. But, it's fun nevertheless. Wish it had more friends to join in.<br /></p><h3>Design and build quality<br /></h3><p>The LG G5 is an all-metal smartphone that doesn't try to copy other smartphones. At the same time, it isn't just another incremental update over its all-plastic predecessor. It's different and that's a good thing. Subtle curves exist all along the body to help enhance its looks and grip. LG has skipped curved 2.5D glass on the front and instead opted for a more uniform flat surface - of Corning Gorilla Glass 4 -- that sort of eases into the top end via a distinctive curve. Since the lower end of the phone is all silver (metal), the distinctive curve at the top, which is all black, gives out the impression of a curved display. It doesn't solve any real-world purpose though. Maybe a second ticker screen like the one in the LG V10 would have made more sense here but hey, that's just nit-picking. The G5 does have an always-on display, so everyone's a winner here.<br /></p><p class="review_quote"><i class="fa fa-quote-left"></i>   The lower end of the phone is where all the action is happening. It is removable and swappable. Inside lies the battery, again removable and swappable. The whole thing pops out with the help of a small button   <i class="fa fa-quote-right"></i></p><p class="review_also_read"><b>Also Read: </b> <a href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/technology/story/lgs-modular-g5-phone-up-for-pre-booking-in-india-from-may-21/1/673125.html " title=""> LG G5 to be sold in India for Rs 52,990, pre-booking starts </a></p><p>The lower end of the phone is where all the action is happening. It is removable and swappable. Inside lies the battery, again removable and swappable. The whole thing pops out with the help of a small button. But wait, it's not that simple. The button sits rather flush which means it wants your unflinching attention at all times and pulling out the module (and the battery) takes some time and effort. You'll have to get used to it. Popping it out and swapping it with a different module (and battery) seemed way cooler on paper. Not so much in real life. Even when your module has been properly inserted - a gentle clicking sound is your cue here - there remains a very small gap between the adjoining surfaces, even more so on the front. Now LG managed to build invisible antennas on the G5. The gap kind of takes all that effort away, and oh, it collects dust over time. All of a sudden, the G5 doesn't look all that metal unibody anymore.<br /></p><p><iframe src="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/technology/embedegallery_tech.jsp?gid=17029" mce_src="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/technology/embedegallery_tech.jsp?gid=17029" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" class="embedgalleryt" frameborder="0"></iframe>Speaking of which, the quality of metal used in the G5 leaves a lot to be desired. It's metal that doesn't feel all that metallic. The problem is accentuated every time you pop out a module. The whole upper body feels hollow and for the lack of a better word, plastic. LG has opted for a rear-mounted fingerprint scanner on the G5 which is fine. It also doubles as the power button of the phone which could be a problem for some users. It's because there's no way to use the phone while it's lying flat on a surface on a lazy Sunday afternoon. It does support double tap to wake gestures, but you'll have to pick up the device to unlock it anyways, unless of course you're okay with typing in the secure password. Moreover, the circular button is a little too small for a fingerprint scanner. And a little too tacky. This means the fingerprint scanner on the G5 pales in comparison to the ones on the iPhone 6S, the Galaxy S7 and even the <a target="_blank" href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/technology/story/google-nexus-6p-review-the-best-android-phone-you-can-buy/1/507979.html">Nexus 6P</a> . It's fast but it's just not accurate enough.<br /></p><p>The LG G5 may be different, but it does not radiate the type of confidence that a certain Galaxy S7 or the iPhone 6S or even the Nexus 6P do.<br /></p><h3>Display<br /></h3><p>The LG G5 has a 5.3-inch QuadHD IPS LCD display with a 1440x2560 pixels resolution which roughly translates to an impressive 554 ppi. The display is fantastic. Colours look nice and well-saturated. Not as in-your-face popping Galaxy S7 saturated, but truer to life saturated. Brightness levels and viewing angles are top-notch and outdoor legibility is in line with rival top-tier phones like the S7 and the iPhone 6S, if not better.<br /></p><p class="review_also_read"><b>Also Read: </b> <a href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/technology/story/lg-g5-quick-review-something-different-something-playful/1/601138.html " title=""> LG G5 quick review: Something different, something playful </a></p><p>The G5 - much like the Galaxy S7 and the Lumia 950 - has an always-on display feature that keeps select pixels on the screen awake even while the phone is powered down. This gives you access to the clock and your notifications at all times without having you to worry about powering the phone up. It is ridiculously dim though. <br /></p><h3>Software<br /></h3><p>{mosimage}The LG G5 runs Android 6.0.1 Marshmallow with LG's custom skin UX on top. The latest version of its take on Android skips an app drawer and instead comes with a spring board of apps and widgets spanning multiple home screens much like it is in the iPhone. Whether or not you like the approach will ultimately depend on how sorted you like your things to be. I for one prefer the app drawer approach where in everything seems better organised and less of a chaos. There are ways around LG's approach to bring back the app drawer thankfully. That it can be done without deploying any third-party themes is a plus. You can either use the pre-installed EasyHome theme or download and install the Home 4.0 launcher from its app store.<br /></p><p>Still, LG's take on Android isn't entirely a lost cause especially when you compare it with the UIs employed by certain Chinese OEMs who blindly follow the iPhone with no thought or logic. LG's UI, save the no app drawer thing, is totally different from its peers in look as well as functionality. It may take some time getting used to initially but once you're through that phase it's pretty much a smooth ride. LG's UI also stays true to Google's Android where it can, for instance the apps overview and edit home screen windows are almost stock. <br /></p><p>The software also offers a lot of customisation options, which should impress those who like to tailor-make the way their phone looks. And it's slick, slicker than Samsung's TouchWiz. And much smoother.<br /></p><h3>Performance and battery life<br /></h3><p>The LG G5 is powered by Qualcomm's latest and greatest Snapdragon 820 mobile processor (quad-core clocked at 2.15GHz) coupled with Adreno 530 GPU and 4GB of RAM. That's flagship-class hardware checked. As expected, its performance is at par with top-tier phones more notably the Galaxy S7. Thanks to its slick user interface it runs smooth as butter. This phone actually feels faster than the S7 in actual usage. Benchmark scores however pit it slightly below Samsung's top-tier phone.<br /></p><p>The LG G5 breezes through every task-- ranging from basic to hard-hitting -- that you throw at it without breaking a sweat. The phone does have a tendency to get slightly warm on occasions like gaming but good thing is that it never gets out of hand.<br /></p><p>The phone comes with 32GB of on-board memory which is further expandable by up to a whopping 2TB via a hybrid microSD card slot. The mono speaker setup on the G5 gets very loud, louder than most rival phones with little or no distortion at peak volume. Phone calls made with it are of excellent quality and we did not encounter any odd call drop issues with our review unit. The G5 supports dualSIM and 4G LTE.<br /></p><p class="review_quote"><i class="fa fa-quote-left"></i>   There's not much to complain about the G5s overall performance. However it has an Achilles heel to deal with   <i class="fa fa-quote-right"></i></p><p>{mosimage}There's not much to complain about the G5s overall performance. However it has an Achilles heel to deal with. The battery life of the G5 is fairly disappointing. The 2,800mAh battery inside the phone got exhausted in mere 9-10 hours on extreme usage, meanwhile moderate to light usage got us close to a full working day on some occasions. This is one area where the Galaxy S7 convincingly outperforms the G5.<br /></p><p>LG however compensates for its dismal battery life by allowing users to keep a spare one at hand and conveniently swap it to get back in the game. No other smartphone in this price bracket gives you that option. Moreover, Qualcomm's Quick Charge 3.0 feature ensures the phone charges like a bullet. But wireless charging is not supported.<br /></p><h3>LG Friends<br /></h3><p>The main USP of the LG G5 is its support for swappable companion modules that it calls 'Friends'. Right now it has just a couple: the LG Cam Plus which is basically a fancy camera grip with some extra battery and the LG Hi-Fi Plus which is basically a Bang and Olufsen digital-to-analogue converter and headphone amplifier.<br /></p><p>The LG Cam Plus includes a toggle switch to quick launch the camera, a dial wheel for zooming in and out while shooting, a shutter button and a video recording button. The LG Hi-Fi Plus on the other hand is the one for audiophiles, even more so because it can be connected to other devices as well.<br /></p><p>The LG companion accessories are limited at the moment which means it wouldn't pull a crowd to make a purchase. These are fun but not compelling enough for an impulsive buy. Maybe one day, just not right now. <br /></p><h3>Camera<br /></h3><p>LG believes two rear cameras are better than one. The G5 has a dual-camera setup on the back:16-megapixel (f/1.8) plus 8-megapixel (f/2.4). It is accompanied by a laser autofocus, 3-axis optical image stabilisation and LED flash. LG's approach is different from what Huawei employs in its flagship P9 phone. In LG's case, while one of the cameras (16MP) has what you can call a regular lens, the other (8MP) one has a wider lens. A wider lens means the phone's rear snapper can cover a larger area with a distinct fish-eye effect on the edges. It kind of gives you a 3D-like panorama sweep of what you're clicking without having you to move your phone in a certain manner. It shouldn't be confused with an actual panorama shot though.<br /></p><p>Switching between the two lenses happens seamlessly with just a tap on an option that rests comfortably on the screen all the while that you have the camera app up and running. It's actually quite fast to switch and is as fast to focus and shoot. In fact you never lose a breath while switching between the two lenses which makes the G5 all the more fun to play around with. Every time I took a regular picture, I made sure to click the same shot again with the wider lens just to see how things looked from a wider perspective.</p><p>Moreover LG has put in cute software features to make the two lenses even cooler to play around with. One allows you to superimpose the subject clicked with the regular cam over the wider background clicked by the other lens. Another one lets you click three photos in one go and create a collage out of it. <br /></p><p class="review_quote"><i class="fa fa-quote-left"></i>  
Every time I took a regular picture, I made sure to click the same shot again with the wider lens just to see how things looked from a wider perspective  
<i class="fa fa-quote-right"></i></p><p>As for image quality, it's fantastic especially in good light. Both the rear cameras boast of excellent dynamic range. Images clicked with them have no visible metering issues so that level of detail stays put on almost all occasions. The image quality of the wider lens toting camera is slightly inferior to the regular one, but it more than compensates for it courtesy its wider scope.<br /></p><p>Low light photography is where the G5 pales in comparison to the Galaxy S7. Low light photos tend to have some noise every now and then.<br /></p><p>The G5 has an 8-megapixel camera on the front with f/2.0 aperture and it clicks fantastic selfies. Selfies clicked with the G5's front cam boast of excellent detail even in low light. The sensor does tend to over-saturate colours just a tad bit, but overall pretty neat stuff.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><div class="container img-gal-box" id="modal-popup"><div class="row" id="mn_img"><div class="col-lg-3 col-md-3 col-sm-4 col-xs-6 glr"><a title="Image 1" href="#"><img class="thumbnail img-responsive" src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/1_060116021529.jpg"></a></div><div class="col-lg-3 col-md-3 col-sm-4 col-xs-6 glr"><a title="Image 1" href="#"><img class="thumbnail img-responsive" src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/2_060116021529.jpg"></a></div><div class="col-lg-3 col-md-3 col-sm-4 col-xs-6 glr"><a title="Image 1" href="#"><img class="thumbnail img-responsive" src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/3_060116021529.jpg"></a></div><div class="col-lg-3 col-md-3 col-sm-4 col-xs-6 glr pos_rel"><a title="Image 1" href="#"><img class="thumbnail img-responsive" src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/4_060116021529.jpg"></a><div class="seemore"><a title="seemore" href="#"><img class="" src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/tech/gallery-popup/images/see-pic.png"></a></div>  </div><div class="col-lg-3 col-md-3 col-sm-4 col-xs-6 glr hd1"><a title="Image 1" href="#"><img class="thumbnail img-responsive" src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/5_060116021529.jpg"></a></div><div class="col-lg-3 col-md-3 col-sm-4 col-xs-6 glr hd1"><a title="Image 1" href="#"><img class="thumbnail img-responsive" src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/6_060116021529.jpg"></a></div><div class="col-lg-3 col-md-3 col-sm-4 col-xs-6 glr hd1"><a title="Image 1" href="#"><img class="thumbnail img-responsive" src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/7_060116021529.jpg"></a></div><div class="col-lg-3 col-md-3 col-sm-4 col-xs-6 glr hd1"><a title="Image 1" href="#"><img class="thumbnail img-responsive" src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/8_060116021529.jpg"></a></div></div><div class="row"><div class="modal modal_embed" role="dialog"><div class="modal-dialog" style="max-width: 1011.2px; max-height: 735.2px;"><div class="modal-content"> <span class="close_btt" data-dismiss="modal">X</span><div class="modal-body"><div id="modalCarousel" class="carousel"><div class="carousel-inner"><div class="item active" title="Image 1"><a title="Image 1" href="#"><img class="thumbnail img-responsive" src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/1_060116021529.jpg"></a></div><div class="item" title="Image 1"><a title="Image 1" href="#"><img class="thumbnail img-responsive" src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/2_060116021529.jpg"></a></div><div class="item" title="Image 1"><a title="Image 1" href="#"><img class="thumbnail img-responsive" src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/3_060116021529.jpg"></a></div><div class="item" title="Image 1"><a title="Image 1" href="#"><img class="thumbnail img-responsive" src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/4_060116021529.jpg"></a><div class="seemore"><a title="seemore" href="#"><img class="" src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/tech/gallery-popup/images/see-pic.png"></a></div></div><div class="item" title="Image 1"><a title="Image 1" href="#"><img class="thumbnail img-responsive" src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/5_060116021529.jpg"></a></div><div class="item" title="Image 1"><a title="Image 1" href="#"><img class="thumbnail img-responsive" src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/6_060116021529.jpg"></a></div><div class="item" title="Image 1"><a title="Image 1" href="#"><img class="thumbnail img-responsive" src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/7_060116021529.jpg"></a></div><div class="item" title="Image 1"><a title="Image 1" href="#"><img class="thumbnail img-responsive" src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/8_060116021529.jpg"></a></div></div><div class="dtv"><ul><li><img src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/1_060116021529.jpg" alt="" pr="1"></li>  <li><img src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/2_060116021529.jpg" alt="" pr="2"></li>  <li><img src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/3_060116021529.jpg" alt="" pr="3"></li>  <li><img src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/4_060116021529.jpg" alt="" pr="4"></li>  <li><img src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/5_060116021529.jpg" alt="" pr="5"></li>  <li><img src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/6_060116021529.jpg" alt="" pr="6"></li>  <li><img src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/7_060116021529.jpg" alt="" pr="7"></li>  <li><img src="http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/techblog/8_060116021529.jpg" alt="" pr="8"></li>  </ul></div><a class="left carousel-control" href="#modalCarousel" role="button" data-slide="prev"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-chevron-left" aria-hidden="true"></span><span class="sr-only">Previous</span></a><a class="right carousel-control" href="#modalCarousel" role="button" data-slide="next"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-chevron-right" aria-hidden="true"></span><span class="sr-only">Next</span></a></div></div></div></div></div></div></div><p>&nbsp;</p><h3>Should you buy it?<br /></h3><p>{mosimage}The LG G5 is a phone straight out of the future. But it's not quite there yet. Its main USP is its modularity. But it's more like a work in progress than a finished product.</p><p>Take that away and it is still a pretty good flagship smartphone. It's just not good enough as the Samsung Galaxy S7. The Galaxy S7 has a better design, a more saturated display, better cameras and much better battery life. This puts the LG G5 in a tight spot. Maybe a year ago, the G5 would have made heads turn, in 2016 it is just another star in this star-studded galaxy. The only reason why someone should consider this right now is the promise of a swappable battery. But is that compelling enough? The choice is all yours. <br /></p> <p class="review_also_read"><b>Also Read: </b> <a href=" http://indiatoday.intoday.in/technology/story/lg-g5-specs-features-and-everything-you-need-to-know/1/601104.html " title=""> LG G5: Specs, features, and everything you need to know  </a></p>####<div class='tech-pros-cons-main'><h2>LG G5####<strong>7.5/10</strong></h2>####<ul class='pron-cons-img'><li><img src='http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday//images/stories/20160601_124320_305_060116014915.jpg' ></li></ul>####<ul class='tech-pros'><li><span>Good stuff</span></li><li>Excellent display</li><li>Flagship-class performance</li><li>Fun, fantastic cameras</li><li>Excellent audio performance</li></ul>####<ul class='tech-cons'><li><span>Bad stuff</span></li><li>Not enough modules</li><li>Lacklustre build quality</li><li>Low-light photography</li><li>Disappointing battery life</li></ul></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p></div></p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[  Does the LG G5 edge past the Galaxys (and others) on the back of 
its one-of-a-kind modular approach? We find out. ]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>305171</tag>
<tag>493951</tag>
<tag>495045</tag>
<tag>430379</tag>
<tag>342127</tag>
<tag>833226</tag>
<tag>993309</tag>
<tag>735372</tag>
<tag>622721</tag>
<tag>1186401</tag>
<tag>1203554</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[LG G5 review: Just another star in the galaxy]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[LG G5 review: Just another star in the galaxy]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[LG G5 review: Just another star in the galaxy]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>3</like>
<dislike>1</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/technology/story/lg-g5-review-just-another-star-in-the-galaxy/1/682368.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[LG G5 review: Just another star in the galaxy]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/20160601_124320_559_060116015015.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[LG G5 review: Just another star in the galaxy]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/20160601_124320_559_060116015015.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>1</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion>7.5</commentquestion>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[lg-g5-review-just-another-star-in-the-galaxy]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[LG G5 review: Just another star in the galaxy]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[lg g5, lg g5 modular smartphone, modular smartphone, samsung galaxy s7, galaxy s7 edge, lg g5 review, lg g5 software, lg g5 price, lg g5 battery, lg g5 performance, lg g5 camera]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>