<story>
<id>682456</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>no</story_issue>
<select_magazine>0</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date/>
<bylines>
<byline>304</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464775337</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464774601</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1464776650</modifieddate>
<createdby>799</createdby>
<modifiedby>799</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city>285563</city>
</cities>
<categories><category>280038</category><category>938414</category><category>279990</category><category>937785</category></categories><ordering>682456</ordering><primarycategory>937785</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/phobia-story+fb_647_060116033557.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt><![CDATA[Poster of Phobia]]></extra_large_alt>
<extra_large_title><![CDATA[Poster of Phobia]]></extra_large_title>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/phobia-story+fb_305_060116033557.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt><![CDATA[Poster of Phobia]]></large_alt>
<large_title><![CDATA[Poster of Phobia]]></large_title>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/phobia-story+fb_300x350_060116033557.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt><![CDATA[Poster of Phobia]]></mediumimage_alt>
<mediumimage_title><![CDATA[Poster of Phobia]]></mediumimage_title>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/phobia-story+fb_180_060116033557.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt><![CDATA[Poster of Phobia]]></smallimage_alt>
<smallimage_title><![CDATA[Poster of Phobia]]></smallimage_title>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/phobia-story+fb_88_060116033557.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt><![CDATA[Poster of Phobia]]></extra_small_alt>
<extra_small_title><![CDATA[Poster of Phobia]]></extra_small_title>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption><![CDATA[Poster of Phobia]]></kicker_image_caption>
<mosimage>
<image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/phobia-mos_060116034126.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[Pavan Kirpalani]]></caption></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[Phobia director Pavan Kirpalani talks about leading lady Radhika Apte, Delhi's Nirbhaya case, his inspiration and much more.&nbsp; ]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>Pavan Kirpalani would rather have you forget that he made Darr @ the Mall. He is honest enough to admit that it was a "highly objectionable" film. But post Ragini MMS, his directorial debut which he says was "a very adulterated version of what I wanted to put out there", offers weren't flying his way either. Two years of taking a script from one studio to another, he was "desperate and completely broke". So Darr @ the Mall. "I was like let me do something while I pursue what I want to make," he says. "Unfortunately that never happened. Darr threw me back even more. It was very tough to get a film after it." The film's failure made a studio back out of one of his projects.</p><p><u><b><a target="_blank" href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/phobia-review-radhika-apte-is-terrifyingly-good-in-this-psychological-horror/1/678587.html" mce_href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/phobia-review-radhika-apte-is-terrifyingly-good-in-this-psychological-horror/1/678587.html">PHOBIA REVIEW: Radhika Apte is terrifyingly good in this psychological horror film</a></b></u> <br />&nbsp; <br />And then came Phobia. Finally, Kirpalani has made a film he is proud of and rightly so for it is one of the smarter psychological thrillers to come out of Bollywood, featuring a fine performance by Radhika Apte. "It is the first film I have made that is utterly an extension of who I am," he says. "I really did what I wanted to."</p><p><i>Edited excerpts from a conversation.&nbsp; </i>&nbsp;<br /><b></b></p><p><b>It has taken you a while to comeback after Ragini MMS.</b><br />Personally I don't like Ragini MMS. I had no say after a point in what went out. I cringe when I see it. What it was and what it finally came to be were two different things. But that was film school really. &nbsp;</p><p>Phobia is my kind of space. This is my first real attempt at the horror genre. I realised I had to write a very small film if I want to make another [film], because nobody would give me money. I came across this idea [of agoraphobia] and started exploring it. I was also constantly thinking of how to end it. Once I hit upon the climax, I got really excited about it. I remember that very day I went to the house of my editor (Pooja Ladha Surti) and narrated it to her. She also thought it was amazing. But we wondered who was going to make it? </p><p>Before that I had met Radhika (Apte). We had coffee at Leaping Windows ([a cafe in Yarid Road, Mumbai), where I gave her a five-minute narration. I told her the beginning, the ending and the themes I want to explore. She flipped on the ending. She was also writing something on panic disorders. I said I'd call her if it ever happens. It took me a year to write it and then I took it to studios. When I first pitched it to Eros, they said No, that it's too off. But then someone else at Eros saw it and they really liked it and pushed for&nbsp; it. By then Badlapur was a success and Manjhi did well. Suddenly Radhika was hot property. </p><p><b>And does she deliver. </b><br />She found so much truth in the character that even I couldn't find. She can internalise it so well and add so much to it. The scene when she steps out to face Manu [Ankur Vikal]... what was written on the page was only half as funny. The level she takes it to with the desperation she brings to the moment. She was really nervous while making the film about how people would react. Is it too one-note? Weird? She was desperate to see the first cut. When she saw it, she was so relieved. </p><p><b>Phobia is very relevant film for our times as it talks about a woman's consent which is rarely touched upon in Indian cinema. </b><br />We knew that we wanted to play with the dynamics in a relationship between a man and a woman. We wanted Mahek (Radhika Apte) to have control over her life. That's why the film starts off with the Kafka line. We were always looking at her as a free bird. When she survives a sexual attack, she goes into the cage. In fact we played with the bird motif throughout the film. The idea was to keep everything subtextual and just play up with genre elements.</p><p>{mosimage}&nbsp;</p><p><b>Playing the tropes of horror and then subverting them is one of the factors why the film comes across as funny. </b><br />We were trying to sell audiences a genre film but we knew we weren't making one eventually. We were well aware of the tropes being used. I and my DP (director of photography) Jayakrishna Gummadi constantly worked on the subversion. We were making fun of a lot of things. We were dealing with a serious subject, but we needed to make it lighter. I find it really odd that when we are dealing with a dramatic situation in film, why is everyone so serious about it. Everyone around her is not going through the same problem [as her]. So you've the young female neighbour who is bored and adding more to the conspiracy. And there's Manu who is the quintessential creepy neighbour. We removed all the clichés that we first had for him and gave him laughter which is his form of therapy. <br /><b><br />The trauma-inducing event is a reminder of the infamous Delhi Uber case. It's interesting also how her sister reacts to it. </b><br />When I was narrating the script, people were like how could she be so disturbed just because of this? I found that a bit shocking. We are so numb to abuse that it has to be something as devastating as Nirbhaya case&nbsp; for you to believe that she is in the state that she is. We wanted to comment on how numb society is to violence and abuse. Mahek's sister can't understand the situation she is in. If it isn't fatal, then it's OK, get over it. The other comment was that we don't understand, address or accept mental illnesses. The use of mainstream Hindi item songs in the movie was used as a motif for all the negativity in our society; for inciting abuse and objectification of women. </p><p><b>Reviews and pieces mention how the film is reminiscent of Roman Polanski's Repulsion. Was that an inspiration?</b><br />Everything in horror tapers down to Alfred Hitchcock and Polanski, so you can't not go back to them. When I was thinking about the idea, I would constantly re-watch Polanski's The Tenant. I was more influenced by it than Repulsion. I was primarily influenced how Polanski in his early works would build paranoia in the house. I got my entire team, 30 of them, to watch it. <br />I was making this film because of four films - The Tenant, Repulsion, Goodnight Mommy and The Babadook. These were interesting films because they unfold in a closed environment and played on the claustrophobia and the growing insanity brewing in the space. Goodnight Mommy was something me and my DP studied a lot for how restrained the filmmaker's approach was. I was also blown away by the camerawork in It Follows. </p><p><b>It's a film that engages with the audience, requiring their constant attention. It also plays with them.</b><br />We were really hoping that it'd start a dialogue, especially the ending. We wanted people to constantly question and go back to the film. We wanted to keep it ambiguous in some places. We didn't want to fill the blanks for viewers. We wanted them to look deeper and find the connections. &nbsp;</p><p>It's a lofty idea that we expect the Indian audience to pay attention to movie. That's always the scary part. We let audience think that they are smarter than the movie. We were constantly holding back - let's put the camera on Radhika and let the audience process it. The idea was to feel it than show it. </p><p><b>Your surname appears on the apartment's number plate.</b> <br />(Laughs) It's the biggest blunder. I regret it till date. The production guy hadn't put a name. I was like just put any name. Then I noticed, they put mine. We didn't have any time to change it. So I let it go. <br /><b><br />Phobia is as much about trauma as it is about imagination.</b><br />True. That's the why she is an artist. That's why we have started and ended the way we have.&nbsp; It looks at the imagination of the artist and how dark it can get sometimes. Everything is an extension of her headspace. </p><p><b>What are you working on next?</b><br />There is a horror comedy which I have wanted to do for a while. But I'm so stoked by the experience of making Phobia that a large part of me wants to do another film like it - a shut-in environment with few characters. I want to do it in the hills somewhere. <br />Eros is eager to explore different phobias. One of my favourite shows growing up was Twilight Zone. One of its episodes was based on Richard Matheson's story Nightmare at 20,000 feet. It revolves around a man who has fear of flying.&nbsp; <br /></p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[Phobia director Pavan Kirpalani talks about leading lady Radhika Apte, Delhi's Nirbhaya case, his inspiration and much more.&nbsp; ]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>355821</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Phobia: Radhika Apte found so much truth in the character that even I couldn't find, says director Pavan Kirpalani ]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Phobia: Radhika Apte found so much truth in the character that even I couldn't find, says director Pavan Kirpalani ]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Phobia: Radhika Apte found so much truth in the character that even I couldn't find, says director Pavan Kirpalani ]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>1</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/phobia-radhika-apte-pavan-kirpalani-thriller/1/682456.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Phobia: Radhika Apte found so much truth in the character that even I couldn't find, says director Pavan Kirpalani ]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/phobia-story+fb_647_060116033557.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Phobia: Radhika Apte found so much truth in the character that even I couldn't find, says director Pavan Kirpalani ]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/phobia-story+fb_647_060116033557.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[phobia-radhika-apte-pavan-kirpalani-thriller]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Phobia: Radhika Apte found so much truth in the character that even I couldn't find, says director Pavan Kirpalani ]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[phobia, radhika apte, pavan kirpalani, pavan on phobia, phobia director ]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>