<story>
<id>682401</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>no</story_issue>
<select_magazine>0</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date/>
<bylines>
<byline>306</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464771734</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464771558</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1464773393</modifieddate>
<createdby>880</createdby>
<modifiedby>880</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city>285563</city>
</cities>
<categories><category>938502</category></categories><ordering>682401</ordering><primarycategory>938502</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/dsc_3080_559_060116024453.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt/>
<extra_large_title/>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/dsc_3080_305_060116024453.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt/>
<large_title/>
<mediumimage/>
<mediumimage_alt/>
<mediumimage_title/>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/dsc_3080_180_060116024453.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt/>
<smallimage_title/>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/dsc_3080_88_060116024453.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt/>
<extra_small_title/>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption/>
<mosimage>
<image/><caption/></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[Yu's latest phone Yunicorn was launched in India on Tuesday. In a 
hyper-competitive phone market of India, this one seems like a decent 
phone.]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>Yu's latest phone Yunicorn was launched in India on Tuesday. In a hyper-competitive phone market of India, this one seems like a decent phone. I did share some impressions of the phone yesterday and will take a better, more detailed look in the coming days. But if you are following the phone market in India closely, it won't be hard for you to see that the Yunicorn is one of the better phones in the market, but not the absolute best in its class.</p><p>It faces very tough competition. The RedMi Note 3 is cheaper and arguably has better hardware than the Yunicorn, although the Yunicorn looks better. The Moto G4 Plus, or even the Moto G Turbo, are slightly better phones compared to the Yunicorn. The Yunicorn even faces tough competition from the devices like the Lenovo ZUK Z1 and Micromax Canvas 6.</p><p class="review_also_read"><b>Also Read: </b> <a href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/technology/story/yu-yunicorn-full-specifications-top-features-india-price-and-everything-you-need-to-know/1/681505.html" title="">  Yu Yunicorn: Key specifications, top features, India price &amp; everything you need to know </a></p> <p>Online, we are sure that Yunicorn will find takers. It has an attractive design, price is decent, performance is good, screen is bright and punchy and software, at least the interface, is clean. But it is not going to cut through the competition the way Yu's Yureka or Yunique did. It is not going to be the king, similar to how some of the Motorola phones are. It is going to be up there, will be talked about and will be shortlisted by buyers but most likely it will be abandoned for some other phone in the end. But that is all in the world of online sales.</p><p>Offline, it is a different story. This is something that even Yu acknowledges as its founder Rahul Sharma believes that a majority of Yunicorn sale is going to come from offline stores. And understandably so.</p><p>In the last couple of years, India's phone market has seen emergence to channels -- offline and online. Online has become hyper-competitive with phones carrying prices that are mind-bogglingly low. Just see the Xiaomi RedMi Note 3. This is a phone that sells for Rs 9,999 and yet has almost the same core hardware that you get in the Xperia X, a phone launched just couple of days ago at a price of Rs 48,990. But the world of offline is different. The cost of doing offline retail is higher, the seller and company relations complex and the supply chain tougher to manage. Result? There is much less competition and prices have not yet reached that hyper-competitive that we see online.</p><p>In fact, for consumers the offline scene is sad. A colleague wanted to buy a Rs 10,000 phone a couple of days ago and he sought advice. All the phones that I thought were good buy for him were only available on e-retail sites. Even if a few of them were supposed to be in the offline shops the availability was non-existent. This person needed the phone urgently, immediately and from a brick-and-mortar shop. He ended up buying an Oppo phone, which was good but not the kind of device that could compete with the Redmis or Motos.</p><p class="review_also_read"><b>Also Read: </b> <a href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/technology/story/yu-yunicorn-quick-review-slick-design-is-the-cool-factor/1/681533.html" title="">

Yu Yunicorn quick review: Slick design is the cool factor
</a></p><p>This is where the Yu Yunicorn comes into the picture. At its price point -- the MRP is going to be Rs 13,499 for the offline shops -- the Yunicorn is a fantastic phone in its category. The tough competition that it faces in the online is not there in the offline stores.</p><p>It doesn't still make it all right for the offline consumers. They still get a rougher deal compared to the online buyers, who have better choices available to them, but it does help the scene somewhat. Compared to many of the other phones sold in brick-and-mortar shops, the Yunicorn has a much better hardware, better design, better performance and promises overall better experience. It has all the hallmarks of a winner if you compare it to other similarly-priced phones in the shop.</p><p><iframe src="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/technology/embedegallery_tech.jsp?gid=17642" mce_src="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/technology/embedegallery_tech.jsp?gid=17642" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" class="embedgalleryt" frameborder="0"></iframe>This is also a good opportunity. For the company the Yunicorn could be a best-seller in the world of offline. All it needs to do is to make sure that it is in stock in as many places as possible and especially in places where the Motos and the Redmis never reach.</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[Yu's latest phone Yunicorn was launched in India on Tuesday. In a 
hyper-competitive phone market of India, this one seems like a decent 
phone.]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>355528</tag>
<tag>275358</tag>
<tag>621751</tag>
<tag>734388</tag>
<tag>832343</tag>
<tag>266849</tag>
<tag>429981</tag>
<tag>227057</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Yu Yunicorn: Just another phone online, but superstar offline]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Yu Yunicorn is just another phone online, but can be a superstar offline]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Yu Yunicorn is just another phone online, but can be a superstar offline]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>1</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/technology/story/yu-yunicorn-is-just-another-phone-online-but-can-be-a-superstar-offline/1/682401.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Yu Yunicorn: Just another phone online, but superstar offline]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/dsc_3080_559_060116024453.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Yu Yunicorn: Just another phone online, but superstar offline]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/dsc_3080_559_060116024453.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[yu-yunicorn-is-just-another-phone-online-but-can-be-a-superstar-offline]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Yu Yunicorn: Just another phone online, but superstar offline]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[yu yunicorn, yu, yunicorn launch, yunicorn price, yunicorn specs, yureka, yunique, rahul sharma]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>