<story>
<id>683194</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>no</story_issue>
<select_magazine>0</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date/>
<bylines>
<byline>290</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464849096</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464849053</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1464851365</modifieddate>
<createdby>860</createdby>
<modifiedby>860</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city>285563</city>
</cities>
<categories><category>279970</category><category>280038</category><category>280225</category><category>279986</category><category>280477</category></categories><ordering>683194</ordering><primarycategory>280477</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/mumbai---facebook-and-storysize_647_060216122958.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt><![CDATA[Mumbai the best city?]]></extra_large_alt>
<extra_large_title><![CDATA[Mumbai the best city?]]></extra_large_title>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/mumbai---facebook-and-storysize_305_060216122958.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt><![CDATA[Mumbai the best city?]]></large_alt>
<large_title><![CDATA[Mumbai the best city?]]></large_title>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/mumbai---facebook-and-storysize_300_060216122958.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt><![CDATA[Mumbai the best city?]]></mediumimage_alt>
<mediumimage_title><![CDATA[Mumbai the best city?]]></mediumimage_title>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/mumbai---facebook-and-storysize_180_060216122958.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt><![CDATA[Mumbai the best city?]]></smallimage_alt>
<smallimage_title><![CDATA[Mumbai the best city?]]></smallimage_title>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/mumbai---facebook-and-storysize_88_060216122958.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt><![CDATA[Mumbai the best city?]]></extra_small_alt>
<extra_small_title><![CDATA[Mumbai the best city?]]></extra_small_title>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption><![CDATA[Photo: Inverted Umbrella Photography]]></kicker_image_caption>
<mosimage>
<image/><caption/></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[Arpan De, a Quora user, gives a detailed answer to a Quora thread that asked why are people still living in Mumbai. His answer is becoming viral on social media despite the initial thread being deleted. <br />]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>Mumbai monsoons or Delhi winters? Mumbai's Gateway of India or Delhi's India Gate? Mumbai's 'Paani Puri' or Delhi's 'Gol Gappe'? Mumbai's pace or Delhi's vastness? </p><p>The perennial discussion to find the best city in India to live in has been answered by logic and reason only to find that it is Hyderabad, and neither Delhi nor Mumbai. But 'which city is the best' question always manages to create a war-like atmosphere between people from these two cities. Such is their love for the cities that grew on them. </p><p>It is also not often when you see people from Banglore, Hyderabad, Pune, Chennai, Chandigarh or Cochin talk about their cities the way people from Delhi and Mumbai do. </p><p>Arpan Kumar De, a Quora user, nailed it when he explained why he loves Mumbai under a thread that asked <a target="_blank" href="https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-thing-about-Mumbai" mce_href="https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-thing-about-Mumbai">"what is the best thing about Mumbai?"&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;</a> </p><p><b>Here's what he wrote: </b></p><p>"I took a Cab from Lower Parel to Worli. The fare was Rs 67. Since I was coming from Bangalore, I gave Rs 100 to the cab driver and started walking towards my office. The driver called me back. He gave me Rs 30 back. I started walking again. He called me back again and gave me 3 bucks back.</p><p><b>This is why I love Mumbai.</b></p><p>It was Holi Morning. I had to come to office. My cab fare was again 70 bucks. The driver did not have change. He went ahead and bought a Vada (a typical Mumbai snack) worth Rs 10 and returned me the balance. When I was walking away. The driver took his plate of Vada, offered me half of them. "Boss, ek lelo, Holi hai!"</p><p><b>This is why I love Mumbai.</b></p><p>It was my first night out on Marine Drive. The rainy days were about to start. I sat on the rocks with my friend. And suddenly it started raining. Ohh, I can't even start to tell you how much people love the first rain here. It was 3 AM and I saw a group of 3 girls, all dressed up in their short LBDs, probably coming back after a party. They got out of their car and started drenching and dancing in the rain. And no, not a single guy catcalled them.</p><p><b>This is why I love Mumbai.</b></p><p>Just on the opposite side of the road, where the girls were dancing, sat an old Muslim couple. They were completely wet. Yet they sat there enjoying the view of the sea, holding hands. They were in their 60s.</p><p><b>This is why I love Mumbai.</b></p><p>Every Time I took the local train, I realized there is always a place for another person. It always looked impossible from the outside to get in. But somehow "we" always used to fit in those small coaches.</p><p><b>That is why I loved Mumbai.</b></p><p>Every time it rains here, I wonder if the city is coming to a stop. It literally is like hell breaking down. I saw platform being overflown by rainwater. Then when I reached my office, I saw everyone came to work. People somehow manage to live here, irrespective of anything. The best part is that they do it with a smile.</p><p><b>That is why I loved Mumbai.</b></p><p>There used to be a couple, just below my first apartment, on the street. They did not have a place to stay. I used to take the cab for my office right in front of their tent. I saw the old guy reading his news paper, sipping tea and I saw his wife combing hair of one of the stray dogs. I never saw them sad in their happy little home. The wife always wore a little lilly on her hair.</p><p><b>That is why I loved Mumbai.<br /></b><br />I was at Dadar Station. It was 9 in the morning, one of the busiest hours. I saw a couple smooching on the platform. They were probably saying a 'goodbye' to each other. What I could figure was that the girl was moving to another city. And then I realized I am one of the very few people watching. Everyone else is busy about their own train.</p><p><b>That is why I loved Mumbai.</b></p><p>The city is an infrastructural mess. The air is so polluted at times I could not see the top of my own building. The place is so over crowded that there is probably more space in a first world country's prison than in Mumbai. Yet, I saw a Punjabi 26-year-old guy, dressed in formals, singing his heart out while coming back from office on a bike. I saw a Jaguar stuck in the same traffic light. And they coexisted happily, side by side.</p><p><b>That is what Mumbai is for you "naked, sheer raw acceptance of truth."</b></p><p>I saw thousands of small homes. Homes of the size of washrooms of my place in Kolkata. Yet, I never saw a permanent sad face in any of those windows. People ran, people fought, people struggled for their dreams. "One does not live in Mumbai, one struggles in Mumbai." Mumbai is still the city of dreams. Mumbai can give you respect, happiness, irrespective of your caste, creed, gender and economical status. </p><p>Like tea stall owner just outside my office puts it... "Ambani bhi petrol pump pe petrol deta tha.. to hum konsi maal hai?"</p><p><b>And that my friend is the ultimate reason why I will always love Mumbai."</b></p><p><br />Another Quora user, Parina Muchhala, thinks "the sense of living in the most happening Indian city," is what she loves the most about Mumbai. There are others who have posted photos of the picturesque sunsets by the sea as seen from Mumbai, the delicious, cheap options to binge on, and a user Aditya Nanda declares it's the people - Mumbaikars - that make the city a haven. <br /><b><br />Delhi, are you listening? </b><br /></p><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[Arpan De, a Quora user, gives a detailed answer to a Quora thread that asked why are people still living in Mumbai. His answer is becoming viral on social media despite the initial thread being deleted. <br />]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>356033</tag>
<tag>222629</tag>
<tag>222866</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Is Mumbai the best Indian city to live in? Yes, says this Quora thread]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Is Mumbai the best Indian city to live in? Yes, says this Quora thread]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Is Mumbai the best Indian city to live in? Yes, says this Quora thread]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>1</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/mumbai-best-indian-city-to-live-in-quora-thread-answers/1/683194.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Is Mumbai the best Indian city to live in? Yes, says this Quora thread]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/mumbai---facebook-and-storysize_647_060216122958.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Is Mumbai the best Indian city to live in? Yes, says this Quora thread]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/mumbai---facebook-and-storysize_647_060216122958.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[mumbai-best-indian-city-to-live-in-quora-thread-answers]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Is Mumbai the best Indian city to live in? Yes, says this Quora thread]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[Quora, Delhi vs Mumbai, Best Indian City, Viral Post]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>