<story>
<id>683233</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>no</story_issue>
<select_magazine>0</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date/>
<bylines>
<byline>602</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464856449</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464856068</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1464862224</modifieddate>
<createdby>839</createdby>
<modifiedby>839</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city>285563</city>
</cities>
<categories><category>938655</category><category>938706</category><category>938579</category><category>938754</category></categories><ordering>683300</ordering><primarycategory>938655</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/brezza_story_647_060216020409.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt><![CDATA[Vitara Brezza vs TUV300 vs EcoSport]]></extra_large_alt>
<extra_large_title><![CDATA[Vitara Brezza vs TUV300 vs EcoSport]]></extra_large_title>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/brezza_story_305_060216020409.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt><![CDATA[Vitara Brezza vs TUV300 vs EcoSport]]></large_alt>
<large_title><![CDATA[Vitara Brezza vs TUV300 vs EcoSport]]></large_title>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/brezza_story_300_060216020409.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt><![CDATA[Vitara Brezza vs TUV300 vs EcoSport]]></mediumimage_alt>
<mediumimage_title><![CDATA[Vitara Brezza vs TUV300 vs EcoSport]]></mediumimage_title>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/brezza_story_180_060216020409.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt><![CDATA[Vitara Brezza vs TUV300 vs EcoSport]]></smallimage_alt>
<smallimage_title><![CDATA[Vitara Brezza vs TUV300 vs EcoSport]]></smallimage_title>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/brezza_story_88_060216020409.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt><![CDATA[Vitara Brezza vs TUV300 vs EcoSport]]></extra_small_alt>
<extra_small_title><![CDATA[Vitara Brezza vs TUV300 vs EcoSport]]></extra_small_title>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption><![CDATA[The Brezza is based on Suzuki’s global c-platform and is a monocoque like the ecosport. the tuv 300 is based on a ladder frame chassis and at the same time is RWD. (Photo: Nishant Jhamb)]]></kicker_image_caption>
<mosimage>
<image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/brezza-vs-tuv300_060216015232.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[The Brezza is based on Suzuki’s global c-platform and is a monocoque like the ecosport. the tuv 300 is based on a ladder frame chassis and at the same time is RWD. (Photo: Nishant Jhamb)]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/vitara-brezza-interior_060216014138.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[The Brezza comes with a simple dash design. Controls are placed in usual positions and this makes it easy to use. (Photo: Nishant Jhamb)]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/tuv300-interior_060216014212.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[The TUV 300 comes with a simple dash design. Controls are placed in usual positions and this makes it easy to use. (Photo: Nishant Jhamb)]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/ecosport-interior_060216014157.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[The EcoSport has a snazzy dash and it does take time to get used to the stylish setup. (Photo: Nishant Jhamb)]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/engine_060216015232.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[1. The Vitara Brezza comes with the tried and tested 1.3-litre diesel engine. Also Maruti-Suzuki has decided to launch only diesel variants for the Brezza. 2. The EcoSport has the largest engine here, a 1.5-litre oil burner. Thanks to it being compact, the power-to- weight ratio is a rather respectible 71bhp/tonne.  3. The TUV 300 gets a 3-cylinder motor displacing 1.5-litres. However it has to lug a substantial kerb weight which affects performance. (Photo: Nishant Jhamb)]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/brezza-vs-ecosport_060216015232.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[The ecosport is the fastest to 100kmph and at the same time the most powerful followed by the brezza and the tuv 300 respectively. (Photo: Nishant Jhamb)]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/brezza-vs-tuv300-vs-ecosport-infotainment_060216015232.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[1. The unit on the Brezza offers Apple CarPlay. 2. TUV does not offer a touchscreen. 3.The EcoSport has a smart dash design. 4. The instrument panel on the Brezza is the funkiest of them all and comes with five changeable colours. 5. The TUV info display also includes a gear position indicator. 6. Not much glitz but yet attractive is the EcoSport’s instrument panel. (Photo: Nishant Jhamb)]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/wheels_060216015232.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[1. Brezza rides on 215/60 R16 Apollo Alnac 4G tyres. Alloys look smart as well and fills up the wheel wells. 2. The TUV300 uses Ceat Czar tyres. The tyre size is 215/75 R15. The wheel wells still look empty though. 3. The Ford EcoSport rides on 205/60 R16 Goodyear Assurance tyres and overall wheel-package looks good. (Photo: Nishant Jhamb)]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/points_060216015232.jpg]]></image><caption/><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/vitara-brezza-rear_060216014138.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[Brezza: The Brezza is the only one here which does not get a tailgate-mounted spare. The Brezza is also surprisingly spacious especially at the back. Headroom at 980mm is best-in-class. (Photo: Nishant Jhamb)]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/tuv300-rear_060216014212.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[TUV300: The TUV comes with a side-mounted tailgate which also houses the spare. The TUV feels a lot more spacious inside. Seats are large and flat and offer little support at the back. (Photo: Nishant Jhamb)]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/ecosport-rear_060216014157.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[EcoSport: The EcoSport still looks smart with the tailgate mounted spare. Space especially at the back is not the EcoSport’s forte. There is limited knee and headroom with comfortable space only for two. (Photo: Nishant Jhamb)]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/brezza-vs-tuv300-vs-ecosport-side_060216015232.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[Vitara Brezza vs TUV300 vs EcoSport. (Photo: Nishant Jhamb)]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/evaluation-points-1_060216015232.jpg]]></image><caption/><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/evaluation-points-2_060216015232.jpg]]></image><caption/><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/final-points_060216015232.jpg]]></image><caption/></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[After a rather long wait, Maruti-Suzuki has launched the Vitara Brezza. However the Mahindra TUV 300 and the Ford EcoSport are there to ensure that the Brezza does not get everything easily]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>In the recent past, the compact SUV invasion has gathered quite a bit of steam. Waiting lists for every compact SUV launched in India have gone through the roof and in some cases things get ugly with waiting lists stretching as long as nine months! </p><p>So in such a lucrative market, it is lethal not to have one in the portfolio. Ford was one of the manufacturers who started it all with the EcoSport, which too had a massive waiting list. Then Mahindra joined the party with the big and butch TUV 300 (it again has a waiting list) and now comes the Maruti-Suzuki Vitara Brezza (which too has a big waiting list). But the big question is that whether you should buy the new Brezza or go in for the TUV or the EcoSport. Let us help you in making this decision. {mosimage}</p><p>The Maruti-Suzuki Vitara Brezza is the newest kid on the block. It boasts of a new age design and combines compactness and style together. The Brezza is based on Suzuki's Global C-platform which also serves the European Grand Vitara. So with an SUV in its genes, the Brezza looks and feels proper. {mosimage}</p><p>The front end is bold complete with a chrome grille and sleek projector headlamps. In profile the Brezza looks good thanks to the blacked out pillars which envisage a floating roof design. At the back too, the design is very proportionate and overall thanks to the short overhangs, the Brezza does look like a proper SUV.{mosimage}</p><p>{mosimage} The TUV300 boasts of a brand new design. Big and boxy is how I would like to refer to it. But at the same time it does have a brutish charm to it much like one would expect from a full-blown SUV. The front end gets a large five slat grille flanked by large headlamps. The headlamps also offer static cornering lamps which light up at corners and are a truly handy feature. Viewed from the sides, the TUV has rather slab sides. There aren't many curves to caress but what is impressive is the lack of overhangs. </p><p>{mosimage} At the back, the centre of attraction is the tailgate mounted spare wheel. But what can really transform the look of the TUV is the accessory package offered by Mahindra. Roof lights, flared wheel arches, a bull bar, Mahindra has something for everyone and many of the TUVs we have spotted on the roads sport many of these accessories and the SUV does look very different. </p><p>The Ford EcoSport also has a rather sporty design. The company has recently given it a minor upgrade and added features which make it ready for the competition. The bold grille and sleek headlamps have made the EcoSport a design icon. In profile it is a right mix of flared arches and also prominent lines. The EcoSport also comes with a tailgate mounted spare and we still like the small button incorporated within the tail lamp to open the boot. {mosimage}</p><p>When we come to the hard figures and facts of size there is much that differentiates these three compact SUVs. Dimensions reveal that the TUV is the largest of the lot. It is the tallest and also the widest at 1,839mm and 1,835mm. It also boasts of the longest wheelbase at 2,680mm. The EcoSport's overall length at 3,999mm is the longest, which is surprising. The other big differentiator is the fact the TUV is based on a ladder-frame chassis while the other two are monocoque. Also the TUV is a rear-wheel drive while the other two are front-wheel drives. </p><p>{mosimage} The interiors of the Brezza are designed to suit its snazzy exteriors. Although major components are brand new, the Brezza feels surprisingly familiar. There are two glove compartments and next to these sits the large touch screen display which also offers sat nav and Apple CarPlay. Right below the screen sits the control panel for the climate control system. The buttons are large and rather easy to use. The steering is from the Maruti-Suzuki parts bin and also incorporates controls for audio, Bluetooth and cruise control. </p><p>{mosimage}The instrument panel is a twin pod affair and at the same time offers up to five display colour options. When it comes to space the Brezza sure feels compact. However the seats are comfortable for both short hops and long distance driving. We also liked the driving position which is high much like what should be in a SUV. At the back the Brezza does not feel as spacious as the TUV much because of the low roofline. But on paper it is at par. Getting into the cabin of the TUV requires one to utilise the side step. Once in, the seat feels large and comfortable. Up ahead there is a smart looking two-tone dash. The piano black centre console looks good too and houses the infotainment system. </p><p>{mosimage} The instrument panel is a twin pod affair with a digital read out for fuel, temperature and trip in the middle. The view around is also clear and the edges of the bonnet are visible too. The back seat is a bit flat but there is ample room all around. The boot of the TUV comes with two foldable jump seats. The low floor aids space and two adults can be "shoved" in for short rides. However, we must add here that the two seats at the back do not offer seat belts and hence Mahindra calls it a 5+2 arrangement. Getting into the EcoSport is a much easier affair thanks to the clever design. The seats are more compact units and offer a lot more support and this is especially the case in context of the front bucket seats. </p><p>The EcoSport thereafter gets a snazzier dash design. It also comes with its very own display which sits atop the dash and a plethora of buttons which do take time to get used to. Ford has also added a lot more features like automatic wipers and an upgraded Sync system.{mosimage}</p><p>The Brezza comes with the tried and tested 1.3-litre diesel engine which generates 90bhp and ensures that the Brezza feels sprightly to drive. There is lag till the 1,800rpm range after which the turbo is ready to unleash power and from then on the Brezza gathers speed rapidly. This also means that in case you have not downshifted and let the rpm drop below 1,800rpm progress is not as rapid. The only solution is to drop down a gear and allow the revs to rise and then you are good to go. However on the highway it is not much of a bother as speeds are relatively higher and this means that this kind of situation will be rare. {mosimage}</p><p>The TUV comes with a 1.5-litre three-cylinder oil burner, which does emit the standard diesel crackle at start-up. But it does settle down quick. The gearbox feels a bit sticky though it slots in easy. Take off from standstill is adequate and it gets up to speeds with relative ease. The other thing which impressed us was the seamless power delivery. It does not come as a lump and is very linear. Therefore no turbo lag is felt. {mosimage}</p><p>There is also loads of torque which kicks in at lower revs and that eliminates the need to downshift on a regular basis. Even when in top gear just a dab on the throttle ensures a quick speed up. The TUV also boasts of a rather good NVH package. At 100kmph, the engine is barely audible inside the cabin. At around 120kmph is when you can hear it clearly.{mosimage}</p><p>The EcoSport feels lively from the word go. It is more powerful and light as well, by as much as 300kg when compared to the TUV. Therefore, in the sprint to 100kmph, the Ford outpaces the TUV and the Brezza too. It is also more car-like to drive. The engine feels slightly more refined and the gearbox is slicker too. </p><p>{mosimage}The Brezza and EcoSport are also better handlers. The stiff setups ensure that both these SUVs are fun to drive, even up to your favourite hill station. The TUV on the other hand has a soft setup which works wonders at slower speeds by absorbing most ruts and bumps but displays prominent body roll on the go. </p><p>Though much to the Mahindra's advantage is the feeling of being able to go anywhere without breaking something. Last but not the least, we come to the steering setups. The Brezza comes with a responsive steering which makes driving fun. The TUV though feels slightly heavy at most times, especially around the city. The best of the lot is surely the EcoSport.{mosimage}</p><p>&nbsp;</p><h2><b>Verdict</b></h2><br />The last time we compared the TUV and the EcoSport, the EcoSport lost out because of overall purchase cost. But now after the Vitara Brezza was launched, Ford slashed prices and this has given it that edge where it pips the TUV300. <p>The EcoSport is for those who want a compact SUV&nbsp; which offers good ride and handling. The TUV300 on the other hand is the one to have if you desire lots of space and of course two additional seats. </p><p>But the winner of our test is the new Vitara Brezza. Maruti-Suzuki has taken its own time to come up with a compact SUV but they have got it spot on. It is reasonably spacious and offers a good blend of performance and efficiency too.</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[After a rather long wait, Maruti-Suzuki has launched the Vitara Brezza. However the Mahindra TUV 300 and the Ford EcoSport are there to ensure that the Brezza does not get everything easily]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>223453</tag>
<tag>234229</tag>
<tag>234532</tag>
<tag>295763</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Comparison: Vitara Brezza vs TUV300 vs EcoSport]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Comparison: Vitara Brezza vs TUV300 vs EcoSport]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Comparison: Vitara Brezza vs TUV300 vs EcoSport]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>37</like>
<dislike>12</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/auto/story/maruti-suzuki-vitara-brezza-vs-ford-ecosport-vs-mahindra-tuv300-comparison/1/683233.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Comparison: Vitara Brezza vs TUV300 vs EcoSport]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/brezza_story_647_060216020409.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Comparison: Vitara Brezza vs TUV300 vs EcoSport]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/brezza_story_647_060216020409.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>1</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>1</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[maruti-suzuki-vitara-brezza-vs-ford-ecosport-vs-mahindra-tuv300-comparison]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Comparison: Vitara Brezza vs TUV300 vs EcoSport]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[News, Auto News, Vitara Brezza vs EcoSport vs TUV300, Maruti Vitara Brezza, Ford EcoSport, Mahindra TUV300]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>