<story>
<id>683344</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>no</story_issue>
<select_magazine>0</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date/>
<bylines>
<byline>1258</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464892200</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464876926</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1464937304</modifieddate>
<createdby>886</createdby>
<modifiedby>707</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city/>
</cities>
<categories><category>938670</category><category>279970</category><category>280038</category><category>280225</category></categories><ordering>683283</ordering><primarycategory>938670</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/story_647_060216075210.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt><![CDATA[Pacman staring down the camera at Ranthambore National Park. Picture courtesy: Bhavneet S Aurora]]></extra_large_alt>
<extra_large_title><![CDATA[Pacman staring down the camera at Ranthambore National Park. Picture courtesy: Bhavneet S Aurora]]></extra_large_title>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/story_305_060216075210.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt><![CDATA[Pacman staring down the camera at Ranthambore National Park. Picture courtesy: Bhavneet S Aurora]]></large_alt>
<large_title><![CDATA[Pacman staring down the camera at Ranthambore National Park. Picture courtesy: Bhavneet S Aurora]]></large_title>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/story_300_060216075210.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt><![CDATA[Pacman staring down the camera at Ranthambore National Park. Picture courtesy: Bhavneet S Aurora]]></mediumimage_alt>
<mediumimage_title><![CDATA[Pacman staring down the camera at Ranthambore National Park. Picture courtesy: Bhavneet S Aurora]]></mediumimage_title>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/story_180_060216075210.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt><![CDATA[Pacman staring down the camera at Ranthambore National Park. Picture courtesy: Bhavneet S Aurora]]></smallimage_alt>
<smallimage_title><![CDATA[Pacman staring down the camera at Ranthambore National Park. Picture courtesy: Bhavneet S Aurora]]></smallimage_title>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/story_88_060216075210.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt><![CDATA[Pacman staring down the camera at Ranthambore National Park. Picture courtesy: Bhavneet S Aurora]]></extra_small_alt>
<extra_small_title><![CDATA[Pacman staring down the camera at Ranthambore National Park. Picture courtesy: Bhavneet S Aurora]]></extra_small_title>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption><![CDATA[Pacman staring down the camera at Ranthambore National Park. Picture courtesy: Bhavneet S Aurora]]></kicker_image_caption>
<mosimage>
<image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/mos-1_060216075258.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[Picture courtesy: Bhavneet S Aurora]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/mos-6_060216075258.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[Picture courtesy: Bhavneet S Aurora]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/mos-3_060216075258.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[T60 waiting for her third cub to cross the road. Note the way she is standing and looking at the camera and her ears. Her left ear is tuned to her two cubs who have already crossed the road, her right ear is listening for her third cub while she is looking at the assortment of vehicles standing there as if warning the people to not come any closer. Picture courtesy: Bhavneet S Aurora]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/mos-2_060216075258.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[Tigress Lightening. She walked past the jeep within touching distance. Picture courtesy: Bhavneet S Aurora]]></caption><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/mos-5_060216075258.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[An adult and a juvenile Collared Scops Owl. Picture courtesy: Bhavneet S Aurora]]></caption></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[Here's why a summer trip to Rajasthan's Ranthambore National Park turned out to be one of the most amazing travel memories of my life.]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>Every once in a lifetime you embark on a journey that will remain with you forever. For some, it's a trip to the hills and for others it's going deep sea diving. I've been to the hills and I've been to the sea, but the journey that shall remain with me forever is the trip to tiger country--the Ranthambore National Park.</p><p>For us, it was the only choice left. We'd been to the hills, the sea was too far away, plus it was--and still is--too damn hot outside. With electricity playing hooky in Gurgaon, we asked the kids if they wanted to go on a short trip to Ranthambore which would possibly be warmer than Gurgaon. Their reply, "It's hot here, it's hot there, might as well go see tigers than sit around waiting for electricity to come", clinched it for us. A little bit of asking around put me in touch with tigerwalah.com's Anurag Sharma. A phone call to him and we were all set up. All we needed to do was turn up and bring our own booze.</p><p><b>The journey</b><br />So, camera ready, bags packed, early on a Sunday morning, we began our six-hour, 356km drive to Ranthambore. The drive is a beautiful one considering that once you cross Manesar, the roads are wide and beautiful and in some parts, quite scenic. The route we took was: Bhiwadi-Alwar bypass-Sikandra-Dausa-Sawai Madhopur.</p><p>If after reading this you are planning to go to Ranthambore, here's a pointer: the last decent place to eat before Sawai Madhopur is Bhiwadi where you have all the major fast food joints. After that all you'll get are signboards pointing to some dhaba or the other. I would suggest carrying refreshments and munchies with you if you are driving down to Ranthambore.</p><p>With two kids in the car, we made a couple of pit stops for sundry reasons and finally reached around 2.30pm. Perhaps the most beautiful stretch of the route is from Manoharpur to Dausa which is a 40-odd-km road which cuts through the Aravali Hills and barely has any traffic so you can actually put the pedal to the metal and let the car zip along while you listen to your favourite music. <br />The first day we decided to rest and laze around. Our host, Anurag had already checked on tigers and which of the 10 zones in the sanctuary were reporting sightings. So he booked us on a canter for Zone 2 for the next day.</p><p><b>An encounter with Pacman, the lazy tiger</b><br />Now, Zone 2 is a zone given to little water and more uphill and downhill--basically a bumpy track in a bumpy vehicle. Barely two minutes into the zone and we spotted our first tiger. Our guide told us that his name was Pacman. The crown prince that Pacman is, he had his belly full and was in the mood to sleep. So, he lumbered out of the waterhole, grunting all the while but alert to his surroundings and slowly, majestically made his way to a nearby thicket where he went off to sleep. Leaving him sleeping, we headed deeper into the zone, but were disappointed. Of the 60-plus tigers in the sanctuary, we had seen one, and that too was a tiger that had the reputation of being one of the laziest tigers around. {mosimage}&nbsp;</p><p>The rest of the safari consisted of spotting a baby crocodile, an army of langurs--or Bandar log, as my daughter put it--a herd of Sambhar and Spotted deer. On the way back from deep inside the zone, we ran into our friend Pacman again--and he was making his way to another watering hole. Pacman passed within 10 feet of our canter. Slowly, he made his way past us and slinked into the undergrowth. That was the last we saw of any tiger in that safari. We saw Pacman again the next day and true to his reputation, he had found himself a comfortable spot under a tree by the lake and was sleeping. <b>Also read: <a href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/machli-world-oldest-tigress-ranthambore-tiger-wildlife-travel/1/682539.html" mce_href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/machli-world-oldest-tigress-ranthambore-tiger-wildlife-travel/1/682539.html">Machli tales: The 20-year-old tigress from Ranthambore is the world's most photographed</a></b>  </p><p>Time for the evening safari and we were told that our booking is again for zone 2. We were disappointed but our tigerwalah friend assured us of a fantastic sighting. So, still doubtful, we got into the canter with a bunch of men. Our canter driver had probably seen some F1 races an hour before the drive began and was in just that mood. We bumped and flew all over the canter. At one point, I even asked the accompanying guide to ask the driver to go slow. His reply, "Sa'ab, jungle hai, yahan dheere bhi aise hi hota hai." So, we resigned ourselves to our bumpy ride and held on for dear life. Ten minutes later, on the very edge of the path the driver stood up on the brakes and brought the canter to a standstill. {mosimage}&nbsp; <br /></p><p>"Tiger, wahan neeche. (Tiger. Down below.)" All of us peered into the murky depths of a water drain and sure enough, our friend from the morning, Pacman was dozing away peacefully. Only his head was out of the water, the rest of him was partially submerged. Five minutes later, without warning, our driver decided he'd had enough and started the canter and took off. That was the day I realised that I have bones in places which could possibly hurt. For the next 30 minutes, he drove through the forest as if he was being chased by an angry and hungry tiger. Towards the end of zone 2, he slowed down, we breathed deep and then he let the canter inch ahead slowly and sure enough, there on our left was a tigress, T60. She was marking her territory and was a little fretful. When she disappeared into the undergrowth, our canter looped around the bushes and headed in the other direction and stopped. The guide told us that the "tigress will cross the road in front of our canter."</p><p>A minute passed, no tigress. Another five minutes passed, no tigress. I decided I'd had enough of waiting and thought I would shoot something else. I spotted a paradise flycatcher and began training my camera on that when I spotted some movement in the bottom right corner. Focussing on that area, I spotted the tigress heading our way, but slowly. Beside her were three young cubs, all sprightly and jumping around like naughty children, but within eyesight from the tigress. {mosimage}&nbsp; <br /></p><p>In Ranthambore, they say spotting a tigress with cubs is very difficult. And were we lucky! The tigress and her three cubs posed happily for nearly half an hour with us shutterbugs shooting away to glory capturing every moment the tigress and her cubs were visible.</p><p>The tigress sat there in all her glory, surrounded by her cubs, looking at our canter and the 20-odd jeeps that were lined up behind us. Then she led her cubs towards us and veered off to the right. Circling around us, she came out right where the guide had told us she would. The cubs followed suit and quickly crossed over to the other side and disappeared into the thicket. After that we only saw flashes of bright orange as the four made their way away from us.</p><p>Happy with the sighting, we returned to our resort and discussed the tigress and her cubs and the lazy Pacman.</p><p><b>A tale of Ranthambore's three tiger siblings</b><br />The next morning, we decided to sleep in and take the evening safari. Our host had organised a jeep for us and his own guide to take us into Zone 3, where canters aren't allowed. About 15 minutes into the safari, our guide, Arvind, told us that we were heading to tigress Arrowhead and Lightening zone. <br /></p><p>A word about these two tigresses: Arrowhead, Lightening and Pacman are siblings. Arrowhead and Lightening are the two fierce ones from the same litter and can't stand the sight of each other. As the story goes, their mother, T19 or Krishna, was quite frustrated at the never-ending fights between Arrowhead and Lightening. Arrowhead broke away from the family and went independent quite early. Lightening followed suit a little later. Pacman, the laziest of the three is a pampered mama's boy and usually wanders off into either Arrowhead or Lightening's zones and is often reported to freeload off them. {mosimage}&nbsp; </p><p>Back to our safari. So there we were in Zone 3 and our guide told us to wait. Sure enough, out of the tall grass on the left a blaze of dark yellow flashed out on to the road and with slow, measured steps and head low tigress Lightening began walking towards us. But before she could reach us, she turned and made her way down the hill. Our driver decided he wanted to place us in the best spot possible for photos and raced ahead of the remaining gypsies. Suffice to say that 15 minutes later, Lightening had once again walked towards us and at the last moment, she had turned a little and had passed within touching distance of our jeep. {mosimage}&nbsp; <br /></p><p>That was the last of our sightings of Lightening. Apparently, she crossed over into Arrowhead's zone and went and lay down near a cactus thicket which the guide said was her "bedroom".</p><p>That was the end of our tiger sightings. The next morning, we retraced our steps and headed back to Gurgaon. </p><p><b>Good to know </b><br /></p><p><b>Distance from Delhi: </b>380km.<br /><b>Best time to visit: </b>November to May for tiger sightings. Monsoon season the sanctuary is closed.<br /><b>Things to do: </b>Ranthambore National Park is an ideal place for wildlife photography. A walk up to the Ranthambore Fort will give you a picturesque view of the park. The 10th century fort stands 700 ft high atop a hill. Relax!<br /><b>Must-visit:</b> The Trinetra Ganesha Temple inside Ranthambore National Park.<br /><b>Shop:</b> Dastkar is a stone's throw away from the sanctuary.</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[Here's why a summer trip to Rajasthan's Ranthambore National Park turned out to be one of the most amazing travel memories of my life.]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>225036</tag>
<tag>229652</tag>
<tag>224168</tag>
<tag>222581</tag>
<tag>225879</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Pages from an affair with the Ranthambore tigers]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Pages from an affair with the Ranthambore tigers]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Pages from an affair with the Ranthambore tigers]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>0</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/ranthambore-national-park-tiger-travel-india-rajasthan-lifetr/1/683344.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>0</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>0</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position/>
<audio_url/>
<animated_image_position/>
<animated_image/>
<map_embed_code_position/>
<map_embed_code/>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position/>
<social_embed_code/>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Pages from an affair with the Ranthambore tigers]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/story_647_060216075210.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Pages from an affair with the Ranthambore tigers]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/story_647_060216075210.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents><relatedcontent type="text">605110</relatedcontent><relatedcontent type="text">682539</relatedcontent><relatedcontent type="text">616856</relatedcontent><relatedcontent type="text">648023</relatedcontent></relatedcontents>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[ranthambore-national-park-tiger-travel-india-rajasthan-lifetr]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Pages from an affair with the Ranthambore tigers]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[Ranthambore National Park,Tiger,Travel,India,Rajasthan,Tourism,Lifetr]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>