<story>
<id>683393</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>no</story_issue>
<select_magazine>0</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date/>
<bylines>
<byline>221</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464921954</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464921810</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1464951952</modifieddate>
<createdby>704</createdby>
<modifiedby>703</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city>285857</city>
</cities>
<categories><category>279970</category><category>280038</category><category>280225</category><category>279986</category><category>279631</category><category>280185</category><category>279607</category></categories><ordering>683396</ordering><primarycategory>279607</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/ammunition-story_647_060316102707.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt><![CDATA[(Photo: Jugal R Purohit)]]></extra_large_alt>
<extra_large_title><![CDATA[(Photo: Jugal R Purohit)]]></extra_large_title>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/ammunition-story_305_060316102707.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt><![CDATA[(Photo: Jugal R Purohit)]]></large_alt>
<large_title><![CDATA[(Photo: Jugal R Purohit)]]></large_title>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/ammunition-story_300x350_060316102707.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt><![CDATA[(Photo: Jugal R Purohit)]]></mediumimage_alt>
<mediumimage_title><![CDATA[(Photo: Jugal R Purohit)]]></mediumimage_title>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/ammunition-story_180_060316102707.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt><![CDATA[(Photo: Jugal R Purohit)]]></smallimage_alt>
<smallimage_title><![CDATA[(Photo: Jugal R Purohit)]]></smallimage_title>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/ammunition-story_88_060316102707.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt><![CDATA[(Photo: Jugal R Purohit)]]></extra_small_alt>
<extra_small_title><![CDATA[(Photo: Jugal R Purohit)]]></extra_small_title>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption/>
<mosimage>
<image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/ammunition1-moss_060316102950.jpg]]></image><caption><![CDATA[(Photo: Jugal R Purohit)]]></caption></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[Villagers cite colourful 'first hand' accounts of having seen 'night 
turn into day from the explosion', felt the earth shake, buildings 
kilometres away vibrate and heard the roar of self-made anti tank mines 
detonate.]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>On a white board inside the administrative block was a neatly drawn line in black ink. It segregated officers 'Posted In' from those 'Posted Out'. The latter, featuring Colonel Ghaninder Singh, Lt Col RS Pawar and Major K Manoj Kumar, consisted of those who'd received their new orders and were wrapping up. However, 'wrapping up' meant little when in the early hours of Tuesday a Defence Security Corps (DSC) jawan reported a fire in a ammunition-holding shed located near the southern boundary of the 'Delta' block. It was 1:10 am when the trio, the installation's Deputy Commandant, Administrative Officer and Internal Security Officer respectively, charged with their troops towards the fire in a bid to ensure it did not graduate to an explosion. But it did.</p><p>The Central Ammunition Depot (CAD) in Pulgaon is located about 120 kilometres from Nagpur. Outside its perimeter, little has changed since the threat of a Japanese invasion forced the British rulers of India to hurriedly create a centre which could logistically support the war in entire Southeast Asia. An aerial survey tipped the scale in favour of Pulgaon over neighbouring Bhusawal and Itarsi. In 1942, Lieutenant Colonel WV Atkins became the CAD's first Chief Ordnance Officer. &nbsp;</p><p>When dawn arrived on June 1, those at the CAD had already counted nineteen of their colleagues as dead, further seventeen as injured and the permanent shed where the fire was detected as having been completely destroyed. "I have lost too much," said the senior officer, nearly choking, as he hugged his colleague, a qualified specialist dispatched to CAD Pulgaon by army's Pune-based Southern Command. He was right. In its league, Tuesday's accident is the worst to have ever occurred.</p><p>Villagers cite colourful 'first hand' accounts of having seen 'night turn into day from the explosion', felt the earth shake, buildings kilometres away vibrate and heard the roar of self-made anti tank mines detonate.</p><p>In many ways the earth continues to shake.</p><p>Unending curiosity even among well wishers, flagging usual suspects like poor maintenance, reporting based on 'assumptions', social media conversations as well as expert opinions 'from air conditioned television studios' are all being silently suffered. "An inquiry has been ordered by the army', is all a spokesperson in New Delhi offered when asked about the cause.</p><p><b>WHAT COULD HAVE GONE WRONG?<br /></b></p><p>Facts tell you the depot holds close to 99 per cent of the army's ammunition. As the sole receiver of ammunition from the Ordnance Factory Boards (OFB), the CAD keeps all the depots stocked.</p><p>The army has deputed a Major General and two Brigadiers to probe the disaster.</p><p>That however does not stop those in the know from swearing allegiance to procedures. "It is science actually," said an officer. From storing ammunition on plinths, a few decades ago, the army now stops at nothing short of permanent structures built by Military Engineering Services (MES). The planning and construction of sheds is audited by third parties. The compatibility of storing different forms of ammunition keeping the individual hazard quotient in mind is mandated by United Nations guidelines which the army claims to follow to the 'T'.{mosimage}</p><p>The explosive zone, a 7000-acre exclusive facility within the CAD, has at least six check points that an individual needs to cross before being able to enter. Apart from hosting the ammunition-laden sheds, this region also hosts the remedies should they be required. For example, the army maintains 30 million tonnes of water at all times. Grass can help the fire spread. Thus thirty tractors churn in a radius of 50 metres from all the sheds to pick even the youngest blade of grass that may have grown. Roads inside are not made of tar, cement is used. Each shed has a dedicated pond which can be a handy source of water for fire fighters. The zone has nearly ten fire substations with dozens of tenders available. Electricity is forbidden unless a must for moving wares. "No wall of a shed can have even a single crack," explained an insider.</p><p>In response to a set of questions over the quality of upkeep, a source said, "CAD is the most modern, adequately funded and staffed installation."</p><p>Inside CAD, roads, residences and offices wear a desolate look. At the administration block though, the activity is peaking. The phones won't stop ringing. From Kerala to Uttarakhand and in between, everyone has a thing or two to discuss. Quietly, the army is booking flights to transport mortal remains. It will sponsor the travel of a relative along and provide a representative as an escort too. This, they say, is the 'easy' part. "How do we face their wives? How to reconcile with the fact that your friend and colleague who was there on Monday will go forever on Tuesday? We really don't know what went wrong but everyone else, it seems has already drawn conclusions," someone vented out.</p><p>At 'ground zero' in the Delta block, effort materialises in excavating severed limbs and body parts. Samples are being extracted for DNA testing. In the process, there is risk as well, from unexploded ammunition. To not invite further trouble, the digging will be done using with bare hands for as long as it takes.</p><p>Amidst the gloom, the 'mother depot' can hardly grieve. There are wagons waiting to either be loaded or unloaded, every day. Ammunition has to be sent, received or simply held. The gigantic base does all of its transactions online. When it comes to physical movement, over 80 per cent is done on rails.</p><p>Normalcy is returning, it has to<b><br /></b></p><p>Deputy Commandant Col Ghaninder Singh has undergone a surgery. Doctors recommend one more and the army flies him to Command hospital in Pune. As for the other two on the white board, a wipe with a duster says their story.</p><iframe src="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/embed/is7s62vhz4" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" height="396" width="648"></iframe><p><i>- Writer is a senior special correspondent with India Today TV and tweets @jrpur</i><br /><a href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/pulgaon-blast-130-tonn-ammunition-gutted-down-sabotage-angle-being-investigated/1/683350.html" target="_blank" mce_href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/pulgaon-blast-130-tonn-ammunition-gutted-down-sabotage-angle-being-investigated/1/683350.html"><b>&nbsp; <br />ALSO READ | Pulgaon blast: 130 Tonne ammunition gutted down, sabotage angle seriously investigated <br /></b></a></p><p><a href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/pulgaon-fire-death-toll-climbs/1/682342.html" target="_blank" mce_href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/pulgaon-fire-death-toll-climbs/1/682342.html"><b>Pulgaon ammunition depot fire: Two more bodies recovered, toll climbs to 18</b></a> </p><p><a href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/pulgaon-blast-130-tonn-ammunition-gutted-down-sabotage-angle-being-investigated/1/683350.html" target="_blank" mce_href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/pulgaon-blast-130-tonn-ammunition-gutted-down-sabotage-angle-being-investigated/1/683350.html"><b></b></a><br /></p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[Villagers cite colourful 'first hand' accounts of having seen 'night 
turn into day from the explosion', felt the earth shake, buildings 
kilometres away vibrate and heard the roar of self-made anti tank mines 
detonate.]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>355782</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Pulgaon disaster: Inside 'Mecca of ammunition', the ground still shakes  ]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Pulgaon disaster: Inside 'Mecca of ammunition', the ground still shakes  ]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Pulgaon disaster: Inside 'Mecca of ammunition', the ground still shakes  ]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>1</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/cad-disaster-inside-mecca-of-ammunition-the-ground-still-shakes/1/683393.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Pulgaon disaster: Inside 'Mecca of ammunition', the ground still shakes  ]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/ammunition-story_647_060316102707.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Pulgaon disaster: Inside 'Mecca of ammunition', the ground still shakes  ]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/ammunition-story_647_060316102707.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>0</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[cad-disaster-inside-mecca-of-ammunition-the-ground-still-shakes]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Pulgaon disaster: Inside 'Mecca of ammunition', the ground still shakes  ]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[Pulgaon fire,Pulgaon ammunition depot fire,CAD disaster,Pulgaon]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>