<story>
<id>683407</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>no</story_issue>
<select_magazine>0</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date/>
<bylines>
<byline>387</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464924690</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464924585</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1464935273</modifieddate>
<createdby>844</createdby>
<modifiedby>844</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city>285563</city>
</cities>
<categories><category>280038</category><category>938414</category><category>279990</category><category>937785</category><category>938812</category></categories><ordering>683407</ordering><primarycategory>938812</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/lisa-haydon-story-+-fb_647_060316090225.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt><![CDATA[Lisa Haydon]]></extra_large_alt>
<extra_large_title><![CDATA[Lisa Haydon]]></extra_large_title>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/lisa-haydon-story-+-fb_305_060316090225.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt><![CDATA[Lisa Haydon]]></large_alt>
<large_title><![CDATA[Lisa Haydon]]></large_title>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/lisa-haydon-story-+-fb_300x350_060316090225.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt><![CDATA[Lisa Haydon]]></mediumimage_alt>
<mediumimage_title><![CDATA[Lisa Haydon]]></mediumimage_title>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/lisa-haydon-story-+-fb_180_060316090225.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt><![CDATA[Lisa Haydon]]></smallimage_alt>
<smallimage_title><![CDATA[Lisa Haydon]]></smallimage_title>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/lisa-haydon-story-+-fb_88_060316090225.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt><![CDATA[Lisa Haydon]]></extra_small_alt>
<extra_small_title><![CDATA[Lisa Haydon]]></extra_small_title>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption><![CDATA[Lisa Haydon]]></kicker_image_caption>
<mosimage>
<image/><caption/></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[ Housefull 3 is all set to hit the screens on June 3 this year. Ahead of
 its release, Lisa Haydon speaks to IndiaToday.in about working with Akshay 
Kumar and more.]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>Lisa Haydon, who made her acting debut with the 2010 film Aisha, is now set for her upcoming film Housefull 3. Lisa's portrayal of the bohemian Vijaylaxmi in the 2014 film Queen has gained her much appreciation and is still fresh in our memories. The model-turned-actor's last outing The Shaukeens couldn't strike the right chord with the audience, but that doesn't stop Lisa from doing what is to be done. Now, Haydon is all set to entice her fans with Housefull 3.</p><p> 

<a href=" 	http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/housefull-3-sajid-farhad-akshay-kumar-sajid-khan-riteish-deshmukh-abhishek-bachchan/1/683204.html"><u><b>ALSO READ: Housefull 3 - We make films for public and not critics, says director duo Sajid-Farhad</b></u></a> </p><p>  

<a href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/akshay-riteish-open-up-on-comedy-nights-bachao-controversy-and-knowing-where-to-draw-the-line-housefull-3-abhishek-bachchan-aaradhya-exclusive/1/677355.html"><u><b>ALSO READ: Akshay, Riteish open up on Comedy Nights Bachao controversy and knowing where to draw the line</b></u></a> </p><p> 

Lisa plays the love interest of Riteish Deshmukh in the film. Apart from Riteish and Lisa, the film also stars Akshay Kumar, Nargis Fakhri and Jacqueline Fernandez in the lead roles. Housefull 3 is all set to hit the screens on June 3 this year. Ahead of its release, Lisa speaks to IndiaToday.in about working with Akshay Kumar and more. Excerpts from the conversation:</p><p> 
 
<b>You are collaborating with Akshay Kumar for the second time. How was the experience of working with him? What kind of equation do you share with him?</b></p><p> 

Akshay is a big prankster and just wants to have a good time on the sets. He is the funniest person I have ever met. He is always charged up when he does comedy, and one has to be on their toes all the time as you don't know what he might do or say. I don't know why, but he particularly narrows down on me every single time. Maybe that's because I am an easy target. Once, Akshay sneezed and he sprayed a bit of water on my back. And I thought it was his saliva. I was like, 'Jackky... (Jacqueline Fernandez)' as she was standing behind me, but she didn't utter a single word (laughs). Akshay is the master of comedy. You get to learn a lot if you're working with him.</p><p>  

<b>You were last seen in The Shaukeens, which was a solo project and now you're part of a multi-starrer project. What do you prefer more?</b></p><p> 

Both of them are important. I don't regret the films I have done or chosen. The Shaukeens was a solo project and I had a nice time filming that, but if you are part of a multi-starrer like Housefull 3, then I feel you share a lot of responsibility. There is a lot of energy and vibe on the sets. And yes, I would like to do more of solo projects. I liked The Shaukeens even though nobody else watched it.</p><p> 

<b>You were appreciated for your performance in Queen, but then you weren't seen in many films. Were you not offered many films or were you waiting for any particular kind of script?</b></p><p> 

I am so young in the industry. I feel that there is still a lot more to try. There are many parameters involved on why you do a film and why you don't choose to be a part of it. To be frank, I wasn't offered many films (laughs), but I would love to be a part of many projects like Housefull 3. Yes, I was appreciated for my role in Queen, but to be honest, comedy is my favourite genre. If there is a project that is meant for me, it will come my way.</p><p> 

<b>You are paired opposite Riteish Deshmukh in Housefull 3. How was the experience working with him?</b></p><p> 

Just like Akshay, Riteish also ganged up on me. Riteish is funny and has a lot of expressions. He is a man of many faces. Akshay is a prankster, so is he. He might look all sweet and innocent, but by the end of the shoot, I was like what you hiding Riteish behind your back because you just don't know what he's up to (bursts laughing). He is my on-screen protector and boyfriend Teddy. I think I was the easiest target for both Akshay and Riteish. Everybody played a prank on me with a sneeze-fest. I can go on and on about what else happened on the sets, but by the end, I just couldn't trust Riteish!</p><p> 

<iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TlZM9kuqw38" mce_src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TlZM9kuqw38" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" width="445"></iframe></p><p> 

<b>We have talked about Akshay and Riteish. What about Abhishek? Is he also a prankster like them? What about your experience of working with Nargis Fakhri and Jacqueline Fernandez?</b></p><p> 

Well, Abhishek is witty and has a sarcastic sense of humour. It takes you a few seconds to understand what he is saying. Talking about the girls, Jacqueline, Nargis and I struck a good chord instantly. Abhishek used to call us the gaggle, like a gaggle of geese, because we just wouldn't stop chatting.</p><p> 

<b>You don't fall in the category of the quintessential Hindi film heroine. Does that bother you?</b></p><p> 

I don't really know what that means. Is Aishwarya Rai Bachchan a quintessential Hindi film heroine or Sonam Kapoor? This is a mystery for me. Whether it is my body language, my look or my diction, I never treat these things as my weak points. Rather, I feel these add to my USP. I am not bothered about it, I don't see myself as a conventional or an unconventional actor. I am just trying to make my own place in the industry. I am not in a hurry to prove my acting talent. It'll happen at the right time.</p><p>  

<b>You are also a part of Karan Johar's Ae Dil Hai Mushkil. Can you tell us a bit about your role?</b></p><p> 

I can't reveal anything about my character in the film. I shot for it in London. It's a huge project and I am excited about it. Let me add that it's a cameo in the film.</p><p>  

<b>What's next for Lisa?</b></p><p> 

After Housefull 3, I'll shoot for India's Next Top Model.
</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[ Housefull 3 is all set to hit the screens on June 3 this year. Ahead of
 its release, Lisa Haydon speaks to IndiaToday.in about working with Akshay 
Kumar and more.]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>261619</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Lisa Haydon on working with Akshay Kumar: He is a big prankster, I am an easy target]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Lisa Haydon on working with Akshay Kumar: He is a big prankster, I am an easy target]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Lisa Haydon on working with Akshay Kumar: He is a big prankster, I am an easy target]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>0</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/lisa-haydon-on-working-with-akshay-kumar-he-is-a-big-prankster-i-am-an-easy-target-housefull-3/1/683407.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Lisa Haydon on working with Akshay Kumar: He is a big prankster, I am an easy target]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/lisa-haydon-story-+-fb_647_060316090225.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Lisa Haydon on working with Akshay Kumar: He is a big prankster, I am an easy target]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/lisa-haydon-story-+-fb_647_060316090225.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag>exclusive</content_type_tag>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents><relatedcontent type="text">676903</relatedcontent><relatedcontent type="text">675389</relatedcontent></relatedcontents>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[lisa-haydon-on-working-with-akshay-kumar-he-is-a-big-prankster-i-am-an-easy-target-housefull-3]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Lisa Haydon on working with Akshay Kumar: He is a big prankster, I am an easy target]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[housefull 3, housefull 3 review, housefull 3 movie review, housefull 3 show timings delhi, housefull 3 release, lisa haydon, akshay kumar, riteish deshmukh, jacqueline fernandez, abhishek bachchan]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>