<story>
<id>683405</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>no</story_issue>
<select_magazine>0</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date/>
<bylines>
<byline>1180</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464924552</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464924511</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1464934314</modifieddate>
<createdby>781</createdby>
<modifiedby>781</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city>285563</city>
</cities>
<categories><category>938496</category></categories><ordering>683404</ordering><primarycategory>938496</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/devil-daggers-logo_559_060316114145.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt/>
<extra_large_title/>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/devil-daggers-logo_305_060316114145.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt/>
<large_title/>
<mediumimage/>
<mediumimage_alt/>
<mediumimage_title/>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/devil-daggers-logo_180_060316114145.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt/>
<smallimage_title/>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/devil-daggers-logo_88_060316114145.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt/>
<extra_small_title/>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption/>
<mosimage>
<image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/devil-daggers-gameplay-2_060316112429.jpg]]></image><caption/><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/devil-daggers-gameplay-1_060316112429.jpg]]></image><caption/></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title>Devil Daggers</title><rating>7/10</rating><pron_cons_img>http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday//images/stories/devil-daggers-logo_305_060316114033.jpg </pron_cons_img></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item>Simple yet satisfying gameplay</item><item>Good sound</item><item>Value for money</item></tech_pros><tech_cons><item>Can be overwhelmingly difficult</item><item>No story</item><item>Low quality texture</item></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[Devil Daggers can be considered a shooter game infused with the simple sensibilities of endless running games like Temple Run.]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>Devil Daggers feels like an anomaly in the vast ocean of FPS (first person shooter) games. Its brand of fast-paced action doesn't feel novel but what's new is the emphasis on time. Play it for a while and you can describe Devil Daggers as a shooter game infused with the simple sensibilities of endless running games like Temple Run. Now, this may seem like a hard sell, the game does things well enough to keep you hooked for the duration of its bit sized runs. <br /></p><h3>Story and plot<br /></h3><p>On first glance, there doesn't seem to be much in the way of story. It is also possibly because with its emphasis on game play, there is little room left to cram in a story. Just like the Temple Run, in which you start each play by stealing a statue from a temple, you start Devil Daggers by collecting the namesake dagger which floats in front of you. Once your hand is on the dagger, you are transported to an arena filled with endless monsters that spawn in relentlessly. Your goal is to survive as long as you can. <br /></p><p>The rest of the plot is entirely to your discretion, although my impression is that you are stuck in some sort of purgatory where you keep fighting endless waves of demons as some infernal punishment. Although depending on your context and imagination, you may interpret the game differently. The long story short, you don't play Devil Daggers for the story. <br /></p><h3>Gameplay and graphics<br /></h3><p>Just because a game is simple doesn't mean it can't have style. The Devil Daggers is a weird mix of lo-fi Quake like texture work, with fantastic creature design, and it is something that will keep you coming back for more. From the squid like husks that throw out floating skulls in your direction to the large skull with spider like legs that creep towards you, all the creatures look and sound unique. <br /></p><p>Sound design is especially convincing and each hell spawn has a unique sound associated with it, easily allowing you to differentiate between two monstrosities. As the difficulty slowly ramps up and creatures fill the arena, these sound cues may mean the difference between success and an untimely death. &nbsp;<br /></p><p>{mosimage}The gameplay is also deceptively simple. You have two modes of attack, pressing down the left mouse button releases a stream of infinite projectiles that have to be aimed properly unless you just want to spray all over the place. The second attack concentrates the particles into a shotgun like blast, useful when enemies get up close. As more and more baddies spawn in, the game slowly reveals its depths. As you frantically run around staying out of reach of nasty baddie, you have to quickly think on your feet. Which enemy do you kill first? Do you kill all of them as quickly as possible or allow some to stay to farm pickups? When a dozen skulls bum-rush you and you can see the silhouette of a giant kite like thing about to take off, what do you do? Your end goal is to survive and you do so by thinking on your feet. One hit means game over.<br /></p><p class="review_quote"><i class="fa fa-quote-left"></i>  
The Devil Daggers is a weird mix of lo-fi Quake like texture work, with fantastic creature design, and it is something that will keep you coming back for more <i class="fa fa-quote-right"></i></p>The absolute masterstroke here are the leaderboards, that show you the best runs from the top players. What's neat is that you can click on the little eye icon next to each person's name to see a real-time replay of their best run -- I have only averaged around 55 seconds at best - and it's something that adds that "little bit extra" needed to motivate you too to do better for your next run. You watch and learn from the best players, it makes you competitive to improve but also strangely makes you root for the next person about to go up against unwinnable odds. It taps into the social community aspect by borrowing leader boards while smartly integrating replays into the game itself so that you don't end up alt-tabbing between a browser and the game. <br /><p>&nbsp;</p><h3>Should you buy it?<br /></h3><p>{mosimage}The extreme difficulty is sure to turn some players off! The fact that on average a playtime lasts between 9 to 10 seconds is enough to send most people scurrying but it does enough things right to keep you hooked and most importantly keeps you coming back for bite-sized runs, if only to see whether you can best your previous time. Smartly, Devil Daggers is also priced about right. On PC, you can download Devil Daggers via Steam for Rs 259 and that feels like a sweet spot (except when a AAA title is not on sale) between a full-fledged Rs 999 release or a cheap indie title. We say you go for it. If nothing else, buy it to experience the unique first person take on the endless runner genre.</p>####<div class='tech-pros-cons-main'><h2>Devil Daggers####<strong>7/10</strong></h2>####<ul class='pron-cons-img'><li><img src='http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday//images/stories/devil-daggers-logo_305_060316114033.jpg' ></li></ul>####<ul class='tech-pros'><li><span>Good stuff</span></li><li>Simple yet satisfying gameplay</li><li>Good sound</li><li>Value for money</li></ul>####<ul class='tech-cons'><li><span>Bad stuff</span></li><li>Can be overwhelmingly difficult</li><li>No story</li><li>Low quality texture</li></ul></p></div></p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[Devil Daggers can be considered a shooter game infused with the simple sensibilities of endless running games like Temple Run.]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>356084</tag>
<tag>301346</tag>
<tag>267547</tag>
<tag>224533</tag>
<tag>275376</tag>
<tag>231819</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Devil Daggers review: Quake meets Temple Run]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Devil Daggers review: Quake meets Temple Run]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Devil Daggers review: Quake meets Temple Run]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>0</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/technology/story/devil-daggers-review-quake-meets-temple-run/1/683405.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Devil Daggers review: Quake meets Temple Run]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/devil-daggers-logo_559_060316114145.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Devil Daggers review: Quake meets Temple Run]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/devil-daggers-logo_559_060316114145.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion>7</commentquestion>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[devil-daggers-review-quake-meets-temple-run]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Devil Daggers review: Quake meets Temple Run]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[devil daggers, game review, devil daggers review, gaming consoles, gaming]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>