<story>
<id>683430</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>no</story_issue>
<select_magazine>0</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date/>
<bylines>
<byline>304</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464931643</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464930941</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1464932518</modifieddate>
<createdby>799</createdby>
<modifiedby>799</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city>285563</city>
</cities>
<categories><category>280038</category><category>938414</category><category>279990</category><category>938232</category></categories><ordering>683430</ordering><primarycategory>938232</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/thithi-story+fb-_647_060316105843.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt><![CDATA[A still from Thithi]]></extra_large_alt>
<extra_large_title><![CDATA[A still from Thithi]]></extra_large_title>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/thithi-story+fb-_305_060316105843.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt><![CDATA[A still from Thithi]]></large_alt>
<large_title><![CDATA[A still from Thithi]]></large_title>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/thithi-story+fb-_300_060316105843.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt><![CDATA[A still from Thithi]]></mediumimage_alt>
<mediumimage_title><![CDATA[A still from Thithi]]></mediumimage_title>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/thithi-story+fb-_180_060316105843.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt><![CDATA[A still from Thithi]]></smallimage_alt>
<smallimage_title><![CDATA[A still from Thithi]]></smallimage_title>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/thithi-story+fb-_88_060316105843.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt><![CDATA[A still from Thithi]]></extra_small_alt>
<extra_small_title><![CDATA[A still from Thithi]]></extra_small_title>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption><![CDATA[A still from Thithi]]></kicker_image_caption>
<mosimage>
<image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/ramreddy-mos_060316105938.jpg]]></image><caption/><image><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/2016May/thithi-mos-full_060316105938.jpg]]></image><caption/></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[Filmmaker Raam Reddy speaks about his film school, his style of filmmaking and National Award-winning Kannada film, Thithi. <br />]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>Anurag Kashyap has seen the National Award-winning Kannada film, Thithi, four times, saying he can't get enough of the tragicomedy.&nbsp; The Raman Raghav 2.0 filmmaker also organised a special screening for the film in Mumbai. Aamir Khan praised Thithi on Twitter in four back-to-back tweets, and his wife-filmmaker Kiran Rao also held a screening for the film industry. Raam Reddy, 26, is overwhelmed with Bollywood glitterati and elite's approval and appreciation as well as the response of the audiences from his home state, Karnataka, where the film released in the first week of May.</p><p><u><b><a target="_blank" href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/thithi-kannada-film-aamir-khan-anurag-kashyap-kangana-ranaut-vicky-kaushal-swara-bhaskar/1/681461.html">ALSO READ: Thithi gets a thumbs up from Aamir Khan, Anurag Kashyap&nbsp; </a></b></u> <br /></p><p>Seated at a cafe in Mumbai, where he has been devising the national release strategy for Thithi, Reddy is eagerly waiting for the rest of India to discover his film which releases with English subtitles in Mumbai, Pune, Delhi/NCR and a screen in Chennai on June 3. Co-written by his friend Eregowda and co-produced with his father, Pratap Reddy, the film, set and shot in Eregowda's village Nodekoppalu, follows the lives of three male members from three different generations who are brought together after the demise of the family's oldest patriarch. Sweet, funny, poignant with many endearing characters including the wandering Gadappa, Thithi won two awards at the Locarno International Film Festival.&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;</p><p>Born in Karnataka, Raam Reddy studied economics at St Stephen's College in Delhi and then headed to Prague for studies in filmmaking. A fan of Austrian auteur Michael Haneke ("for his command of craft"), German-Turk filmmaker Fatih Akin ("for his balance between narrative and art), acclaimed TV series, The Wire, and Peter Jackson's Lord of the Rings trilogy ("it proved the magic of cinema"), Reddy directed shorts in Telugu, Czech, English, Hindi and even a silent one. Thithi though is Reddy's first project in his home tongue and also his first feature. </p><p>{mosimage}&nbsp;</p><p>Edited excerpts from the interview:</p><p><b>You come from a political family. Your grandfather was the first Chief Minister of Karnataka. Was your family supportive of your career in filmmaking?</b><br />I have heard how great my grandfather was but I never got to meet him as he passed away before I was born. After my grandfather became Chief Minister, he strictly told his children to not get into politics. So the next generation - my father and his siblings - no one's in it. </p><p>We are not an art family at all. We are a business-oriented one. My immediate family is really different. My father's a businessman, mother a social worker, sister has a PhD in linguistics and my brother is in stock market and also into wildlife photography. I was never ever told by anyone in family on what I should pursue.&nbsp; There was no pressure of business. It was that whatever you take up, just try and do your best at it. Be your own perfectionist. It's the best kind of upbringing. </p><p><b>Tell us a bit about your stint at the Prague Film School. What made you pick it?</b><br />I am very rebellious against the teaching of art and I still maintain you shouldn't be taught art. Post Stephen's and before I went to film school, I had made eight shorts already. I was very stubborn about not going to film school. I said that I'd save the money that I spent for film school to make a feature instead. </p><p>Then I went to Eregowda's village. I was thinking that if I start a project then I had to keep it intimate. But once I was there, I realised it had to be an ambitious project. Now to achieve this, I wasn't technically confident enough. I had to search for a place that didn't teach me art but technically honed my skills and improve my networking. </p><p>Prague Film School is the best template for practical learning in the world. During my nine months there, I was in the crew of 34 films and made six shorts of my own. I got exactly what I wanted from there.</p><p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q_NltD4Stv4" mce_src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q_NltD4Stv4" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" width="445"></iframe></p><p>Eregowda has done a series of jobs for your family. How did the collaboration with him happen?&nbsp; Did you always notice i a creative spark in him? <br />Eregowda can do whatever he puts his mind to. He is sharp and talented. He learns quickly. Both of us got along really well. [Like him] Even I don't like to put myself in a cubbyhole. It's just a way of treating the world. &nbsp;</p><p>His background and upbringing gave him a sense of reality which was very far removed from mine. We grew up challenging each other. I think I introduced him to art, starting with photography. He did the production for my short, Ika (Feather). He started to like filmmaking when he documented my mother's works. He has formatted my English novel too. Personally, he is interested in camera than writing. </p><p><b>Most of the cast is from the village. Kashyap is impressed with how you have directed the non-actors. Did having Eregowda, who was known to them, help? </b><br />Absolutely. I am used to working with non-actors because I made all my shorts barring the last, a Czech one, with them. A humanistic way of working with non-actors is something I developed through my shorts. I'd take takes quickly to get them into rhythm. <br />&nbsp;<br />With Thithi, it was little difficult. Of course, everyone got frustrated at points. My quality control level is very high. You have to stay calm while everyone is getting cranky around you. You have to get your shot. Patience is required. </p><p>Thithi's shoot was tailored to [accommodate] non-professionals. I told my crew that performance is the leader of the film. The characters are the soul of the script. The actors were king on sets. The simplest visual, editing and sound design approach was taken. It was a very observational process of filmmaking. Our equipment was geared towards quick reactivity. </p><p>Eregowda's relationship with the people in the village was key in getting us [the crew] comfortable. He was the dialogue coach, getting the non-actors to remember lines. He ensured the cultural references are correct. </p><p><b>All the four male characters have shades of grey. What kind of family portrait you and Eregowda had in mind?</b><br />I wanted to have two characters which are materialistic in a way typical to their generation. So there is a pubescent teen, Abhi, who is running after a girl, and a middle-aged man, Thamanna, who wants to better his position in society. There is lot of myself and my family in Gadappa. We are very spiritually oriented. My mother's father sold off his business and lives in an ashram. These little things made me want to create a story that makes people reflect on materialistic pursuits. &nbsp;</p><p>In terms of nuances, the film itself is based on the actors' personalities in some way. The complexities came from Eregowda's insight into village life. The intention was to create an authentic film without altering the reality in anyway.</p><p>Thithi also makes you reflect on our obsession with rituals and their relevance in today's age. <br />I come from a spiritual zone of thought where any sort of systematised ritual is regressive for freedom of thought. As Gadappa says at one point, 'Will the dead get to know?' </p><p>Morality is an egoistic thing. When you say this is right or wrong, you are creating boundaries, you are limiting yourself. Gadappa is a symbol of free-flowing life from the heart. He just lives life in the moment. </p><p>{mosimage}&nbsp;</p><p><b>There are also some very strong female characters which aren't afraid to speak their mind in front of the men. </b><br />It was not easy to get women from the village to agree to play large roles in this film. You had to get permission from the rest of family. In that sense it is still a patriarchal society. I knew this film would be male-dominated film because it is a character study of three generations. So the idea was to have them not play big but memorable roles and strong in terms of particularity. </p><p>I personally am of the opinion both genders are equal. In my personal life, I have grown up around strong women in my mother and sister. I'm also very irritated with how women are treated in cinema. &nbsp;</p><p><b>What are you working on next?</b><br />I have an idea but it is in nascent stages. I believe language is one of the characters of your film so my next may not be in Kannada. I don't want to stick to any genre. I want to make something more personal, something I am in more control of.&nbsp; I'd like to make it with professional actors. </p><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[Filmmaker Raam Reddy speaks about his film school, his style of filmmaking and National Award-winning Kannada film, Thithi. <br />]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>345798</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Thithi: The shoot was tailored to accomodate non-actors, says director Raam Reddy ]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Thithi: The shoot was tailored to accomodate non-actors, says director Raam Reddy ]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Thithi: The shoot was tailored to accomodate non-actors, says director Raam Reddy ]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>2</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/thithi-raam-reddy-kannada-national-award-winning-film/1/683430.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Thithi: The shoot was tailored to accomodate non-actors, says director Raam Reddy ]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/thithi-story+fb-_647_060316105843.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Thithi: The shoot was tailored to accomodate non-actors, says director Raam Reddy ]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/thithi-story+fb-_647_060316105843.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[thithi-raam-reddy-kannada-national-award-winning-film]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Thithi: The shoot was tailored to accomodate non-actors, says director Raam Reddy ]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[thithi, thithi news, raam reddy, kannada film thithi, anurag kashyap praises ]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>