<story>
<id>683611</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>no</story_issue>
<select_magazine>0</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date/>
<bylines>
<byline>347</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1464996279</createddate>
<publisheddate>1464996016</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1465028759</modifieddate>
<createdby>852</createdby>
<modifiedby>882</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city>285563</city>
</cities>
<categories><category>279844</category><category>279970</category><category>280038</category><category>279986</category><category>279583</category><category>280185</category><category>279607</category><category>280229</category></categories><ordering>683611</ordering><primarycategory>279583</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/startup-2-105_647_060416015442.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt/>
<extra_large_title/>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/startup-2-105_305_060416015442.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt/>
<large_title/>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/startup-2-105_300x350_060416015442.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt/>
<mediumimage_title/>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/startup-2-105_180_060416015442.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt/>
<smallimage_title/>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/startup-2-105_88_060416015442.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt/>
<extra_small_title/>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption><![CDATA[Prime Minister Narendra Modi had launched the Startup India campaign in January amid much fanfare.]]></kicker_image_caption>
<mosimage>
<image/><caption/></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[Officials explained that the reason for low approval was the fact that 
many applications were not worthy for clearance while others had simply 
not completed procedures and submitted relevant documents.]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>Months after the launch of Prime Minister Narendra Modi's flagship scheme Startup India, only a single project has got clearance from the government out of over 200 aspiring entrepreneurs who had applied for the permission to set up new business. </p><p>Modi had kicked off the ambitious Startup India in January and the Ministry of Commerce and Industry launched the Startup web portal and mobile app in April. </p><p>The portal is meant to enable start-ups avail all tax benefits announced in the startup action plan. Officials explained that the reason for low approval was the fact that many applications were not worthy for clearance while others had simply not completed procedures and submitted relevant documents. Shailendra Singh, joint secretary, Department of Industrial Policy and Promotion (DIPP) told Mail Today that over 200 people had applied on the startup portal for registration. "Many of them have not completed the complete formalities required for registration on the startup portal. Many ideas were not innovative enough. Only one of them has been given certificate," said the officer. <br /><b><br />FAILURE</b></p><p>Out of over 200 applicants, about 170 had not completed the process of registration. About 25 had not given their process details of business. Many of the projects were not innovative enough to attract attention of the board members which decided for certification of startups. When asked if it meant that there are not too many innovative business ideas, officials denied that being the case. </p><p>"Many entrepreneurs don't come to us for registration. They get funding from other sources and they are doing their own business," said an official. </p><p>When asked whether the registration process on the startup portal needs to be more simplified, DIPP officials said it is already easy. "Everything is there on the portal. There is no human intervention. List of incubators. Startups needs to go to them," said an official. However, some experts have raised questions over the registration process at the government portal. "Every startup can't go to the incubators for funding. Aspiring entrepreneurs having innovative ideas but not having background of IIT or IIM may not find incubators. Government can appoint third party expert body to assess the innovative business ideas," said Himanshu Kumar, founder, anglepaisa.com, a crowd funding platform where one can invest in startups business and raise capital. </p><p>DIPP has also set up an inter-ministerial board to verify the eligibility of start-ups opting to avail tax and IPR-related benefits. Besides, the department is engaging with state governments in building incubation capacities for young entrepreneurs. The Modi government has already declared the fund for startups in the Budget and accordingly Rs 2,500 crore each year would be released over next four years to SIDBI. </p><p>All the tax benefits will be extended to budding entrepreneurs after the passage of the Finance Bill. The startup portal provides with a real-time recognition certificate. Moreover, startups can also find information regarding various notifications issued by government ministries and information about incubators and funding agencies. Also, the site features the Startup India Hub, established within Invest India, which is a single point of contact for the ecosystem enabling exchange of knowledge. </p><p>This works like a hub and spoke model with governments, V-Cs, angel funds, incubators, mentors. It also assists start-ups through their lifecycle, on all aspects, such as providing mentorship, incubator facilities, IPR support and funding. The firm which has been selected is Hyderabadbased Cygny Energy Pvt Ltd which provides inverter-less home renewable energy controller. This is an innovative power back-up solution replacing the traditional inverters. No inverters means 50 per cent saving in electricity bills through intelligent use of solar, battery and energy-efficient DC equipment. THe technology for the back-up was developed in collaboration with IITM, provides a 48V DC as a power backup line.</p><p><b><a target="_blank" href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/startup-registration-must-be-simplified-a-budding-entrepreneur/1/682168.html" mce_href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/startup-registration-must-be-simplified-a-budding-entrepreneur/1/682168.html">Also read: </a><a target="_blank">Startup India registration must be simplified: A budding entrepreneur</a></b>  </p><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[Officials explained that the reason for low approval was the fact that 
many applications were not worthy for clearance while others had simply 
not completed procedures and submitted relevant documents.]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>321701</tag>
<tag>222613</tag>
<tag>222538</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Startup India: 250 requests, 90 days, 1 picked]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Startup India: 250 requests, 90 days, 1 picked]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Startup India: 250 requests, 90 days, 1 picked]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>0</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/startup-india-250-requests-90-days-1-picked/1/683611.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[<a href="http://mailtoday.in" target="_blank">Mail Today</a>]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Startup India: 250 requests, 90 days, 1 picked]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/startup-2-105_647_060416015442.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Startup India: 250 requests, 90 days, 1 picked]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/startup-2-105_647_060416015442.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents/>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase><![CDATA[Hyderabad solar firm is Startup India’s chosen one]]></briefcase><briefcase><![CDATA[Startup India was launched in January]]></briefcase><briefcase><![CDATA[It has been PM Modi's flagship scheme]]></briefcase></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[startup-india-250-requests-90-days-1-picked]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Startup India: 250 requests, 90 days, 1 picked]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[Start-up,Startup India,Narendra Modi,BJP]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>