<story>
<id>683691</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>no</story_issue>
<select_magazine>0</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date/>
<bylines>
<byline>290</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1465041008</createddate>
<publisheddate>1465040877</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1465069163</modifieddate>
<createdby>681</createdby>
<modifiedby>681</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city>285563</city>
</cities>
<categories><category>279844</category><category>279856</category><category>938154</category><category>280038</category><category>280225</category><category>279986</category><category>279631</category><category>280185</category><category>937822</category><category>938626</category></categories><ordering>683691</ordering><primarycategory>938626</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/eknath4_647_060416053631.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></extra_large_alt>
<extra_large_title><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></extra_large_title>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/eknath4_305_060416053631.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></large_alt>
<large_title><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></large_title>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/eknath4_300_060416053631.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></mediumimage_alt>
<mediumimage_title><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></mediumimage_title>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/khadse4_180_060416053631.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></smallimage_alt>
<smallimage_title><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></smallimage_title>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/eknath4_88_060416053631.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></extra_small_alt>
<extra_small_title><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></extra_small_title>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption><![CDATA[File photo of Eknath Khadse.]]></kicker_image_caption>
<mosimage>
<image/><caption/></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[Maharashtra Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis today tweeted that Eknath Khadse's resignation letter has been forwarded to Governor C Vidyasagar Rao for acceptance and a retired high court judge will probe charges levelled against him.]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>After Maharashtra Revenue Minister Eknath Khadse tendered his resignation for his alleged involvement in the controversial Pune land deal, land owner Abbas Unkani's son Anis Ukani admitted that his father had sold the plot to Chaudhri and Mrs Khadse and criticised the Maharashtra Industrial Development Corporation (MIDC) for the inordinate delay in paying the compensation. However, the Ukanis refused to speak on camera.</p><p>Speaking on the land row, Anis Ukani said, "We refrained from speaking to Media as our main and immediate concern was our father's health as he has been keeping unwell due to the situation. Yes, my father Abbas R Ukani sold the land to Chaudhri and Mrs Khadse on April 28, 2016".</p><p>"We have not received any compensation in the last 45 years regarding which the acquisition was started but the ownership remained with us and we have been fighting this case since then. MIDC needs to answer why it takes so long for any such cases and regarding the lawful entitlement to the land owners. We ran from&nbsp; pillar to post. We approached the court and our case is currently in the Mumbai High Court and due for hearing. Hence further we have no details to furnish," Anis added.</p><p>Khadse's wife Mandakini and son-in-law Girish Chaudhary had bought 1.21 hectares of land in Bhosari, Pune, for a mere Rs 3.75 crore against the RR price of Rs 23 crore. <br /></p><p>Abbas Ukani moved to high court in October 2015 to reclaim his land. While case was still pending, Ukani reportedly sold the land Khadse's wife, Mandakini, and son-in-law, Dattaram Chaudhari on April 27, 2016.</p><p>According to the agreement signed between the Khadse's family and Ukani, the awarded compensation will be given to the purchaser.</p><p>Going by the land value in 1969 (Rs 6000/- per acre) the compensation should amount to Rs 23 crore. However under the new Land Acquisition Act the amount is expected to be anywhere around Rs 100 crore. </p><p><b>FADNAVIS ACCEPTS KHADSE'S RESIGNATION</b></p><p>Maharashtra Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis today accepted Eknath Khadse's resignation over the later's alleged involvement in the land deal. A retired high court judge will probe charges levelled against Khadse and his resignation forwarded to Governor C Vidyasagar Rao for acceptance, Fadnavis tweeted.</p><p>"Khadse ji has demanded an inquiry into allegations against him. A retired HC Judge will be appointed to conduct inquiry," said Fadnavis in a tweet.<br /><b><br />KHADSE PLEADS INNOCENCE</b></p><p>Embattled Khadse today said that he resigned from his post to "uphold moral values" in BJP and that the party was standing firmly behind him over the "baseless" allegations.</p><p>"For the last 40 years, I have been working in politics and the party but have not experienced a media trial like this before," Khadse told reporters at the state BJP office soon after he met CM Devendra Fadnavis to submit his resignation.</p><p>"There has been an unprecedented media trial against me.</p><p>I have demanded to Fadnavis that there should be a probe into the allegations.</p><p>"BJP is firmly behind me and even tomorrow it will stand behind me. The party has always abided by moral values. BJP is of the opinion that one should not continue to hold posts in face of allegations," he said.</p><p>On the allegations by a Pune-based builder Hemant Gawande that he purchased a land in MIDC area of Bhosari near Pune in the name of his wife, the BJP leader said, "The revenue department has said that no transaction regarding the MIDC plot purchase is illegal."</p><p>"Had the land really belonged to MIDC, the corporation's name would have been in the concerned documents. I suggested to police to file FIR against the person who was illegally trying to usurp Pune agricultural college land worth Rs 400 crore.</p><p>"I issued a GR on taking back Wakf land illegally taken over by some people and they will naturally bear the brunt of that decision," Khadse said, in a veiled reference to allegations that bigwigs affected by that GR may have been behind the campaign to dislodge him.</p><p>"The allegations levelled by Congress and AAP are baseless. Allegations have been made against senior BJP leaders Advani and Gadkari in the past," he said.</p><p>"Police have said that no call was made or received on my mobile from Dawood Ibrahim," Khadse said referring to hacker Manish Bhangale's claim.</p><p>"A hacker means a thief and hacking is an offence of treason. If they can't furnish proof, action should be taken against those making such false charges," he said.</p><p><b>ANJALI DAMANIA TO CONTINUE HER FAST</b></p><p>On 3rd day of her fast, activist Anjali Damania said that she is happy to know that Khadse has put in his papers, however, she will not end her fast till Fadnavis announces an enquiry - preferably of three former judges of high court against Khadse.</p><p>She has been served a notice by Azad Maidan Police Station against her fast. The notice says that her fast is illegal and punishable. Meanwhile, Damania has returned the notice and challenged the police to do whatever they want against her.</p><p>Damania has announced that she will travel to Ralegansiddhi and tell Anna Hazare about all the scams that Khadse has been involved in.</p><p><b>ALSO READ</b>:</p><p><b><a target="_blank" href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/eknath-khadse-resigns-india-today-impact-dawood-calls-pune-land-deal/1/683647.html ">India Today Impact: Eknath Khadse resigns as Maharashtra minister, supporters stage protest </a></b></p><p><b><a target="_blank" href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/eknath-khadse-dawood-links-land-grabbing-amit-shah/1/683214.html" mce_href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/eknath-khadse-dawood-links-land-grabbing-amit-shah/1/683214.html">From Dawood calls to land grab: Defiant Khadse refuses to quit, Fadnavis to meet Modi, Shah</a> &nbsp;</b> <br /></p><iframe src="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/embed/is619twf7k" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" height="396" width="648"></iframe><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[Maharashtra Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis today tweeted that Eknath Khadse's resignation letter has been forwarded to Governor C Vidyasagar Rao for acceptance and a retired high court judge will probe charges levelled against him.]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>290472</tag>
<tag>494287</tag>
<tag>622039</tag>
<tag>263640</tag>
<tag>252470</tag>
<tag>227257</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Pune land owner admits selling plot to Mrs Khadse, slams MIDC for delay in compensation]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Pune land owner admits selling plot to Mrs Khadse, slams MIDC for delay in compensation]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Pune land owner admits selling plot to Mrs Khadse, slams MIDC for delay in compensation]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>0</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/maharashtra-land-row-eknath-khadse-pune-land-owner-abbas-unkani-and-midc/1/683691.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Pune land owner admits selling plot to Mrs Khadse, slams MIDC for delay in compensation]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/eknath4_647_060416053631.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Pune land owner admits selling plot to Mrs Khadse, slams MIDC for delay in compensation]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/eknath4_647_060416053631.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents><relatedcontent type="text">683647</relatedcontent><relatedcontent type="text">682612</relatedcontent><relatedcontent type="text">683080</relatedcontent></relatedcontents>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase><![CDATA[My father Abbas R Ukani sold the land to Chaudhri and Mrs Khadse on April 28]]></briefcase><briefcase><![CDATA[ 2016: Anis Ukani]]></briefcase><briefcase><![CDATA[We have not received any compensation in the last 45 years: Anis Ukani]]></briefcase><briefcase><![CDATA[Abbas Ukani moved to high court in October 2015 to reclaim his land.]]></briefcase><briefcase><![CDATA[According to the agreement signed between the Khadse's family and Ukani]]></briefcase><briefcase><![CDATA[ the awarded compensation will be given to the purchaser.]]></briefcase></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[maharashtra-land-row-eknath-khadse-pune-land-owner-abbas-unkani-and-midc]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Pune land owner admits selling plot to Mrs Khadse, slams MIDC for delay in compensation]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse,Maharashtra land row,Khadse land grabbing case,Pune land owner,Abbas Unkani,Devendra Fadnavis,MIDC]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>