<story>
<id>683713</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>no</story_issue>
<select_magazine>0</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date/>
<bylines>
<byline>1351</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1465049149</createddate>
<publisheddate>1465048997</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1465069105</modifieddate>
<createdby>681</createdby>
<modifiedby>681</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city>285443</city>
</cities>
<categories><category>279844</category><category>279856</category><category>938154</category><category>280038</category><category>280225</category><category>279986</category><category>279631</category><category>280185</category><category>937822</category><category>938626</category></categories><ordering>683713</ordering><primarycategory>938626</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/khadse--_146504896862_647x404_060416073549.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></extra_large_alt>
<extra_large_title><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></extra_large_title>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/khadse--_146504896862_305x182_060416073549.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></large_alt>
<large_title><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></large_title>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/khadse--_146504896862_300x350_060416073549.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></mediumimage_alt>
<mediumimage_title><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></mediumimage_title>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/khadse--_146504896862_180x118_060416073549.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></smallimage_alt>
<smallimage_title><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></smallimage_title>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/khadse--_146504896862_88x66_060416073549.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></extra_small_alt>
<extra_small_title><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></extra_small_title>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse.]]></kicker_image_caption>
<mosimage>
<image/><caption/></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[The senior BJP leader thought high command will not touch him being the most senior minister and the tallest OBC face of the party in Maharashtra.]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>Former Maharashtra Revenue Minister Eknath Khadse has paid a heavy price for keeping wrong company. His office was full of unreliable people with dubious distinctions from the day he took charge of the office. There were complaints about wrong doings and malpractices from across the state but Khadse kept a mum on them.</p><p>He was convinced that the BJP high command will not touch him as he was the party's most senior minister and the tallest OBC face in the state. He continued saying that someone had conspired against him and he would nail the person soon. Many felt that he was referring to chief minister Devendra Fadnavis who had announced that one of Khadse's aids Gajanan Patil was on the police radar for three months for asking bribe on behalf of the minister.</p><p><b>GADKARI DIDN'T SUPPORT KHADSE </b><br /></p><p>On the night of June 3 when Union transport minister Nitin Gadkari told Khadse that he should meet BJP president Amit Shah in Delhi on June 7 and present his side on the allegation that he misused his position while purchasing a three acre piece of industrial land at Bhosari near Pune Khadse was again convinced that he might get a new lease of life. However, his only hope in the form of support from Gadkari vanished after he received a call from Shah at 11:45 am on June 4 asking him to step down.</p><p><b>CONFLICT OF INTEREST</b> <br /></p><p>According to a senior BJP minister Khadse's act to buy the land in name of his wife Mandakini and son-in-law Girish Choudhary was a clear case of conflict of interest. "It was a violation of the high court's ruling that a minister should not purchase property for himself or his family while he is in the government. Had bhau (as Khadse is called in BJP) purchased the land in someone else's name he would not have been in trouble at all," the minister says.</p><p><b>DESAI WANTED TO SETTLE SCORE</b><br /></p><p>Khadse's trouble escalated on May 31 when industries minister Subhash Desai pushed him to a corner by declaring that the piece of land purchased by his kin belonged to the Maharashtra Industrial Development Corporation (MIDC). The needle of suspicion pointed towards Khadse since then. Both Khadse and Desai knew that the MIDC had not acquired the land in question. Desai wanted to settle a score over Khadse for taking initiative in snapping the BJP's 27-year-old ties with the Shiv Sena in September 2014. When asked how Khadse's family manage to buy a land owned by MIDC, Desai had said, "I don't know. You should ask this question to him."</p><p>The Shiv Sena workers distributed sweets after Khadse stepped down. There is a feeling among them that he was the killer of their alliance. Had the BJP continued alliance with Shiv Sena the Shiv Sena would have got more seats and their chief Uddhav Thackeray would have become the CM. The Shiv Sena workers were also rejoicing the situation where corruption was "established" in form of Khadse's resignation.</p><p><b>PRAKASH MEHTA VS EKNATH KHADSE </b><br /></p><p>BJP ministers Prakash Mehta and Vinod Tawde will be equally happy along with Shiv Sena chief Uddhav Thackeray after Khadse's exit. Mehta was upset with Khadse as the latter had not cleared several files he had recommended pertaining to certain works in Raigad district for which he is the guardian minister. Both had heated arguments over phone on the issue. Tawde too was not happy with Khadse's dominating position in the government. According to a source in the BJP, Mehta played a key role in providing details on Khadse family's land deal to the opponents.</p><p>The land deal was sealed on April 27. However, it became public in last week of May when the nominations for legislative council election were about to be finalised. The source says Mehta, who has good equations with Shah, wanted to stop Khadse from choosing his own men as candidates. Mehta wanted a ticket for his close friend R N Singh to whom Khadse had opposed. Finally, when Khadse was put in the dock Mehta succeeded in fetching a ticket for Singh. Subsequently, Singh, Pravin Darekar and Sujitsinh Thakur were elected unopposed to the council.</p><p><b>POLITICAL CONSPIRACY </b><br /></p><p>Khadse believes that those were hurt by his stringent actions have conspired against him. He indirectly pointed fingers towards industrialist Mukesh Ambani. "I had served notices to several people who have encroached wakf board lands. They might be upset with me," he says. Ambani's Rs 6,000 crore house, Antilia stands on a land owned by the wakf board. According to law, a wakf board land cannot be sold.</p><p>After he tendered his resignation Khadse went to his government bungalow Ramtek. His family members were weeping on hearing the news of his resignation. Khadse looked at them but did not say anything. He asked an attendant to call to the BJP workers in his constituency, Muktainagar in Jalgaon district. "Stop the violence. I am coming," he said and went to take rest.</p><p><b>ALSO READ</b>:&nbsp; <b><a target="_blank" href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/maharashtra-land-row-eknath-khadse-pune-land-owner-abbas-unkani-and-midc/1/683691.html" mce_href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/maharashtra-land-row-eknath-khadse-pune-land-owner-abbas-unkani-and-midc/1/683691.html">Pune land owner admits selling plot to Mrs Khadse, slams MIDC for delay in compensation</a></b> <br /></p><iframe src="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/embed/is619twf7k" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" height="396" width="648"></iframe></p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[The senior BJP leader thought high command will not touch him being the most senior minister and the tallest OBC face of the party in Maharashtra.]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>290472</tag>
<tag>494292</tag>
<tag>235758</tag>
<tag>734641</tag>
<tag>489953</tag>
<tag>222538</tag>
<tag>252470</tag>
<tag>227257</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[Khadse pays price for overconfidence and bad company]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[Khadse pays price for overconfidence and bad company]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[Khadse pays price for overconfidence and bad company]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>1</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/khadse-pays-price-for-over-confidence-and-bad-company/1/683713.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[Khadse pays price for overconfidence and bad company]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/khadse--_146504896862_647x404_060416073549.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[Khadse pays price for overconfidence and bad company]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/khadse--_146504896862_647x404_060416073549.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>1</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents><relatedcontent type="text">683647</relatedcontent><relatedcontent type="text">683691</relatedcontent><relatedcontent type="text">683214</relatedcontent></relatedcontents>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase><![CDATA[Khadse was convinced that the BJP high command will not touch him as he was the party's most senior minister and the tallest OBC face in the state.]]></briefcase><briefcase><![CDATA[Support from Nitin Gadkari vanished after Khadse received a call from Amit Shah at 11:45 am on June 4 asking him to step down.]]></briefcase><briefcase><![CDATA[Khadse's act to buy the land in name of his wife Mandakini and son-in-law Girish Choudhary was a clear case of conflict of interest.]]></briefcase><briefcase><![CDATA[Industries minister Subhash Desai pushed Khadse to a corner by declaring that the piece of land purchased by his kin belonged to the MIDC.]]></briefcase></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[khadse-pays-price-for-over-confidence-and-bad-company]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[Khadse pays price for overconfidence and bad company]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse,Pune land row,Mandakini,Girish Choudhary,BJP,Nitin Gadkari,Amit Shah,MIDC,Maharashtra]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>