<story>
<id>683723</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>no</story_issue>
<select_magazine>0</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date/>
<bylines>
<byline>260</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1465057518</createddate>
<publisheddate>1465057311</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1465069078</modifieddate>
<createdby>681</createdby>
<modifiedby>681</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city>285443</city>
</cities>
<categories><category>279844</category><category>279856</category><category>938154</category><category>280038</category><category>280225</category><category>279986</category><category>279631</category><category>280185</category><category>937822</category><category>938626</category></categories><ordering>683723</ordering><primarycategory>938626</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/khadse--_146504896862_647x404_060416095654.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt/>
<extra_large_title/>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/khadse--_146504896862_305x182_060416095654.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></large_alt>
<large_title><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse]]></large_title>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/khadse--_146504896862_300x350_060416095654.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt/>
<mediumimage_title/>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/khadse--_146504896862_180x118_060416095654.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt/>
<smallimage_title/>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/khadse--_146504896862_88x66_060416095654.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt/>
<extra_small_title/>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption><![CDATA[Eknath Khadse called ethical hacker Manish Bhangale a thief.]]></kicker_image_caption>
<mosimage>
<image/><caption/></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[Senior BJP leaders have decided to hold a meeting on Monday where certain modalities will be discussed like how the party will deal with the barrage of questions ahead of the Vidhan Sabha sessions.]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>After playing hide and seek the entire couple of days in Jalgaon, his hometown, on Friday night Eknath Khadse issued a video clipping saying that he was not in hiding and that he was busy working for the farmers in his region. It's said that he travelled to Mumbai last night and on Saturday early morning he left his official residence Ramtek early in the morning to meet Chief Minister Devendra Fadnavis. He was however not alone, state finance minister Sudhir Mungantiwar and state BJP president Raosaheb Danve along with a few others were by his side.</p><p>The meeting at Fadnavis's official bungalow Varsha lasted for about one and half-hour during which much was discussed with regards to the procedure of Khadses resignation. It did seem like Fadnavis had managed to convince the senior party leaders on why it was important for Khadse to resign and why only the formality of the procedure was left. Khadse had been defiant all along in spite of mounting party pressure. Saroj Pande, the party general secretary had also called up Khadse thrice to convince him to toe the party line. However, it was only later that he is said to have reluctantly agreed after much convincing.</p><p><b>BJP STANDS BEHIND KHADSE</b> <br /></p><p>Even after the procedure of putting in the paper by Khadse was decided, the party did not want to portray that it had left senior leader like him to lurch after the barrage of allegations. That is why a press conference was hold at the BJP head office and Maharashtra leaders - Sat Danve, Mungantiwar, Prakash Mehta, Chandrakant Patil and Vinod Tawde - were on the dias along with Khadse.&nbsp; &nbsp;</p><p>During the press conference, Danve said, "There have been baseless allegations against Khadse for the past few days. This is a conspiracy to malign the party. We have always maintained the moral high ground therefore Khadse has resigned till he comes out clean." </p><p>Khadse said that he had not yet put in his papers and that he would do so only after speaking to the media. Khadse spoke about all the toiling that he had done for the party over 40 years. Calling the exposes done by India Today against him a trial by media, Khadse said, "From day one, I have been asking for proof but they have failed to bring it out. I had thrown an open challenge that I will quit politics if the land rate allegations are proved. People like Anjali Damania made false allegations against me for cheap publicity." He claimed that he himself had asked Chief Minister&nbsp; Fadnavis to relieve him of his post and responsibility. He called hacker Manish Bhangale a thief. Bhangale was the one who claimed that Khadse and Dawood had spoken to each other. Khadse said, "Hacker means thief, people are believing a thief. I have requested the chief minister to investigate such people and take action."</p><p><b>BJP LEADERS TO MEET ON MONDAY </b><br /></p><p>After the press conference got over, Danve and Khadse, along with the troupe of Mehta, Patil and Tawde, left for chief minister's bungalow where Khadse tendered his resignation. Soon after, the cavalcade left Varsha for Ramtek where a closed-door meeting was again held. The senior leaders of party have decided to hold a meeting on Monday where certain modalities will be discussed like how the party will deal with the barrage of questions ahead of the Vidhan Sabha sessions. Meanwhile, the portfolios that were handled by Khadse have been handed over to Mungantiwar.</p><p><b>FADNAVIS ACCEPTS RESIGNATION</b> <br /></p><p>By evening, Fadnavis tweeted, "Received the resignation from Shri Eknathkhadseji. I have accepted it and sent it to Hon'ble Governor." He added that, "Eknath Khadse ji had demanded an enquiry into allegations against him. A retired high court judge will be appointed to conduct inquiry."</p><p>Even though Fadnavis tweeted that it was an enquiry on Khadse's request, cheer went up in activist Anjali Damania's camp at Azad Maidan who had been fasting for three days asking for a judicial enquiry against Khadse. She said, "Government never wants to give credit to activists. All I was asking for is an enquiry and if it's done am happy." However, she did not break her fast as she said that until she gets an official confirmation that an enquiry would be set up, she will not break her fast. "This government has assured us that their government will be corruption free. So it is their job to prove it too. So until I get a written assurance of an enquiry I will not stop fasting," she said.</p><p><b>ALSO READ</b>: <a target="_blank" href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/maharashtra-land-row-eknath-khadse-pune-land-owner-abbas-unkani-and-midc/1/683691.html" mce_href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/maharashtra-land-row-eknath-khadse-pune-land-owner-abbas-unkani-and-midc/1/683691.html"><b>Pune land owner admits selling plot to Mrs Khadse, slams MIDC for delay in compensation</b> </a> <br /></p><iframe src="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/embed/is619twf7k" allowfullscreen="" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" height="396" width="648"></iframe></p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[Senior BJP leaders have decided to hold a meeting on Monday where certain modalities will be discussed like how the party will deal with the barrage of questions ahead of the Vidhan Sabha sessions.]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>290472</tag>
<tag>256071</tag>
<tag>263640</tag>
<tag>236744</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[After defiance, comes Khadse's resignation and an enquiry by a retired judge]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[After defiance, comes Khadse's resignation and an enquiry by a retired judge]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[After defiance, comes Khadse's resignation and an enquiry by a retired judge]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>0</like>
<dislike>0</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/after-defiance-comes-khadses-resignation-and-an-enquiry-by-a-retired-judge/1/683723.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>1</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position>0</audio_position>
<audio_url><![CDATA[]]></audio_url>
<animated_image_position>0</animated_image_position>
<animated_image><![CDATA[]]></animated_image>
<map_embed_code_position>0</map_embed_code_position>
<map_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></map_embed_code>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position>0</social_embed_code_position>
<social_embed_code><![CDATA[]]></social_embed_code>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[After defiance, comes Khadse's resignation and an enquiry by a retired judge]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/khadse--_146504896862_647x404_060416095654.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[After defiance, comes Khadse's resignation and an enquiry by a retired judge]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/khadse--_146504896862_647x404_060416095654.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>0</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents><relatedcontent type="text">681004</relatedcontent><relatedcontent type="text">683713</relatedcontent></relatedcontents>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase><![CDATA[The meeting at Fadnavis's official bungalow lasted for about one and half-hour during which much was discussed with regards to the procedure of Khadses resignation.]]></briefcase><briefcase><![CDATA[Khadse had been defiant all along in spite of mounting party pressure.]]></briefcase><briefcase><![CDATA[The party did not want to portray that it had left senior leader like Khadse to lurch after the barrage of allegations.]]></briefcase><briefcase><![CDATA[Hacker Manish Bhangale was the one who claimed that Khadse and Dawood had spoken to each other.]]></briefcase></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[after-defiance-comes-khadses-resignation-and-an-enquiry-by-a-retired-judge]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[After defiance, comes Khadse's resignation and an enquiry by a retired judge]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[#KhadseOut,Eknath Khadse,Maharashtra BJP,Devendra Fadnavis,Anjali Damania]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>