<story>
<id>683825</id>
<state>1</state>
<story_issue>no</story_issue>
<select_magazine>0</select_magazine>
<select_supplement/>
<issue_date/>
<bylines>
<byline>222</byline>
</bylines>
<createddate>1465136702</createddate>
<publisheddate>1465136562</publisheddate>
<modifieddate>1465187498</modifieddate>
<createdby>863</createdby>
<modifiedby>799</modifiedby>
<cities>
<city>285443</city>
</cities>
<categories><category>280038</category><category>938414</category><category>279990</category><category>938232</category></categories><ordering>683825</ordering><primarycategory>938232</primarycategory><extralargeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/sairatfb-story_647_060516082407.jpg]]></extralargeimage>
<extra_large_alt><![CDATA[A still from Sairat]]></extra_large_alt>
<extra_large_title><![CDATA[A still from Sairat]]></extra_large_title>
<largeimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/sairatfb-story_305_060516082407.jpg]]></largeimage>
<large_alt><![CDATA[A still from Sairat]]></large_alt>
<large_title><![CDATA[A still from Sairat]]></large_title>
<mediumimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/sairatfb-story_300_060516082407.jpg]]></mediumimage>
<mediumimage_alt><![CDATA[A still from Sairat]]></mediumimage_alt>
<mediumimage_title><![CDATA[A still from Sairat]]></mediumimage_title>
<smallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/sairatfb-story_180_060516082407.jpg]]></smallimage>
<smallimage_alt><![CDATA[A still from Sairat]]></smallimage_alt>
<smallimage_title><![CDATA[A still from Sairat]]></smallimage_title>
<extrasmallimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/sairatfb-story_88_060516082407.jpg]]></extrasmallimage>
<extra_small_alt><![CDATA[A still from Sairat]]></extra_small_alt>
<extra_small_title><![CDATA[A still from Sairat]]></extra_small_title>
<bigimage/>
<kicker_image_caption><![CDATA[A still from Sairat]]></kicker_image_caption>
<mosimage>
<image/><caption/></mosimage>
<pros_cons><tech_pros_cons_main><title/><rating/><pron_cons_img/></tech_pros_cons_main><tech_pros><item/><item/><item/></tech_pros><tech_cons><item/><item/></tech_cons></pros_cons><tech-image-gallery><image/></tech-image-gallery><fulltext_conclaveformat><listicle_title/>
<quote_title/>
<quote_image/>
<factoids_title/>
<listicle_content><listicle/>
</listicle_content>
<quotes><quote/>
</quotes>
<factoids_content><factoids/>
</factoids_content>
</fulltext_conclaveformat>
<storykicker><![CDATA[For last few days, the entire state of Maharashtra has been gripped 
by a fever called Sairat a film by Nagraj Popatrao Manjule. The film 
has become the most successful film ever in the history of Marathi 
Cinema by grossing over 80 crores in the first 5 weeks. ]]></storykicker>
<storybody><![CDATA[<p>For last few days, the entire state of Maharashtra has been gripped by a fever called Sairat a film by Nagraj Popatrao Manjule. The film has become the most successful film ever in the history of Marathi Cinema by grossing over 80 crores in the first 5 weeks. One may attribute the success of this film to the changing trend in Marathi Cinema and the new found mantra of attracting the audience to the theatre.&nbsp; Not very long ago, Natasamrat starring Nana Patekar, Lai Bhari starring Riteish Deshmukh, Duniyadari Starring Swapnil Joshi , Natrang starring Atul Kulkarni did remarkably well at the box office. Apart from Commercial success, another common factor about these films was that all of them got a thumbs up from critics as well.</p><p><a href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/irrfan-khan-holds-a-special-screening-for-nagraj-manjules-marathi-film-sairat/1/676210.html" mce_href="http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/irrfan-khan-holds-a-special-screening-for-nagraj-manjules-marathi-film-sairat/1/676210.html"><u><b>ALSO READ:&nbsp;

 
Sairat - Irrfan holds a special screening for Nagraj Manjule's marathi film</b></u></a>  </p><p>But still, Sairat's success is different from all these movies. Sairat not only sent the box office ringing, it also sparked or rather reignited the debate over caste supremacy in a progressive state of Maharashtra. Superbly crafted as a tragic love story, the film set on the backdrop of a western Maharashtra village, tears apart the mask of so-called progressive&nbsp; state like Maharashtra, where Honor killing still remains a reality. The lead protagonists Archi ( Rinku Rajguru) and Parsha (Akash Thosar) belong to two dramatically different worlds. While Prashant Kale alias Parsha belongs to a lower Pardhi caste, Archana Patil or Archi hails from a politically dominant family of Patils. The best part about Sairat is that though the director narrates a love story , he never takes the romance to&nbsp; superficial levels. The ambience of the film stays real depicting the post liberalisation village economy and the emerging confidence of the Dalits. </p><p>The director made a similar film in the past called Fandry.&nbsp; It is the story of a boy belonging to Vadaar community (that generally does the odd job of catching pigs), his coming to terms with caste hierarchy. But this heartbreak is not the typical heartbreak of a teenager. His heartbreak opens him up to the reality of his caste, exploitation, and disparity. But unlike the protagonist of Fandry, Parshya in Sairat is aassertive. He plays cricket, is dressed well, has fine looks and is confident in approaching his lady love. Knowing well that she hails from the big family, Parshya who is a studious young guy holds the poise to propose Archi.</p><p>But the real hero of the film is Archi, who beats all the stereotypes of rural heroines portrayed earlier. She carries the confidence (or shall we say arrogance?) of being from the upper caste family. She rides a Bullet, drives a tractor, and is extremely open about her sexuality. So far Marathi cinema has mostly been portraying heroines from rural areas&nbsp; as the ones who are victimised or the ones bathing in the river or fetching water from it. But this is not the only stereotype that Sairat breaks.</p><p>Apart from the ones on celluloid, it also breaks notions of the existence of Caste system. Leaders from Maharashtra may have always loved to label the state that has the legacy of Mahatma Phule , Shahu Maharaj and Dr. Ambedkar. But the reality is far from it. Aarchi and Parshya's tragic end in the form of honor killing certainly does not appear to be fiction. Not very long ago did Maharashtra witness the murder of a Dalit boy Nitin Agey in Kharda village of Ahmednagar for falling in love with an upper caste girl.</p><p>The plot, Music, climax and anti-climax may be like any other Bollywood&nbsp; movie in this genre, from Love story to Ek Duje ke liye to Qayamat se Qayamat tak. But Sairat's success is poles apart from these movies. However, Sairat has destroyed this constructed myth of a binary. It proves that successful star cast, big budgets are not the crucial factors in making a film successful.</p><p>So on both the fronts, of critical acclaim and commercial or Box office success, Sairat is a milestone in all senses. Sairat may soon become the first ever Marathi film to join the 100 crore club.</p>]]></storybody>
<magazinekicker><![CDATA[For last few days, the entire state of Maharashtra has been gripped 
by a fever called Sairat a film by Nagraj Popatrao Manjule. The film 
has become the most successful film ever in the history of Marathi 
Cinema by grossing over 80 crores in the first 5 weeks. ]]></magazinekicker><tags>
<tag>350201</tag>
</tags>
<shortheadline><![CDATA[How Sairat became the highest-grossing Marathi film ever]]></shortheadline>
<storytitle><![CDATA[How Sairat became the highest-grossing Marathi film ever]]></storytitle>
<short_introtext><![CDATA[]]></short_introtext>
<magazineheadline><![CDATA[]]></magazineheadline>
<longheadline><![CDATA[How Sairat became the highest-grossing Marathi film ever]]></longheadline>
<strapheadline><![CDATA[]]></strapheadline>
<storyrating/>
<like_dislike>
<like>54</like>
<dislike>2</dislike>
</like_dislike>
<newtitle/>
<redirectionurl><![CDATA[http://indiatoday.intoday.in/story/how-sairat-became-the-highest-grossing-marathi-film-ever/1/683825.html]]></redirectionurl>
<courtesy><![CDATA[]]></courtesy>
<snappost>no</snappost>
<socialmediaintegration>
<facebook/>
<facebook_instant_article>0</facebook_instant_article>
<twitter/>
</socialmediaintegration>
<facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebook_instant_article>0</facebook_instant_article>
<audio_position/>
<audio_url/>
<animated_image_position/>
<animated_image/>
<map_embed_code_position/>
<map_embed_code/>
<gallery_associate_content>
<gallery_associate>
<gallery_id_position/>
<gallery_id/>
</gallery_associate>
</gallery_associate_content>
<social_embed_code_position/>
<social_embed_code/>
</facebook_instant_article_integration>
<facebooknarrative><![CDATA[How Sairat became the highest-grossing Marathi film ever]]></facebooknarrative>
<facebookimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/sairatfb-story_647_060516082407.jpg]]></facebookimage>
<facebookvideonarrative/>
<facebookvideo/>
<twitternarrative><![CDATA[How Sairat became the highest-grossing Marathi film ever]]></twitternarrative>
<twitterimage><![CDATA[http://media2.intoday.in/indiatoday/images/stories/sairatfb-story_647_060516082407.jpg]]></twitterimage>
<twittervideodescription/>
<twittervideo/>
<syndication>0</syndication>
<syndications_photo>0</syndications_photo>
<noindex_nofollow>0</noindex_nofollow>
<content_type_tag/>
<configurations>
<breakingnews>0</breakingnews>
<googlestandout>0</googlestandout>
<comment>0</comment>
<mediumstylecomment>0</mediumstylecomment>
<displaylock>0</displaylock>
</configurations>
<commentbox>1</commentbox>
<commentquestion/>
<featuredname/>
<relatedcontents><relatedcontent type="text">676210</relatedcontent></relatedcontents>
<scheduledatetime/>
<storyexpires/>
<storyexpirydate/>
<selectlisticletemplates/>
<quotes>
<quote><![CDATA[]]></quote>
</quotes>
<blurbs>
<blurb/>
</blurbs>
<tables>
<table><![CDATA[]]></table>
</tables>
<external_url/>
<buzz_content>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
<buzz>
<headline/>
<image/>
<description/>
</buzz>
</buzz_content>
<briefcase_content><briefcase/></briefcase_content><expertname/>
<expertimage/>
<expertdescription/>
<archive/>
<associatetvdate/>
<metatags>
<sefurl><![CDATA[how-sairat-became-the-highest-grossing-marathi-film-ever]]></sefurl>
<pagetitle><![CDATA[How Sairat became the highest-grossing Marathi film ever]]></pagetitle>
<keywords><![CDATA[sairat, sairat review, sairat box office collection, nagraj manjule, ringu rajguru]]></keywords>
</metatags>
</story>